<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_5"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>News Page</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-02" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>News Page</head>
                <div>
                    <head>Using the RSS News Feed</head>
                    <p>The News Page contains items relevant to the project as a whole, and news of
                        changes to the website or uploads of new online content (e.g. a new
                        manuscript brought online). News items are added as they happen, so this is
                        not like a newsletter which has e.g. a weekly update. It can be read in
                        place as a normal web page, but to save you from having to check this page
                        at regular intervals to see if anything has changed, it has been constructed
                        as an RSS feed page. This means that if you click on the ‘RSS newsfeed' link
                        to the right of the top of the page, you can ‘subscribe' to the DIAMM page,
                        and you will be automatically notified of new items.</p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Help19.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>If you have never subscribed to a newsfeed before simply click on the link
                        and you will be guided through the steps by your browser. News feeds may be
                        added either to your browser or your e-mail client. </p>
                    <p>Usually if you use an e-mail software such as Outlook it is best to direct
                        the feed to go to that software, and new items will appear as if they are
                        new e-mails in a special ‘mailbox' created by your e-mail software, or else
                        will appear in your Inbox as e-mails. If you usually use webmail through a
                        browser then you should direct the feed to be read by your browser by
                        creating a bookmark. You will be offered these options when you click on the
                        link.</p>
                    <p>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Subscribing to the feed is free</item>
                            <item>You can cancel or remove your feed connection easily, at any
                                time</item>
                            <item>You cannot receive spam through an RSS newsfeed</item>
                            <item>Your e-mail address is not communicated through an RSS feed, so it
                                cannot be passed on to anyone else</item>
                            <item>You cannot get a virus through an RSS feed.</item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/>
                    </p>

                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
