<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_6" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Reporting Errors</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-02" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Help</head>
            <div>
                <head>Reporting Errors</head>

                <p>Please notify errors in content to the project manager by e-mail. Do not use the
                    commenting tools to list errors. Examples of error types may include:</p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Typographical in the text</item>
                        <item> Incorrect shelf mark for manuscript </item>
                        <item>Source description out of date</item>
                        <item>New bibliographical information not listed</item>
                        <item>Manuscript not listed</item>
                        <item>Incorrect catalogue page referenced by catalogue link</item>
                        <item>Library address or URL incorrect/out of date</item>
                        <item>Incorrect image displayed</item>
                        <item>Image rotated</item>
                        <item>Image not loading</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Server errors</head>
                <p>These are of two types. In the first the page may display incorrectly, with
                    visible code (text enclosed in &lt; &gt;) and no formatting. The other type of
                    error will return a page which may look like this (depending on which browser
                    you are using):</p>
                <p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Help20"/>
                    </figure>
                </p>
                <p>You may be able to clear the error by using your browser's back button to return
                    to the previous page, and repeating your search or other action that took you to
                    the error page.</p>
                <p>If this does not clear the error you should ensure you have the latest version of
                    Java installed. Go to <ref type="external" target="http://www.java.com/"
                        >http://www.java.com/</ref> and click on the button ‘Free Java Download'.
                    This link will automatically check your system Java installation and advise you
                    of any new download required.</p>
                <p>Occasionally there are software or data upgrades in action on the website which
                    may cause unusual functioning or errors. Maintenance work does not usually last
                    more than about 30 minutes. If you have time, it is worth leaving the site and
                    resuming your work later on.</p>
                <p>If the error persists you should report it to the project manager, but you must
                    include the following information:</p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Your operating system</item>
                        <item>Your browser software</item>
                        <item>What you did to cause the error (i.e. which link you clicked on, or
                            which search you performed).</item>
                        <item>If possible include the URL of the page</item>
                        <item>If possible, cut and paste the http error information into your
                            e-mail.</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                </p>


            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
