<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_4_3">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Archiving</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2006-04-18</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p2_2</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Archiving</head>
                <p>All Archived images are stored in uncompressed TIF format. TIF (or TIFF) format
                    allows the inclusion of a metadata tag in every image that does not affect the
                    image information itself. At present TIF is considered the most widely
                    compatible and easily transferable file format for images. Longevity of the file
                    format is constantly monitored.</p>
                <p>DIAMM images are archived at two locations: the Oxford Hierarchical File Server,
                    managed by OUCS in Oxford, and the Arts and Humanities Data Service in London.
                    Both these archives have secure off-site backup that is updated every 24 hours.
                    Many newly-created archives use, or plan to use, CD or DVD discs for the
                    long-term storage of their data. This is NOT an archive, and will almost
                    certainly result in data loss. The shelf-life of CDs or DVDs is anything from 2
                    years upwards, but discs can fail before that because they are extremely
                    vulnerable to damage. CD or DVD juke-box systems are completely inappropriate
                    for long-term archiving strategies. The minimum requirement for archiving is a
                    hard-drive RAID system, with off-site secondary backup. Even this is not
                    necessarily sufficient for an important collection of data where the archive is
                    the only repository. Management of a proper storage archive requires a dedicated
                    staff, temperature controlled environment for the systems, and constant
                    monitoring and upgrades. If you are creating a data archive, please contact the
                    Arts and Humanities Data Service for advice about creating a secure long-term
                    archive for your materials.</p>
                <p>The OUCS Hierarchical File Server (HFS) system can only be accessed by project
                    staff. It is not accessible via the internet, nor can it be accessed by any
                    registered user of the web portal. The Archive is entirely independent of the
                    web portal, and provides a secure storage system for all the full-size
                    uncompressed images that have so far been captured by DIAMM or its partners, as
                    well as those that have undergone digital manipulation work to restore them to
                    readability. It is purely a storage facility: the images are not used for
                    standard working, and once archived are only accessed again to upgrade format
                    when that becomes necessary (it has not yet been necessary to do this, as TIF
                    format is both stable and universally used). Because it is not a 'working' copy
                    of the images, the HFS content is described as a 'Dark Archive'. </p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
