<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_4_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Image capture</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2008-04-24</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Changed text to accommodate for
                changed caption length.</change>
            <change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Put images in tables so they
                would appear side by side. This is an unsatisfactory solution and requires CCH to
                alter presentation things.</change>
            <change><date>2006-04-18</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-10-26</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>update to camera
                description and specs</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-06</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p2_6</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Image capture</head>
                <div>
                    <head>Acknowledgements</head>
                    <p> We would like to acknowledge the generous help and support of the following
                        in supplying us with damaged documents for testing of imaging techniques: </p>
                    <p>Richard Linenthal, Bernard Quaritch Rare books</p>
                    <p>Bill Marger, Philadelphia</p>
                    <p>Pierre Joppen of Paulus Swaen old maps, Florida</p>
                    <p>Doyle W Flowers Jr, www.hisbooks.net, Atlanta, Georgia</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Digitizing primary sources for the DIAMM archive: why build a digital and
                        not an analogue archive?</head>
                    <p>The main advantage of a digital image over analogue is the longevity of the
                        digital medium (although this assumes a well-managed archiving strategy).
                        Even carefully stored film or glossy pictures will become brittle in 20
                        years, and is also subject to physical damage that cannot be repaired.
                        Analogue images cannot be accurately copied or reproduced into multiple
                        generations without loss of data and degradation or alteration of the
                        original material.</p>
                    <p>The fact that a digital image remains unchanged and can be copied precisely
                        is both an advantage and a disadvantage, as the copyright issues that arise
                        with exact copying are significantly more pertinent than with analogue
                        images where copying is never completely exact. Because digital imaging
                        technology is still relatively in its infancy, we have yet to see whether
                        our preservation and file migration strategies will indeed leave an image
                        'unchanged' over time, but the ability to preserve in this way is inherent
                        to the digital medium.</p>
                    <p>A second advantage of the Digital image is its ability to reproduce the
                        original with far more exactitude than the analogue image can. Digital
                        capture at resolutions employed by DIAMM (144 Megapixels), involves the
                        acquisition of a far greater quantity of information than analogue. Most of
                        this information is not visible to the naked eye except under extreme
                        magnification, but this sort of magnification is possible in the digital
                        medium. The basic digital image tolerates far more enlargement without
                        graining than its analogue counterpart would.</p>
                    <p>Because analogue developing processes require the use of human judgement
                        equally as much as any technical process to produce the final image, any
                        close study of colours and ink bleed (for example) would be pointless unless
                        conducted on the original source. Given the fragility of most of the sources
                        from the Medieval period, this would be highly undesirable.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Why digitize primary and not secondary sources (surrogates)?</head>
                    <p>The question of the necessity of scanning from the original source rather
                        than a surrogate (a slide or photograph) frequently arises: it is certainly
                        possible to obtain very high-resolution scans of surrogates without having
                        any recourse to the original. However, a good scan of a photograph or slide,
                        is still only a scan of a secondary image, and any deficiencies in that
                        source will only be carried forward into the digital copy. Englargement of
                        digital scans made from high-quality photographs emphasizes the deficiency
                        in focus, since conventional photography does not allow the photographer to
                        view his focussing at very high magnification. Even if the image is in
                        focus, the grain resolution of the print medium causes degradation in the
                        image quality when that is in turn scanned and enlarged.</p>
                    <p>In addition, between the primary source and the surrogate, the potential for
                        corruption of the original data has been introduced, as a human operator has
                        had to make decisions about focus and colour reproduction. Scanning from
                        surrogates allows the introduction of a level of error caused by the
                        original capture process. Because our ability to perceive colour is often
                        flawed, and always limited by our ability to perceive the full light
                        spectrum, every layer of reproduction adds a level at which errors are
                        introduced. The eye is also incapable of fine focus beyond a certain level,
                        and it is this further level of definition that is so essential in studying
                        manuscripts in the digital medium. A scan from a surrogate is only as good
                        as the surrogate, not the original.</p>
                    <p>The first image below was scanned from a good colour photograph. The second
                        image was scanned directly from the original source. Both images have been
                        enlarged to pixel-for-pixel resolution on screen (i.e. full size).</p>


                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Scanner.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>



                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Camera.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>





                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Colour</head>
                    <p>When photo labs make a reprint either from a print or from its negative they
                        are rarely, if ever, able to reproduce the colour of the original print
                        precisely, because they rely both on human judgement and the use of chemical
                        processes that are too inaccurately calibrated to be exactly reproduced.</p>
                    <p>The mechanism by which we perceive colour is still only partially understood,
                        but one extraordinary ability of the brain, chromatic adaptation, which
                        enables us to function normally in changing light conditions becomes a
                        handicap when dealing with precise colour balancing. As an example, if you
                        put on a pair of dark glasses, the lens will completely change the real
                        colours reaching your eye. However, a split-second adjustment in the brain
                        allows us to continue to recognise correctly and understand colours even
                        through a very heavily tinted filter.</p>
                    <p>All capture devices from scanners to hand-held cameras require calibration to
                        determine how the CCD responds to colours. Archival digital scanning work is
                        done with consistent daylight balanced lighting: this increases the scan
                        time but ensures a more accurate result. Since the light is continuous
                        (unlike flash), exact calibration of the capture equipment can ensure a
                        correct record of the lighting conditions.</p>
                    <p>Direct digital acquisition from the original source ensures both stability of
                        the colour balance and the quality of the information, which remains true to
                        the original because it is not subject to transformation from the analogue
                        to the digital language. As long as the equipment used to view or print the
                        image is correctly calibrated, and makes correct use of the embedded profile
                        of the capture equipment, the user will see correct colour either on-screen
                        or when the digital image is printed. No post-processing (unsharp masking to
                        correct poor focus, level adjust to correct exposure, colour adjustment,
                        de-skewing or other 'tweaking' etc.) should be necessary on a correctly
                        scanned or photographed image. If any post-processing is required, then the
                        image has not been properly taken, and the work must be re-done.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Image capture and archival process in DIAMM</head>
                    <p>DIAMM digital images are captured at very high resolution (usually 600 dpi or
                        above at real size), the resulting uncompressed TIFF files being in the
                        region of 200-340 MB in size. These are the archive images which are stored
                        by Oxford University Computing Services, which uses a Hierarchical File
                        Server system. This is a resource of the Oxford Humanities Computing
                        department. A second deposit of the images is held by the HFS of the Arts
                        and Humanities Data Service (UK). Each image includes an industry-standard
                        colour patche and a rule showing the original dimensions. DIAMM stores
                        extensive metadata about each individual image, including the type and
                        quality of the light source and the equipment used for image capture in
                        order to anticipate any future needs that may arise with improvements in
                        technology and software. Capture metadata and Dublin Core information about
                        the source is held in the TIF header, and also in the project database.
                        Further detailed metadata describing the manuscript and its contents is
                        recorded in the database, portions of which may be consulted through this
                        website. </p>
                    <p>DIAMM is unique in providing a mobile imaging service with capture protocols
                        in place that enable us to create digital images of exactly matching quality
                        and consistency, anywhere in the world, and in virtually any working
                        conditions. Funding from the AHRB has enabled the project to acquire digital
                        images of many of the most important medieval music manuscripts in Europe,
                        as well as the fragments which, because of their limited size, are rarely
                        visited due to the relatively higher cost of travelling to see a single leaf
                        as opposed to a 300-page manuscript. The libraries that own these sources
                        would not have been able to afford to digitize them at this quality
                        themselves, so the creation of these images has been a major work of
                        conservation, as well as providing scholars with a set of images which they
                        can acquire for themselves through each library. The mobile studio is shown
                        below, set up for work in a darkened room provided by the archive.</p>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="equipment1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <p>In cases of extreme (or even minor) damage to sources, copies of these large
                        images are be used for virtual restoration processes with the permission of
                        the owner. Since restoration is only done on the images, this is completely
                        safe for the manuscript, as it is not touched again. If a restoration
                        process on an image fails or is unsatisfactory, the image is simply
                        discarded, and the process is redone with a new copy of the original
                        image.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Camera specifications</head>
                    <p>Most 'high-street' hand-held digital cameras have a capture resolution of 5-7
                        megapixels. High-end digital cameras used by professional photographers have
                        a capture resolution of about 7-11 megapixels which, thanks to massive
                        recent improvements in print technology, is sufficient to produce a
                        high-quality printed image at around A3 size. These cameras can capture
                        images at speeds similar to those of conventional cameras, and are referred
                        to as 'single-shot' cameras, as they use a rectangular CCD.</p>
                    <p>DIAMM uses a PhaseOne PowerPhase FX digital scanning back mounted on a custom
                        built large-format camera with motor-driven focus designed by ICAM Archive
                        Systems, the company responsible for our camera technical support. The
                        maximum capture resolution is 144 Megapixels and the dpi obtainable depends
                        on the size of the original source. Capture times vary but are usually in
                        the region of 4-6 minutes. This is because a single CCD of 144 megapixels
                        would be extremely expensive, so a scanning back uses a double row of 24,000
                        sensors (red-green/green-blue. Green is used twice because this is the most
                        difficult colour to see and capture), which is mounted on a movable scanning
                        head. The scanning back works much like a flatbed scanner in the sense that
                        it takes a set of pictures in position one (which are sent to the computer)
                        then it moves the capture head and takes another set of pictures in position
                        2, and so on, all the way to position 12,000. The resulting bits are
                        stitched together by the capture software, and the end result is a perfect
                        digital image, which looks just the same as one made by a single-shot camera
                        or a flatbed scanner.</p>
                    <p>All images are captured at the highest possible resolution in the hope that
                        there will be no necessity to revisit the manuscript for photography in the
                        near future.</p>
                    <p>Advances in camera technology during 2005 led to two companies, PhaseOne and
                        Hasselblad, each bringing out a very large-sensor single-shot camera, of
                        approx 38 Megapixels (cost variable, but around £30,000 at the time of
                        writing). This would be more than adequate for archive-quality imaging of
                        smaller-size sources, as long as there is no damage on the original that
                        requires digital restoration, which would require a higher-resolution image.
                        It is clear that the emphasis on camera technology now is going to be the
                        development and marketing of much larger single-shot sensors, and as the
                        quality and demand goes up, the price will gradually come down. For the
                        immediate future though, the only way to obtain pictures at 144 Mpx is to
                        use a scanning back, or a single-shot device which takes a number of
                        pictures and stitches them together afterwards.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
