<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_4_4">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Conservation</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Put images in tables so they
                would appear side by side. This is an unsatisfactory solution and requires CCH to
                alter presentation things.</change>
            <change><date>2006-05-10</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-05</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p2_5</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Conservation</head>
                <p>Although many of the fragmentary sources of Medieval Polyphonic Music were
                    damaged by contemporary 'vandalism' - most commonly the use of dismembered
                    parchment manuscripts to reinforce later bindings - a significant number have
                    been further damaged by restoration procedures in the early- and mid-1900s.
                    Restoration always carries some risk and sometimes a certain level of loss often
                    has to be accepted in favour of the retention of the majority of material for a
                    longer time.</p>
                <p>DIAMM aims to ensure that nothing in the digital capture process will hasten the
                    gradual natural deterioration of any source. In the long term it is hoped that
                    the availability of high-quality and high-resolution colour images will allow
                    archives to minimize the direct handling of each source as well as providing a
                    stable reference point against which deterioration may be measured, and thus aid
                    in conservation. DIAMM images have proved of sufficient quality to restore a
                    great deal of material lost through the natural damage incurred during the life
                    of the source, and in many cases have proved of greater benefit than examining
                    the original source, since the ability to enlarge on screen well above normal
                    size has enabled scholars to find material that is not visible to the naked
                    eye.</p>
                <div>
                    <head>Lighting</head>
                    <p> DIAMM does not use natural daylight nor flash because of the high UV content
                        of these light sources. We also do not use a flatbed scanner, as the
                        proximity, heat and brightness of scanning lights is potentially damaging.
                        Instead we rely on cold fluorescent daylight-balanced tubes, which cast a
                        clear cold light that emulates daylight in colour, but without the damaging
                        UV content. These lights are mounted about 70-100 cm from the source and the
                        image is captured using a digital scanning back and custom-designed camera
                        body. Although this means that exposure times are quite long, the light
                        exposure (and therefore the potential for UV damage) is nevertheless
                        significantly less than a split-second flash exposure, or a slow exposure
                        under real daylight. The intensity of the light is far less than with most
                        flatbed scanners, even taking the slow exposure time into account.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Handling</head>
                    <p> Although it is possible to place some loose leaves on a flatbed scanner, it
                        is generally impossible with bound manuscripts, and highly undesirable from
                        the conservation point of view. This method of capture is considered
                        inadvisable even for loose leaves since, apart from the potential for damage
                        from scanning lights, inks and particles of the surface or other material
                        may stick on contact with the glass surface. For this reason DIAMM does not
                        place any items under glass during photography.</p>
                    <p>DIAMM personnel have now accrued considerable experience in handling a wide
                        variety of sources in various stages of repair. We use specially-devised
                        handling aids to hold pages flat with the minimum of physical contact. In
                        general the book is allowed to find its own level and ‘comfortable'
                        position, and the photographic procedure is adjusted to compensate, rather
                        than forcing the book into an unnatural position for the convenience of the
                        photographer. Occasionally this has meant that it was impossible to
                        photograph details e.g. in binding gutters, but we felt that the loss of
                        minimal material in this way was necessitated by the need for respect of the
                        binding as a historical artefact in its own right.</p>


                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="capture1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="capture2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>



                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
