<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_4_2"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Image quality</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2008-04-24</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Small text edits.</change>
            <change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Put images in tables so they
                would appear side by side. This is an unsatisfactory solution and requires CCH to
                alter presentation things.</change>
            <change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Removed head tag</change>
            <change><date>2006-05-08</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p2_1</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Image quality</head>
                <p>Whether images are captured by DIAMM using our portable studio, or by the
                    contributing institution with their own equipment, DIAMM has established a
                    base-line set of standards providing for a MINIMUM capture quality to be met by
                    all archived digital images in the collection. This is designed to ensure that,
                    should the original source be lost or damaged, a colour-accurate, high-quality,
                    full-size facsimile could be reproduced from the archived image.</p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:oList>
                        <item>The MINIMUM capture resolution at real size for any source is 400
                            dpi.</item>
                        <item>Each image must include a cm or inch scale, photographed with the
                            image, at the same height as the surface being photographed.</item>
                        <item>Each image should included an industry-standard gray scale,
                            photographed with the image, at the same height as the surface being
                            photographed</item>
                        <item>All images should have the colour profile of the capture device
                            embedded at the point of capture.</item>
                        <item>Black and white points should be adjusted at capture to avoid
                            highlight-clipping.</item>
                        <item>No unsharp mask may be used during capture, and no post-processing may
                            be applied to the image after capture.</item>
                        <item>Images should be saved in uncompressed TIF format.</item>
                        <item>Clips or bones must be placed where they do not obstruct any written
                            matter on the surface.</item>
                        <item>Lighting should ideally mimic natural daylight, with and even and
                            stable light-spread across the source. Flash and natural daylight are
                            not desirable (see Conservation).</item>
                    </xmt:oList>
                </p>
                <p>In addition to the above requirements, DIAMM specifies a number of desirable
                    requirements that we would include if undertaking the work ourselves, and expect
                    to be included if done by the archive, but which can be omitted if it is deemed
                    unusually difficult or too costly in terms of time required to include them.</p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:oList>
                        <item>The Metadata regarding the manuscript, its location references and the
                            conditions of capture and equipment used should be embedded in the image
                            at the point of capture.</item>
                        <item>If possible, each image should include an industry-standard colour
                            scale in addition to the grayscale (e.g. Kodak Q13, or Macbeth colour
                            chart).</item>
                        <item>If clips or bones are used to hold the surface in place during
                            photography, a second image should be made with any extraneous items in
                            a different position.</item>
                    </xmt:oList>
                </p>
                <div>
                    <!-- <head>Image Quality</head> -->
                    <p>A particular feature of digital capture using a high-resolution digital
                        camera, such as the scanning-back equipment used by DIAMM, is the extremely
                        high definition of the images, acquiring greater information by far than
                        that obtainable with a conventional analogue camera. However this does
                        introduce the potential for inefficient use of the digital medium, since a
                        photographer might consider that their ability to focus through a lens is
                        sufficient for focusing under digital capture conditions. The accuracy of
                        focus available to the eye as opposed to the Digital 'eye' is dramatically
                        different, emphasized by the facility for enlargement of digital images.</p>
                    <p>In the following examples, tiny sections of a leaf were captured at high
                        resolution having focused the camera by eye. The result, at normal size,
                        looks sharp and in focus:</p>
                    <!--<p>-->
                    <!--
                <table>
                    <row>
                        <cell>
                            <figure url="FocusA"/>
                        </cell>
                        <cell>
                            <figure url="FocusB"/>
                        </cell>
                    </row>
                </table>
-->


                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="FocusA.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="FocusB.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>



                    <!--</p>-->
                    <p>However when the image is enlarged to pixel-for-pixel view onscreen, it loses
                        integrity, only apparent when fully enlarged. The focus is adjusted minutely
                        making no perceptible difference to the operator, and the same very small
                        segment is captured and enlarged. The process is repeated until the enlarged
                        result is as sharp as possible: this gives a finesse of focal length that is
                        a considerable improvement on by-eye focus. The images shown above are
                        enlarged below: in each case, the first image of each pair shows the
                        enlarged version of the segment above which was focussed by eye, while the
                        second shows the image with focus adjusted after several test scans to
                        improve the quality:</p>



                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Focus1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Focus2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>


                    <!--
                <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <figure url="Focus1"/>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <figure url="Focus2"/>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
   -->


                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Focus3.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Focus4.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <!--   
                <table>
                        <row>
                            <cell>
                                <figure url="Focus3"/>
                            </cell>
                            <cell>
                                <figure url="Focus4"/>
                            </cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
   
   -->

                    <p>A scan of a surrogate can only ever be as good as the surrogate itself, and
                        will never be as good as a scan of the original: it cannot provide colour
                        detail at the same level or accuracy as scans from the original source, nor
                        can it be enlarged to the same extent that a directly acquired image can.
                        Since preservation of the best data possible with current technology is the
                        specific aim of archiving, this would not be yielded by digitization of
                        surrogates. Restoration processes on badly damaged sources require the
                        exceptional quantity of information stored in a high-resolution digital
                        image (often of higher quality than a simple archive-quality image): test
                        restorations on scans of colour slides have shown that the quality of the
                        surrogate is not sufficient to allow restoration to be as effectively
                        undertaken as with direct captures.</p>
                    <p>HOWEVER, if the scanning device is miscalibrated, or the scanning process is
                        faulty, the information obtained is of little use: post-processing is
                        required to make the picture look correct to the user, thus destroying much
                        information and invalidating what is left. <hi rend="bold">Unless an image
                            is captured correctly in the first instance, there are no advantages to
                            be gained from direct capture.</hi>
                    </p>
                    <p>Quite often, creators of digital images use 'quick fixes', made possible with
                        image-processing software, to compensate for poor original images. DIAMM
                        maintains a policy that if ANY post-process activity is necessary in order
                        to make the image correct, then the image has been incorrectly taken, and
                        must be taken again with the problem corrected in order to create an
                        archive-quality image.</p>
                    <p>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>If the image requires the addition of an unsharp mask to make it
                                appear focussed, then the original focus is inadequate or incorrect; </item>
                            <item>If a rectangular page appears trapezoid in shape in the image, the
                                camera is not perpendicular to the shooting surface, and the setup
                                needs to be adjusted: the picture must not be 'de-skewed' after
                                capture as this damages the content; </item>
                            <item>If colours or levels require adjustment after capture, the gray
                                balance has not been correctly calibrated, the white and black
                                points have not been correctly set at capture, or the exposure was
                                incorrectly set.</item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/>
                    </p>
                    <p>Some operators check images on their monitor against the original source, and
                        make minor colour adjustments so that the on-screen image looks the same
                        colour as the original document. Even if the monitor is correctly calibrated
                        (which it rarely is), this is a completely pointless process: the original
                        document is viewed with reflective light (i.e. the light bounces off the
                        surface to the eye). The on-screen version uses transmissive light (i.e. the
                        light source is pointing directly into the eye) and so the two items could
                        never look the same colour. No post-capture adjustment of any sort should be
                        made to an archive image. If the capture protocols are correct, and the
                        correct colour profile for the capture equipment are embedded in the image,
                        then print output to a correctly calibrated printer should match the colour
                        of the original as closely as is possible.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
