<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_4_6" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digital Restoration</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change when="2011-02-24" who="CT">Combined the four separate restoration files into
                this one</change>
            <change><date>2006-04-24</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-05</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p3</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Digital restoration</head>
                <p>
               <!--     <xmt:uList>
                        <item><ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p3_3">Introduction</ref> What is meant by ‘digital
                            restoration', and why it is sometimes necessary</item>
                        <item><ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p3_1">Process</ref> A brief description of the basic
                            processes used with Adobe Photoshop to restore damaged or unreadble
                            sources to a point where they can be transcribed</item>
                        <item><ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p3_2">Samples</ref> Three examples of images before
                            and after restoration to show the effect enhancement can have on
                            legibility and content</item>
                    </xmt:uList>-->
                    <!--<table>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="linkTitle" cols="1" rows="1"><ref type="internal"
                                    cRef="p3_3">Introduction</ref></cell>
                            <cell role="linkDesc" cols="1" rows="1">What is meant by ‘digital
                                restoration', and why it is sometimes necessary</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="linkTitle" cols="1" rows="1"><ref type="internal"
                                    cRef="p3_1">Process</ref></cell>
                            <cell role="linkDesc" cols="1" rows="1">A brief description of the basic
                                processes used with Adobe Photoshop to restore damaged or unreadble
                                sources to a point where they can be transcribed</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="linkTitle" cols="1" rows="1"><ref type="internal"
                                    cRef="p3_2">Samples</ref></cell>
                            <cell role="linkDesc" cols="1" rows="1">Three examples of images before
                                and after restoration to show the effect enhancement can have on
                                legibility and content</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>-->
                </p>
                <div>
                    <head>Introduction</head>

                    <p>As well as archiving sources for the future, part of the work of the DIAMM
                        project is to attempt to restore and retrieve lost works using the already
                        sophisticated and still developing technology available through digital
                        photography.</p>

                    <!--   <table type="thumbnail">
        <row role="data">
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="BL"/>
        </cell>
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="Cambrai"/>
        </cell>
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="Leeds"/>
        </cell>
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="Wells"/>
        </cell>
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="Stratford"/>
        </cell>
        <cell role="data" cols="1" rows="1">
        <figure type="thumb" url="Durham"/>
        </cell>
        </row>
        </table>-->


                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="BL.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Cambrai.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Leeds.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Wells.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Stratford.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>

                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Durham.gif" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                    </figure>


                    <p>Click on an image to see animated restoration process of the whole page. The
                        animations are necessarily large, and so will load slowly even with an
                        ethernet connection. As they open in separate windows, it is possible to
                        view other web pages while the images are downloading</p>
                    <p>Very few pre-reformation British music manuscripts survive in even
                        semi-complete form. Most are damaged and fragmentary, and have been
                        preserved only because they were re-used as binding material or for other
                        purposes: this music went out of fashion quite fast (a testimony to the
                        vitality of the tradition few manuscripts contained music more than 30 or 40
                        years old) and when obsolete many manuscripts were consigned to the
                        book-binder's waste-box (or, in one case, for use as backing for some
                        ceiling paintings at New College, Oxford). Medieval vandalism was compounded
                        by the more wilful destruction at the Reformation and again in later
                        centuries when books were re-bound and the early bindings containing the
                        music fragments simply discarded. This practice was common up to the
                        mid/late 19th century; there is a notable difference in fragment survival
                        rates between libraries that rebound extensively in the 19th century and
                        those that did not.</p>
                    <p>Several samples of Virtual Restoration have been reproduced on the <ref
                            type="internal" cRef="p3_2">Samples</ref> page showing the degree to
                        which sources apparently damaged beyond retrieval can be manipulated
                        sufficiently to return the text to a readable state. This is not an attempt
                        to return them to a pristine condition, only to enhance the text
                        sufficiently to make transcription or study of the music possible.</p>
                </div>

                <div>

                    <head>Restoration process</head>
                    <p>More information regarding techniques employed in virtual restoration may be
                        found in the DIAMM publication: <ref type="redist"
                            cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook.pdf">Image Restoration Workbook
                            (58Mb)</ref>
                    </p>
                    <p>The use of digital images to explore the possibilities of restoration in a
                        virtual environment (i.e. without intervention in the primary source) has
                        been a possibility for some time, though mainstream image processing
                        software has only recently reached a level of sophistication coupled with
                        cost-effectiveness for the processes to become practically available to a
                        wide user-base. The aim of the DIAMM project in developing restoration
                        techniques is to use public domain software that many potential users of the
                        techniques may already own, and others could afford to buy.</p>
                    <p>There are a number of image-processing applications currently available, but
                        the most widely-used is Adobe Photoshop. The advantage of mainstream
                        software like this is that it is commercially economic for the developers to
                        continue to upgrade and improve the product, and the cost of obtaining it
                        will remain within a range accessible to a high percentage of potential
                        users. Because of its wide customer-base many of the functions available in
                        Photoshop are designed towards a creative graphical end, irrelevant to
                        virtual restoration (VR). However, three tools are of specific value in VR
                        (layers, levels and selective colour), with a host of smaller routines
                        offering additional subtlety.</p>
                    <p>Firstly, one of the recent additions to Photoshop is the facility that allows
                        any process applied to the original image to be added as a Layer. This
                        superimposes the alteration in much the same way as placing a succession of
                        transparent overlays which can be added or removed:</p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Layers1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Layers2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Layers3.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>But this is far more than simply a sophisticated 'undo' feature. As well as
                        being able to switch the visibility of an overlay on and off, it is possible
                        to adjust its opacity and also the manner in which it affects the underlying
                        material.</p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Opacity.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Overlay.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>Sequential overlays can also be shuffled to achieve optimum results. Once an
                        ideal finish is achieved the overlays can be permanently 'flattened' onto
                        the original image, and the result saved alongside the untouched original as
                        a TIFF or other format file.</p>
                    <p>However, because of the marked variance in restoration needs across even
                        single leaves, one particular 'overlay' may improve one section of a
                        document while disimproving another section, and the interactive fluidity of
                        adding, removing and adjusting layers can become an essential part of the
                        process which cannot be discarded. Photoshop allows an image to be saved (in
                        it's proprietary format) with the layers intact, so that users can continue
                        to switch visibility of layers on and off or adjust their opacity. This is
                        an extremely powerful feature, but has the disadvantage that resulting files
                        can become very large, depending on the number of layers being saved.
                        Individual layers can usually be merged into each other, which can save some
                        space.</p>
                    <p>Layers can be imported from other documents and superimposed in the same way
                        as layers created internally: ultra-violet images when overlaid on a faded
                        original have proved successful, and in a similar way, performing multiple
                        major alterations to a document, saving it separately and re-introducing the
                        altered image as a semi-transparent layer to the original has produced
                        unexpectedly good results.</p>
                    <p>Level Adjust is probably the most basic tool offered by Photoshop, and has
                        yielded more impressive results than a whole host of sophisticated filters.
                        Brightness and Contrast adjustments are available and can sometimes be
                        sufficient for sources which are simply badly faded. Level adjust is a more
                        subtle approach to the same problems. The level adjust tool offers a
                        histogram which graphically represents the wavelengths of the colours
                        present in the image. Peaks and troughs indicate colour density:</p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Levels1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Levels2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Levels3.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>Here, the full RGB spectrum is covered. By moving the sliders at the base of
                        the diagram inwards, it is possible to spread a narrow colour range over a
                        much wider bandwidth, thus darkening the deeper and lightening the paler
                        colours. The middle slider allows a subtler adjustment of mid-range colours
                        alone. Most often, adjusting the full RGB spectrum is the most useful
                        approach, but the drop-down menu at the top of the dialog box allows the
                        three channels to be adjusted individually. By performing Level Adjust
                        actions within an added layer, the results can not only be switched on and
                        off, but can also be re-adjusted at a later stage, a feature not available
                        when level adjustment is applied directly to the 'background' image.</p>
                    <p>Finally, Photoshop's Colour Range... selection tool (from the "Select" menu)
                        enables the user to select pixels of a specific colour and also to capture
                        pixels of a similar colour range. Using the pointer to indicate the colour
                        pixels to be selected, the degree of similarity can be specified by the user
                        as value from 1 to 200: the selected area appears as a 'negative' white in
                        the preview box. The selected colour can then either be replaced by a
                        neutral background tone, or faded back using level adjustment.</p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Corpus2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Corpus3.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Corpus4.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Corpus5.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                    </p>
                    <p>This has proved the most important tool in lifting layers of dirt, glue or
                        later over-writing from a document by selecting a specific colour, mounting
                        that selection as a layer and applying level adjust to the specific colour
                        selected. The process nearly always has to be repeated several times, and
                        the colours selected more accurately by enlarging the image repeatedly to a
                        point where the pixels begin to break up. Repeating the process with limited
                        selections avoids any colour range extending to material that you wish to
                        remain unaffected.</p>
                    <p>The same process is used to darken writing that has become too pale to read -
                        using 'select colour' the colours of the note-shapes in this example were
                        isolated, and then darkened by using level adjust in a layer.</p>
                    <p>The example above was achieved after four successive colour selections and
                        blanket level adjust, but as the aim was readability of the underlying
                        material the results are more dramatic than would be expected with the
                        majority of documents. Where readability is more important than an
                        attractive finish, the ability to separate and manipulate colour channels is
                        a useful tool and serves to emphasize how much hidden information there is
                        in high-resoultion images that the naked eye cannot perceive.</p>
                    <p>There is always an ethical problem in applying this process:</p>
                    <p>
                        <list type="ordered">
                            <item>The 'restorer' has to make decisions from the start about what
                                information he wishes to discard, and what he wishes to retain: thus
                                to some extent the restorer must know (or have decided) in advance
                                which elements on the page are later accretions, and which are the
                                original notation. Inevitably different readings will be obtained by
                                different scholars.</item>
                            <item>A restored version misrepresents the original source, so care must
                                be taken to ensure the user of the image knows that this image has
                                been digitally processed. The current policy of DIAMM regarding
                                restoration is to make it absolutely clear that any material
                                presented as 're-found' notes cannot be mistaken for the original:
                                notes darkened to improve readability are therefore coloured in a
                                bright primary colour. There is thus no doubt that the material has
                                been 'added', and in fact the material is often easier to read when
                                the colours are less closely approximated to what is thought to be
                                the original.<p>
                                    <figure>
                                        <graphic url="SanLorenzo1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                                    </figure>
                                </p><p>
                                    <figure>
                                        <graphic url="SanLorenzo2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                                    </figure>
                                </p></item>
                            <item>It is unusual to find a method of enhancement in which some
                                desirable material is not lost along with the undesirable. Often
                                there is no 'optimum' result, and a reading can only be obtained by
                                using a collation of different restorations.<p>
                                    <figure/>
                                </p></item>
                        </list>
                    </p>
                    <p>Other Projects using image processing technology are generally looking for
                        repeatable algorhythms that can be applied to a group of sources. The nature
                        of the medieval documents in the DIAMM collection means that no single
                        process can be applied to all the sources with equally satisfactory results.
                        Since colour selection also relies on the hand-positioning of a 'target'
                        over a specific colour pixel, even repeating the same operations on a single
                        page can produce startlingly different results.</p>
                    <p>More detailed and complex restoration processes are possible using
                        image-processing software, but these are not discussed here. In general, an
                        ability to look beyond the primary purpose of a piece of software and
                        explore new processes is essential in digital restoration, since no one
                        process, or group of processes, can be used on every source. Once familiar
                        with the software and comfortable with the concepts behind digital
                        restoration processes, most scholars can achieve satisfactory results.</p>


                </div>

                <div>

                    <head>Restoration samples</head>
                    <p>More information regarding techniques employed in virtual restoration may be
                        found in the DIAMM publication: <title level="m">Image Restoration
                            Workbook</title> (see News: Publications)</p>
                    <p/>
                    <div>
                        <head>Palimpsest (Oxford, Corpus Christi College MS 144)</head>
                        <p>Corpus manuscript 144 is unusual (though not unique) in containing leaves
                            from a 14th-century music book that were scraped, refinished and re-used
                            for writing another text in the 15th century (the Libermetricus de nova
                            poetria of Geoffrey of Vinsauf). The music leaves were also trimmed,
                            removing still more of the original musical text. First discovered in
                            the 1970s, the music in this manuscript has until now been virtually
                            illegible: it is clearly present, but a continuous composition could not
                            be transcribed. The following pictures show a folio of Corpus MS 144
                            before and after recovery undertaken by DIAMM. Description of the
                            process is given below in <hi rend="bold">Process</hi>.</p>
                        <p>The images on this page have been provided for viewing only by kind
                            permission of the President and Fellows of Corpus Christi College,
                            Oxford: please do not download or reproduce them.</p>
                        <p>
                            <figure>
                                <graphic url="Corpus_1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                            </figure>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            <figure>
                                <graphic url="Corpus_2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                            </figure>
                        </p>
                        <p>The images show a much reduced version of a digital image that was
                            captured at high resolution using conventional daylight balanced
                            lighting: the first image shows how the page looks to the naked eye
                            without the aid of ultra-violet light. The underlying music is barely
                            apparent, and that overlaid by text is unreadable. The second image is
                            of the same page after digital restoration. In between is an animation
                            that shows the gradual transformation of the document.</p>
                        <p>The first stage of enhancement involves the removal of the overlaid text.
                            This is done in several stages, and the text is replaced in this case by
                            a neutral background colour. Once this is done, the contrast level is
                            slightly altered to darken the underlying music and lighten the
                            background. The next stage was reached by lightening the background
                            colour, heightening the contrast between the ink colour that should be
                            retained and the colour of the parchment which can be discarded.
                            However, because the ink has faded or is there is very little of it
                            left, in places its colour is almost inseparable from the
                            background.</p>
                        <p>Compared to an undamaged source this is still not very easy to read,
                            however there is enough information now for someone familiar with the
                            style of notation of the period to read every note on the page.</p>
                        <p/>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Dirt Removal (Stratford, Shakespeare Birthplace Trust, DR 37 Vol. 41,
                            back cover)</head>
                        <p>The commonest form of ‘damage' found in medieval fragments is the simple
                            accretion of dirt. Since parchment was much tougher than paper it was
                            often used as reinforcement for binding or to form binding or a wrapper
                            itself. The Stratford source is a fascinating case study: a large vellum
                            leaf from a music manuscript (or loose-leaf collection) was reused as a
                            wrapper for paper documents. For many years it was believed that there
                            was either no music written on this face of the leaf, or that if there
                            was it was permanently lost. Inside the wrapper the leaf is remarkably
                            clean and clear and the music is in extremely good condition.</p>
                        <p>The images below have been provided for viewing only, by kind permission
                            of the Shakespeare Birthplace Trust, and may not be reproduced without
                            permission of the Trust.</p>
                        <!--<p>-->
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Stratford1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                        <!--</p>
                <p>-->
                        <figure>
                            <graphic url="Stratford2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                        </figure>
                        <!--</p>-->
                        <p>In this case a similar process was applied to the Corpus fragment, though
                            here there was negligible overwriting to exclude. However the dirt
                            accumulation on the surface was very dark, and apparently obscured any
                            notes that may have appeared. On the top left corner there were some
                            shapes that appeared to be notes when the image was magnified, and the
                            colours of these artefacts were searched across the image and darkened,
                            while areas that were clearly background were lightened. The result is
                            far from beautiful but again is now fully transcribable, not just the
                            notes, but the text too (not visible at this small size).</p>
                        <p>It is evident though from this source that even the most basic
                            restoration techniques requires editorial decisions: the restorer had to
                            decide which colours were notes, and which were background. On the
                            original image a string of rising minims was visible in the middle of
                            the top half of the page. On restoration these minims disappeared, and
                            turned out to have been in the gap between two staves. Evidently a
                            different decision on which elements to darken and which to lighten
                            would have produced a quite different result: it is believed that this
                            line of ascending notes must be an offset from another leaf, now lost,
                            and a second restoration process must be undertaken to attempt to
                            recover some of the lost offset.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Palimpsest repair and editorial process (Florence, San Lorenzo, MS
                            2211, f. 82v)</head>
                        <p>The main problem with the type of restoration shown above is that the
                            appearance of the original source is ‘falsified' by the restoration
                            process. It is possible to come to the restored image and see the
                            naturalistic colours which would imply this is the condition of the
                            original source. In presenting digital restoration it is actually much
                            more profitable, rather than darkening existing colours, to replace a
                            ‘found' colour with a completely unlikely colour, such as green, blue or
                            purple. The effect is very dramatic: not only are the notes extremely
                            clearly readable, but there is no question in the mind of the viewer
                            that this is a restored image, as it cannot be natural. In addition, the
                            areas of colour selected by the editor/restorer are clearly apparent,
                            enabling later users to make some evaluation of the accuracy of the
                            restorer's work. It has been found that this type of restoration, using
                            bright colours, yields more readable results than other processes with a
                            more ‘natural' finished appearance.</p>
                        <p>The two images below are from a major palimpsest manuscript source in
                            Florence. The music manuscript was completely scraped and refinished,
                            often to the extent that all that remains on a leaf are the very edges
                            of the music. Some pages however are better, and what can be seen once
                            the overwriting is removed is eminently transcribable, particularly as
                            it is now known that many of the works have concordances in other
                            sources which can act as a check against the found music in San Lorenzo
                            2211.</p>
                        <p>The images below are provided for viewing only by kind permission of the
                            Chapter of San Lorenzo, Florence. Please do not copy or reproduce them
                            without permission.</p>
                        <p>
                            <figure>
                                <graphic url="SanLorenzo1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                            </figure>
                        </p>
                        <p>
                            <figure>
                                <graphic url="SanLorenzo2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="img-left"/>
                            </figure>
                        </p>
                    </div>

                </div>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
