<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>DIAMM Publications</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>

            <div>
                <head>Bologna Q15: The Making and Remaking of a Musical Manuscript</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">A deluxe colour facsimile of Bologna, Museo Internazionale e
                        Biblioteca della Musica di Bologna, Ms Q.15</hi>
                </p>
                <p>LIM Editrice, Lucca, has published these volumes in collaboration with DIAMM.
                    Copies are only available through LIM or their distributors. Their website is
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.lim.it">here</ref>.</p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="Q15-1" rend="left"/></figure>This manuscript is the largest international
                    anthology of polyphonic music of the early 15th century. It was compiled in the
                    Veneto, in Padua in the early 1420s (stage I) and Vicenza in the early 1430s
                    (stages II-III), all copied by a single scribe between 1420 and 1435. The three
                    illuminations are an unusual luxury for a musical manuscript at this period. It
                    was acquired by Padre Martini in 1757 and is one of the great treasures of his
                    library in Bologna.</p>
                <p>About half of its 323 compositions are unique; some others are shared with and
                    complemented by the slightly younger Veneto manuscripts Bologna, Biblioteca
                    Universitaria 2216 and Oxford, Canon. misc. 213. It is the most important source
                    for the works of Zacara and Ciconia and for the early works of Guillaume Du Fay
                    (with 78 works, nearly a quarter of the manuscript, many of them unica). About
                    50 composers are represented, including native Italians, and composers from the
                    north who were sought after and made their careers in Italy.</p>
                <p>It is primarily a collection of mass movements (mostly Glorias and Credos, and a
                    few cycles) and motets. Du Fay's Missa Sancti Jacobi was assembled as a cycle
                    only here, and can now be linked with the circle in which Q15 was compiled. </p>
                <p>Margaret Bent tells the complete story of this manuscript in her extensive
                    introductory study, which also includes comprehensive indexes and catalogues.
                    She spells out some of the conclusions to be drawn from the partial destruction
                    of the manuscript by its own creator, a unique and extraordinary testimony to
                    changing taste and contemporary reception.</p>
                <p>Deluxe limited edition consisting of introductory study (400 pp) and facsimile
                    (686 pp), supplied with slipcase.</p>
                <p>A list of addenda and corrigenda is available <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/Q15_add-corr.pdf">here</ref>.</p>
                
            </div>
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>