<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>DIAMM Publications</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
     
         
            <div>
                <head>The Eton Choirbook</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">A full-colour facsimile edition of Eton College Library, MS
                        178</hi>
                </p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="Eton2" rend="left"/></figure>One of the most iconic of music manuscripts, the
                    Eton Choirbook is of unique importance, both in its own right as a cultural
                    artefact and as a source of English choral polyphony composed during the late
                    fifteenth and early sixteenth centuries. Had it perished, along with so many
                    other (less fortunate) pre-Reformation music manuscripts, our knowledge of a
                    critical moment in the history of English music would have been immensely
                    diminished.</p>
                <p>Ever since it was first copied for use in the college chapel in the early 1500s,
                    the choirbook has been continuously in the possession of Eton College. Several
                    composers whose works were included in it had close associations with the
                    college, not least Robert Wylkynson, who served as the college's informator
                    choristarum from 1500. Other composers represented include Banaster, Browne,
                    Cornyshe, Davy, Fawkyner, Fayrfax, Hygons, Lambe and Turges. Most of its
                    original contents (67 out of a total of 93 pieces) were votive antiphons, or
                    devotional motets of prayer and praise, sung each evening to the Virgin Mary,
                    the college's dedicatee. The Salve ceremony, familiar to worshippers throughout
                    Catholic Europe, lay at the heart of Eton College's raison d'être as a
                    chantry college: the Eton Choirbook is an eloquent witness to this flowering of
                    devotional culture on the eve of the Reformation.</p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="Eton3" rend="right"/></figure>The manuscript is also a work of consummate
                    artistry, copied by an experienced scribe on large vellum leaves, and
                    illuminated by a professional limner. Even in its in-complete state (nearly half
                    of its original 224 leaves have been lost), the Eton Choirbook is the undoubted
                    queen of early Tudor music manuscripts.</p>
                <p>The Choirbook is presented in full colour facsimile on heavy matt art paper,
                    hard bound, with an introduction by Magnus Williamson (Newcastle University) and
                    published by the Digital Image Archive of Medieval Music (University of
                    Oxford)</p>
                <p>Pages: 92 (introduction) + iv + 252 + iv</p>
                <p>Format: 427 x 306 mm (reduced from 590 x 420 mm)</p>
                <p>Images from and a detailed source descrition of the Eton Choirbook is available
                    on the DIAMM website. While the description is always available, you must be
                    logged in to DIAMM in order to see the images. Please sign up for your free
                    DIAMM account <ref type="internal" cRef="p7_2">here</ref> or log in <ref type="internal" cRef="p12_2">here.</ref> Once you have logged in, please
                    come back to this page and use the link below to be taken direct to the Eton
                    Choirbook's page.</p>
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=202">Eton Choirbook on DIAMM</ref></p>
                <p>A contents list for the manuscript can be found <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/Eton_Contents.pdf">here</ref> (PDF document)</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">Pricing and order information</hi></p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        
                        <item>Standard binding £180; Full-leather binding £250</item>
                        <item>Postage UK £10; Europe £18; Elsewhere (except N America -
                            see below) £44. Copies collected from Oxford or Eton will not
                            incur postage charge.</item>
                        
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                </p>
                
                <p>UK/Europe etc. orders or enquiries should be sent to:</p>
                <p>DIAMM, Faculty of Music, St Aldates, Oxford OX1 1DB, enclosing a cheque (payable
                    to ‘Oxford University') for the appropriate amount plus postage, and including
                    all contact details for despatch or notification if collected, or purchased
                    directly through our <ref type="external" target="http://tinyurl.com/DIAMMpubs">online shop</ref>.</p>
                <p>All orders for <hi rend="bold">USA and Canada</hi> should be made through <ref type="external" target="http://www.omifacsimiles.com">OMI Facsimile
                    sales</ref></p>
                <p>All orders for <hi rend="bold">Japan and Asia</hi> should be made through <ref type="external" target="http://www.academia-music.com">Academia
                    Music</ref></p>
                <p>Orders in <hi rend="bold">Australia and New Zealand</hi> can also be made through
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.saraband.com.au">Saraband
                        Music</ref></p>
                <p>Orders and payment may also be made electronically in any currency via our <ref type="external" target="http://tinyurl.com/DIAMMpubs">online shop</ref>.</p>
                <p>Please contact DIAMM or OMI if you wish to make multiple purchases to enquire
                    about discounts, or if you are a retailer.</p>
                <p>Download publicity leaflet <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/Eton.pdf">here</ref></p>
                <!--<figure url="EtonWeb1"/>-->
            </div>
          
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>