<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>DIAMM Publications</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>

            <div>
                <head>DIAMM Digital Restoration Workbook</head>
                <p><hi rend="bold">An introduction to digital restoration techniques using high
                    resolution digital images.</hi></p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="workbook" rend="left"/></figure>The DIAMM Digital Restoration Workbook was
                    written in response to a demand for information about digital restoration
                    techniques demonstrated by Dr Craig-McFeely at various conferences and other
                    venues. With the financial and administrative support of the AHRC ICT Methods
                    Network a workshop was organised in June 2006 for which this textbook was
                    printed. The printed copies are sold out, but as it was prepared as press-ready
                    pdf this has now been made available for download. The copy supplied is at print
                    resolution so that the colour images can be clearly read both on screen and when
                    printed.</p>
                <p>The book utilises samples and images drawn from the DIAMM collection, and the
                    images were used by the workshop participants. Due to rights
                    restrictions the images are only available for demonstration purposes and are
                    therefore not available for download. However, access
                    to the images shown in the workbook, and the samples prepared for the workshop
                    is not essential to an understanding of the techniques described, which can
                    easily be applied to any image of suitable type and resolution. The workbook has
                    proved a useful starting point for dealing with images of damaged documents for
                    researchers in many fields, both those with prior experience of digital
                    restoration and those who have never attempted to adjust an image.</p>
                <p>The techniques described make use of Adobe Photoshop, and do not require more
                    than a fairly basic knowledge of the software in order to understand the
                    descriptions. Those unfamiliar with Photoshop may need a little while to
                    familiarise themselves with the software interface before embarking on
                    restoration work using the workbook, but should find the information in the
                    workbook helpful in understanding and accessing the various tools available. All
                    the images in the book are copyright and may not be reproduced except for
                    personal research purposes. The workbook may be downloaded on the understanding
                    that it is only reproduced for personal use: it may not be reprinted and sold or
                    otherwise distributed by a third party.</p>
                <p>You may download the Workbook using the links below:</p>
                <p><ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook.pdf">Complete Workbook
                    (58Mb)</ref> | <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook1.pdf">Chapter 1</ref> | <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook2.pdf">Chapter 2</ref> | <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook3.pdf">Chapter 3</ref> | <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook4.pdf">Chapter 4</ref></p>
            </div>
       
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>