<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_9" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Alice V. Clark, Concordare cum Materia: The Tenor in the Fourteenth-century
                    Motet (PhD, Princeton University, 1996)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/Clark.pdf">Full dissertation (9.6 MB)</ref>
                </p>
                <p>This PDF is made up of images of the original dissertation. It has been scanned
                    using optical character recognition and should therefore be searchable within
                    Adobe Acrobat. This process is not perfect, however, so an electronic search of
                    the document should not be considered exhaustive.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>This study takes as its starting point the description of motet composition by
                    Egidius de Murino, who says that the tenor should "concord with the matter" of
                    the motet to be written. The repertory under consideration at this stage is the
                    French tradition of the mid-fourteenth century, mostly transmitted in the
                    complete-work manuscripts of Guillaume de Machaut (Paris, Bibliotheque
                    Nationale, MSS fonds francais 1584, 1585, 1586, 9221 and 22545-22546, and New
                    York, Wildenstein Galleries) and in the Ivrea codex (Ivrea, Biblioteca
                    Capitolare, MS 115); this group is further limited to those motets for which a
                    liturgical source has been identified for the tenor. After an introductory
                    chapter that traces modern scholarly interest in the tenor's role in the motet,
                    chapter 2 examines the evidence for compositional manipulation of borrowed
                    melodic material. The loss of liturgical propriety as a functional criterion
                    allows the tenor to serve as more than a source of melodic and harmonic
                    materials, and the possibility of alteration of a chant-based melody suggests
                    the existence of other reasons for the use of a liturgical source. One of these,
                    the use of liturgical function as a symbolic device, is explored in chapter 3,
                    with special focus on a group of French-texted amatory motets that use tenors
                    from Lent and Holy Week chants, a process that encourages an explicit comparison
                    between the lover's sufferings and the passio of Christ. Chapter 4 examines
                    another group of motets, also in French on the subject of love, that appear to
                    name historical women by the liturgical context of their tenors; these motets
                    are probably connected with the marriage or betrothal of the women named.
                    Chapter 5 considers three new tenor sources discovered during the course of this
                    study and suggests avenues for future work.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="contents">
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Abstract<ref type="pageref">iii</ref></item>
                    <item>Table of Contents<ref type="pageref">v</ref></item>
                    <item>Note on the Citation of Motets<ref type="pageref">viii</ref></item>
                    <item>Acknowledgements<ref type="pageref">ix</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 1: Introduction<ref type="pageref">1</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 2: The Tenor Melody and its Chant Source<ref type="pageref">21</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>General Characteristics<ref type="pageref">24</ref></item>
                            <item>Exact Matches<ref type="pageref">25</ref></item>
                            <item>Melodic Alteration<ref type="pageref">37</ref></item>
                            <item>Machaut<ref type="pageref">54</ref></item>
                            <item>Ivrea<ref type="pageref">65</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter 3: Liturgical Symbolism<ref type="pageref">70</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Machaut<ref type="pageref">73</ref></item>
                            <item>Ivrea<ref type="pageref">96</ref></item>
                            <item>Expanding the Range: The Chantilly Codex<ref type="pageref">111</ref></item>
                            <item>A Backward Look: The Roman de Fauvel<ref type="pageref">122</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter 4: The Vernacular Dedicatory Motet<ref type="pageref">138</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Agnes<ref type="pageref">138</ref></item>
                            <item>Lucy<ref type="pageref">153</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter 5: New Tenor Sources<ref type="pageref">161</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Displicebat ei etc.<ref type="pageref">162</ref></item>
                            <item>Non est inventus similes illi<ref type="pageref">174</ref></item>
                            <item>Magister invidie / Magister meus Christus?<ref type="pageref">181</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Appendix 1: Melodic Comparisons<ref type="pageref">185</ref></item>
                    <item>Appendix 2: Chant and Biblical Sources<ref type="pageref">237</ref></item>
                    <item>Manuscripts Cited<ref type="pageref">280</ref></item>
                    <item>Works Cited<ref type="pageref">288</ref></item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>