<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_12">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Michael Scott Cuthbert, Trecento Fragments and Polyphony Beyond the
                    Codex (PhD, Harvard University, 2006)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p> Please download from <ref type="external" target="http://www.trecento.com/dissertation/">Michael Scott Cuthbert's own
                        website</ref></p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>This thesis seeks to understand how music sounded and functioned in the Italian
                    trecento based on an examination of all the surviving sources, rather than only
                    the most complete. A majority of surviving sources of Italian polyphonic music
                    from the period 1330– 1420 are fragments; most, the remnants of lost manuscripts.
                    Despite their numerical dominance, music scholarship has viewed these sources
                    as secondary (and often neglected them altogether) focusing instead on the few
                    large, retrospective, and predominantly secular codices which mainly
                    originated in the Florentine orbit. Connections among manuscripts have been
                    incompletely explored in the literature, and the omission is acute where
                    relationships among fragments and among other small collections of polyphony are
                    concerned. These small collections vary in their construction and contents—some
                    are not really fragments at all, but single polyphonic works in liturgical and
                    other manuscripts. Individually and through their very numbers, they present a
                    wider view of Italian musical life in the fourteenth century than could be gained
                    from even the most careful scrutiny of the intact manuscripts. Examining the
                    fragments emboldens us to ask questions about musical style, popularity, scribal
                    practice, and manuscript transmission: questions best answered through a study
                    of many different sources rather than the intense scrutiny of a few large
                    sources. Our view of the trecento is transformed by moving the margins into the
                    center. Many cities emerge as producers of “high-art” polyphony. French-texted
                    music abounds in the fragments (at least fifteen sources mingle Italian and
                    French repertories). The Francophilia of the next century has long been viewed
                    as a discontinuity with the past, but it should now be considered an extension
                    of trecento practice. The space for sacred music in the trecento also increases
                    dramatically. The dissertation reports the discovery of a new Paduan fragment,
                    along with a radical reassessment of the Paduan sources. It includes 51
                    transcriptions, nearly all of unpublished works previously considered too
                    fragmentary or difficult to transcribe. Twelve new identifications of pieces
                    are made, including new sources for Esperance, Je voy mon cuer, Fuyés de moy,
                    and Mass movements by Engardus, Zachara, and Ciconia. </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <p>
                    Please go to <ref type="external" target="http://www.trecento.com/dissertation/">Michael Scott Cuthbert's own
                        website</ref> to view his table of contents.
                </p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>