<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_2"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Online Doctoral Dissertations</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_5" n="A">Allsen</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_4" n="B">Margaret Bent, Name of Dissertation</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_6" n="B">Berry</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_7" n="B">Blachly</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            -->
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_8" n="B">Roger Bowers, Choral Institutions within
                        the English Church:- Their constitution and development 1340 - 1500 (PhD,
                        University of East Anglia, 1975)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>[Taken from Introductory:] This thesis deals with the history of English
                    liturgical choirs between the years 1340 and 1500. It seeks to enlighten the
                    history of pre-Reformation English church music by relating to it the history of
                    the personnel to whom its performance was entrusted.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Five PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>

            </div>

            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_9" n="C">Alice V. Clark, Concordare cum Materia:
                        The Tenor in the Fourteenth-century Motet (PhD, Princeton University,
                        1996)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>This study takes as its starting point the description of motet composition by
                    Egidius de Murino, who says that the tenor should "concord with the matter" of
                    the motet to be written. The repertory under consideration at this stage is the
                    French tradition of the mid-fourteenth century, mostly transmitted in the
                    complete-work manuscripts of Guillaume de Machaut...</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>One PDF file, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.ramesescats.co.uk/thesis/">Julia M. Craig-McFeely, English Lute
                        Manuscripts and Scribes 1530-1630 (DPhil, University of Oxford, 1993)
                        1530-1630</ref>
                </head>
                <p>An examination of the place of the lute in 16th- and 17th-century English Society
                    through a study of the English Lute Manuscripts of the so-called 'Golden Age',
                    including a comprehensive catalogue of the sources.</p>
                <p><hi>Downloadable from author's website</hi></p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_10" n="C">Cobin</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_11" n="C">Cox</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            -->
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_12" n="C">Michael Scott Cuthbert, Trecento
                        Fragments and Polyphony Beyond the Codex (PhD, Harvard University,
                        2006)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>This thesis seeks to understand how music sounded and functioned in the Italian
                    trecento based on the examination of all the surviving sources, rather than only
                    the most complete. A majority of surviving sources of Italian polyphonic music
                    from the period 1330-1420 are fragments; most, the remnants of lost manuscripts.
                    Despite their numerical dominance, music scholarship has viewed these sources as
                    secondary...</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Many PDF files, in different formats and resolutions, downloadable from
                        author's website</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_29" n="E">Warwick A. Edwards, The sources of
                        Elizabethan consort music (PhD, Cambridge University, 1974)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>The main part of the dissertation is concerned with a detailed investigation of
                    all known sources which contain consort music estimated to have been written
                    during the period 1550 to 1600 approximately. These are over eighty in number
                    (mainly manuscripts) and range in date from c1570 to the mid-seventeenth
                    century. A second volume is devoted to a thematic catalogue in which the entire
                    repertory, listed under individual sources in Volume One, is collected together
                    and classified.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Five PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_13" n="E">Earp</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_14" n="E">Etheridge</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_15" n="H">Haggh-Hugo</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_16" n="K">Kanazawa</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_17" n="L">Layton</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            -->
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_3" n="L">Peter Martin Lefferts, The Motet in
                        England in the Fourteenth Century (PhD, Columbia University, 1983)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>The history of polyphonic music in late medieval England is difficult to
                    reconstruct on account of the paucity of intact sources, the concomitant lack of
                    a substantial number of complete pieces, and the difficulty with which the
                    surviving repertoire can be associated with any specific institutions or social
                    milieu. Nonetheless, there are significant scattered remains, and this study
                    endeavors to examine in detail one important genre, the motet...</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Two PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_18" n="N">Nadas</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            -->
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_19" n="L">Adelyn Peck Leverett, A Paleographical
                        and Repertorial Study of the Manuscript Trento, Castello del Buonconsiglio,
                        91 (1378)(PhD, Princeton University, 1990)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>This dissertation is an anaiysis of Trent 91, one of the series of
                    fifteenth-century musical manuscripts known collectively as the Trent Codices.
                    Trent 91 contains a large repertory of sacred music, most of it anonymously and
                    uniquely preserved. The following study defines, for the first time, that
                    repertory's pivotal place in the larger context of musical developments during
                    the Renaissance.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Three PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_20" n="R">Gilles Rico, Music in the Arts Faculty
                        of Paris in the Thirteenth and Early Fourteenth Centuries (DPhil, University
                        of Oxford, 2005)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>In the thirteenth-century, the city of Paris witnessed the birth of the
                    University, the gradual penetration of the new philosophical paradigm of
                    Aristotelianism and the emergence of a new theoretical discourse dealing with
                    the measurement and notation of musical time. Scholars have attempted to find
                    correlations between these three distinct phenomena. Focusing on music theory
                    sources and on other indirect testimonies, they have never satisfactorily
                    approached the central question of the teaching of music in the Arts faculty of
                    Paris. The objective of the present study is precisely to explore this terra
                    incognita.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>One PDF file, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>

            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_21" n="S">Nicholas Sandon, The Henrican Partbooks
                        Belonging to Peterhouse: A Study, with Restorations of the Incomplete
                        Compositions Contained in Them (PhD, University of Exeter, 1983)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>This dissertation examines Cambridge, University Library, Peterhouse mss 471–474,
                    four partbooks from a set of five copied late in the reign of Henry VIII, which
                    contain seventy-two pieces of Latin church music.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Two PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>

            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_31" n="S">Uri Smilansky, Rethinking <hi
                            rend="italic">Ars Subtilior</hi>: Context, Language, Study and
                        Performance (PhD, University of Exeter, 2010)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>This dissertation attempts to re-contextualise the late fourteenth and early
                    fifteenth century musical phenomenon now referred to as the Ars subtilior, in
                    terms of our modern understanding of it, as well as its relationship to wider
                    late medieval culture. In order to do so I re-examine the processes used to
                    formulate existing retrospective definitions, identify a few compelling reasons
                    why their re-evaluation is needed, and propose an alternative approach towards
                    this goal.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>One PDF file, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>

            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_22" n="S">Jason Stoessel, The Captive Scribe: The
                        context and culture of scribal and notational process in the music of the
                        ars subtilior (PhD, University of New England, 2002)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>The extant scribal record of the music of the ars subtilior is considered in
                    terms of the reception of this musical style within particular cultural
                    contexts. The first part of this study re-examines the two principal sources
                    (F-CH!564 and I-MOe5.24) of a partially shared ars subtilior repertoire and
                    concludes that, despite the presence in part of a repertoire ostensibly composed
                    north of the Alps (c. 1380-1395), these manuscripts were compiled in or close to
                    major centres on the Italian peninsula (Florence and Pisa/Bologna/Florence
                    respectively). These conclusions form the background to the second part of this
                    study that identifies cultural tendencies/influences in the notation of musical
                    rhythm in the ars subtilior repertoire.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Two PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_23" n="T">Trowell</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
-->
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_24" n="W">Jean Widaman, The Mass Ordinary
                        Settings of Arnold de Lantins: A Case Study in the Transmission of Early
                        Fifteenth-century Music (PhD, Brandeis University, 1988)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>Arnold de Lantins, a composer widely represented in the musical sources of the
                    1420s and 1430s and a singer in the papal chapel from 1431 to 1432, stood at the
                    forefront of stylistic developments of the early fifteenth century, yet his
                    music is hardly known among music historians and performers today. Although he
                    was one of the first composers to link the Gloria and Credo by motto beginnings
                    and to write a complete, musically unified Mass cycle, few of his Ordinary
                    settings are available in modern transcription and little has been written about
                    them.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Two PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>

            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_25" n="W">Magnus Williamson, The Eton Choirbook:
                        Its Institutional and Historical Background (DPhil, Oxford, 1997)</ref>
                </head>
                <p>The Eton Choirbook (Eton College Library, MS 178) is one of the most important
                    English musical codies surviving from the century before the Reformation. Its
                    significance derives from its size and quality; from its value as a source of
                    unica; and from its unbroken association with its host institution, one of the
                    foremost royal foundations of the late Middle Ages.</p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Two PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <!--
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_26" n="W">Wolinski</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>
                    <ref type="internal" cRef="p13_27" n="W">Woods</ref>
                </head>
                <p> Bit of Abstract </p>
                <p>
                    <hi>Some PDF files, downloadable</hi>
                </p>
            </div>
            -->
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
