<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_19" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Adelyn Peck Leverett, A Paleographical and Repertorial Study of the
                    Manuscript Trento, Castello del Buonconsiglio, 91 (1378)(PhD, Princeton University, 1990)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/PeckPart1.pdf">Part One (10.2 MB)</ref> | <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/PeckPart2.pdf">Part Two (3.3 MB)</ref> | <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/PeckPart3.pdf">Part Three (4.3 MB)</ref></p>

                <p>These PDFs are made up of images of the original dissertation. They have been
                    scanned using optical character recognition and should therefore be searchable
                    within Adobe Acrobat. This process is not perfect, however, so an electronic
                    search of the documents should not be considered exhaustive.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>This dissertation is an anaiysis of Trent 91, one of the series of
                    fifteenth-century musical manuscripts known collectively as the Trent Codices.
                    Trent 91 contains a large repertory of sacred music, most of it anonymously and
                    uniquely preserved. The following study defines, for the first time, that
                    repertory's pivotal place in the larger context of musical developments during
                    the Renaissance. The first chapter, which centers on an extended account of
                    Trent 91's physical formation, challenges seme widely accepted hypotheses
                    concerning the genesis of Trent 91. While for many years scholars have viewed
                    the later portions of the Trent collection as the work of a single scribe,
                    Johannes Wiser, active in Trento itself from about 1455 to 1465, both the
                    configuration and the contents of these manuscripts, including Trent 91, can be
                    more coherently explained by analyzing them as the joint creations of a number
                    of scribes working somewhat later (through most of the 1470s) and with ready
                    access to a flourishing musical life at the Imperial Court at Wiener Neustadt,
                    near Vienna. Specific support for this theory, set forward in Chapter Two, is to
                    be found in the anonymous plainchant paraphrase compositions in Trent 91. Like
                    Isaac's Choralis Constantinus from several decades later, these pieces use chant
                    melodies and liturgical orders appropriate for the Diocese of Passau, and so may
                    be from the Imperial Chapel at Wiener Neustadt, which lay within that Diocese's
                    jurisdiction. Chapter Three next turns to the repertory contained in the first
                    four fascicles of the manuscript. A close examination of the relations between
                    Trent 91's readings of some of these works and their concordances in other
                    manuscripts suggests, together with physical features of the copies themselves,
                    that this first portion of Trent 91 may have entered the collection through the
                    agency, direct or indirect, of the Flemish composer Johannes Martini, whose
                    Missa Cucu heads this portion of the manuscript. The remaining two chapters
                    cover a series of Mass Ordinary cycles previously considered to be, like the
                    repertory of the first four fascicles, imported from Franco-Flemish circles.
                    Both argue instead that these Masses, which represent two distinctive traditions
                    of Mass composition, come instead from the circle of composers resident at the
                    Imperial Court in Wiener Neustadt - chief among them Johannes Touront, whose
                    work is known almost exclusively in manuscripts from Imperial territory. A
                    concluding section assesses the possible impact of these Mass genres on Martini,
                    who may have spent several years in or near the Imperial Court circle. Through
                    Martini's later activities in Ferrara, these developments in supposedly
                    provincial Austria may have come to influence a new generation of composers,
                    such as Obrecht and Josquin, working in France and Italy.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="contents">
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Abstract<ref type="pageref">iv</ref></item>
                    <item>Acknowledgements<ref type="pageref">vi</ref></item>
                    <item>Volume One - Part I: Text <xmt:uList>
                            <item>I. Introduction: On the Creation of Trent 91<ref type="pageref">1</ref></item>
                            <item>II. Plainchant Paraphrase Compositions in Trent 91: Trent, Passau,
                                and the Imperial Court<ref type="pageref">73</ref></item>
                            <item>III. Franco-Flemish Repertory in Trent 91: The Frontispiece
                                    Collection<ref type="pageref">112</ref></item>
                            <item>IV. Masses for Three Voices in Trent 91: The Case for a Regional
                                    Tradition<ref type="pageref">170</ref></item>
                            <item>V. Parody Masses in Trent 91: Tradition and Influence<ref type="pageref">221</ref></item>
                            <item>List of Manuscripts Discussed<ref type="pageref">274</ref></item>
                            <item>Bibliography<ref type="pageref">277</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Volume Two - Part II: Illustrations, Diagrams, Tables, and Examples <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Chapter One <xmt:uList>
                                    <item>Illustrations<ref type="pageref">1</ref></item>
                                    <item>Diagrams<ref type="pageref">7</ref></item>
                                    <item>Tables<ref type="pageref">16</ref></item>
                                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                            </item>
                            <item>Chapter Two <xmt:uList>
                                    <item>Illustrations<ref type="pageref">29</ref></item>
                                    <item>Tables<ref type="pageref">31</ref></item>
                                    <item>Examples<ref type="pageref">54</ref></item>
                                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                            </item>
                            <item>Chapter Three <xmt:uList>
                                    <item>Illustrations<ref type="pageref">59</ref></item>
                                    <item>Diagrams<ref type="pageref">71</ref></item>
                                    <item>Tables<ref type="pageref">72</ref></item>
                                    <item>Examples<ref type="pagereg">89</ref></item>
                                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                            </item>
                            <item>Chapter Four <xmt:uList>
                                    <item>Tables<ref type="pageref">100</ref></item>
                                    <item>Examples<ref type="pagereg">119</ref></item>
                                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                            </item>
                            <item>Chapter Three <xmt:uList>
                                    <item>Illustrations<ref type="pageref">134</ref></item>
                                    <item>Diagrams<ref type="pageref">135</ref></item>
                                    <item>Tables<ref type="pageref">138</ref></item>
                                    <item>Examples<ref type="pagereg">159</ref></item>
                                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                            </item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Part III: Transcriptions of Anonymous Compositions
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>1. Missa Regina caeli laetare<ref type="pageref">172</ref></item>
                        <item>2. Gloria<ref type="pageref">197</ref></item>
                        <item>3. Benedicamus domino<ref type="pageref">203</ref></item>
                        <item>4. Te deum<ref type="pageref">206</ref></item>
                        <item>5. Credo<ref type="pageref">213</ref></item>
                        <item>6. Missa sine nomine<ref type="pageref">220</ref></item>
                        <item>7. Missa Zersundert ist das junge Herze mein<ref type="pageref">235</ref></item>
                        <item>8. Introit Vultum tuum deprecabuntur<ref type="pageref">254</ref></item>
                        <item>9. Introit Gaudeamus omnes<ref type="pageref">256</ref></item>
                        <item>10. Introit Salve sancta parens (I)<ref type="pageref">259</ref></item>
                        <item>11. Introit Salve sancta parens (II)<ref type="pageref">264</ref></item>
                        <item>12. Introit Rorarte caeli<ref type="pageref">267</ref></item>
                        <item>13. Introit Benedicta sit<ref type="pageref">270</ref></item>
                        <item>14. Missa Gentil madonna mia<ref type="pageref">272</ref></item>
                        <item>Notes to the Transcriptions<ref type="pageref">302</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>