<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_20" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Gilles Rico, Music in the Arts Faculty of Paris in the Thirteenth and Early
                    Fourteenth Centuries (DPhil, University of Oxford, 2005)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/RicoFull.pdf">Full dissertation (5.6 MB)</ref>
                </p>
                <p>This PDF document is fully searchable. It was created from the original
                    electronic word-processed files.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>In the thirteenth-century, the city of Paris witnessed the birth of the
                    University, the gradual penetration of the new philosophical paradigm of
                    Aristotelianism and the emergence of a new theoretical discourse dealing with
                    the measurement and notation of musical time. Scholars have attempted to find
                    correlations between these three distinct phenomena. Focusing on music theory
                    sources and on other indirect testimonies, they have never satisfactorily
                    approached the central question of the teaching of music in the Arts faculty of
                    Paris. The objective of the present study is precisely to explore this <hi rend="italic">terra
                        incognita</hi>. This exploration will take as a point of departure a
                    multiplicity of hitherto unpublished sources, produced by the Parisian masters
                    of Arts, likely to yield insightful information about the form and the content
                    of the teaching of music in the Arts faculty of Paris in the thirteenth and
                    early fourteenth centuries. It will be asserted that the teaching of music in
                    the institution was confined to <hi rend="italic">musica</hi> as an intellectual discipline.
                    It involved commenting a textbook and discussing scholastic <hi rend="italic">questiones</hi>
                    about musical issues and was profoundly influenced by the gradual change of
                        <hi rend="italic">epistemé</hi> brought about by the study of Aristotelian natural
                    philosophy. Reconstructing the nature and function of music teaching in the Arts
                    faculty will lead to the reassessment of the role played by the institution in
                    the developments of <hi rend="italic">musica mensurabilis</hi>. It will be demonstrated that,
                    contrary to what has been asserted, the University authorities do not seem to
                    have fostered the cultivation of measured polyphony. Correlatively it will also
                    be shown that influence of the Arts faculty and of its intellectual orientations
                    on the elaboration and shaping of the theoretical discourse on rhythmic notation
                    has been largely overestimated.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="contents">
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Acknolowledgements<ref type="pageref">ii</ref></item>
                    <item>Abbreviations<ref type="pageref">iii</ref></item>
                    <item>Introduction<ref type="pageref">1</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 1 <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Teaching Music at the Arts Faculty of Paris: A Reappraisal<ref type="pageref">14</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter 2
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Thirteenth- and Early Fourteenth-Century Glosses on Boethius' De institutione musica<ref type="pageref">76</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter 3
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Music in Parisian Commentaries on Aristotle<ref type="pageref">149</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter 4
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Scholastic Questions on Music from the Arts Faculty of Paris<ref type="pageref">187</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter 5
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Polyphony, Musica Mensurabilis and the Arts Faculty<ref type="pageref">238</ref></item>
                    </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Conclusion<ref type="pageref">299</ref></item>
                    <item>Appendix A<ref type="pageref">308</ref></item>
                    <item>Bibliography<ref type="pageref">311</ref></item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>