<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_21" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Nicholas Sandon, The Henrican Partbooks Belonging to Peterhouse, Cambridge
                    (Cambridge, University Library, Peterhouse Manuscripts 471-474): A Study, with
                    Restorations of the Incomplete Compositions Contained In Them (PhD, University of Exeter, 1983)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/Sandon12.pdf">Chapters 1 and 2 (26.5 MB)</ref> |
                        <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/Sandon34.pdf">Chapters 3 through 7 and musical
                        appendix (23 MB)</ref></p>
                <p>These 8 chapters represent Volume 1 of the original thesis. Volume 2 contained
                    musical editions which have now been published by Antico Edition and therefore
                    not included.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>This first volume of this dissertation examines Cambridge, University Library,
                    Peterhouse mss 471–474, four partbooks from a set of five copied late in the
                    reign of Henry VIII, which contain seventy-two pieces of Latin church music. The
                    first chapter discusses the presence at Peterhouse of this set, investigates its
                    relationship to the Caroline partbooks belonging to the college and suggests
                    means by which this collection of manuscripts could have come to Peterhouse. The
                    second chapter is a palaeographical study of mss 471–474 and seeks to discover
                    the processes by which they were copied; they are found to have been the work of
                    a single scribe. The third chapter brings together biographical information from
                    published and unpublished sources on the composers represented in the books.
                    After referring to conflicting ways in which scholars have interpreted the
                    existence of these books, the fourth chapter provides a new interpretation by
                    relating the palaeographical and biographical evidence to the circumstances of
                    English religious history in the last decade of Henry's reign: it is suggested
                    that most of the repertory in the books was copied from manuscripts belonging to
                    Magdalen College, Oxford, probably in 1540–41, and that the books were intended
                    for use at the New Foundation cathedral at Canterbury; an identity is suggested
                    for the scribe. If the general thrust of the argument is accepted, the
                    conservatism of much of the music in Ph must be considered typical of church
                    music in England at this time. The fifth chapter justifies the practice of
                    restoring voices missing from compositions of this period and describes some of
                    the problems and solutions involved; working notes including analysis and
                    stylistic comment are provided for the fifty restored compositions originally
                    presented in the second volume. The sixth chapter introduces and presents the
                    Latin texts with English translations. The seventh and last chapter consists of
                    a critical commentary. The two original appendices contained short essays on
                    more peripheral topics that arose during the research; these appendices are not
                    included in the present revision because articles based on them have appeared
                    elsewhere. A musical appendix presents the cantus firmi and other material
                    associated with the incomplete compositions.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="contents">
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Title Page<ref type="pageref">i</ref></item>
                    <item>Dedication<ref type="pageref">ii</ref></item>
                    <item>Table of Contents<ref type="pageref">iii</ref></item>
                    <item>Editions, originally included in the dissertation, now published by Antico
                            Edition<ref type="pageref">iv</ref></item>
                    <item>Introduction to the original version<ref type="pageref">v</ref></item>
                    <item>Introduction to the revised version<ref type="pageref">v</ref></item>
                    <item>Summary<ref type="pageref">vii</ref></item>
                    <item>Abbreviations<ref type="pageref">ix</ref></item>
                    <item>Bibliograhpy<ref type="pageref">xi</ref></item>
                    <item>Supplementary Bibliography<ref type="pageref">xix</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter One: The musical manuscripts at Peterhouse <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: Introduction<ref type="pagereg">1</ref></item>
                            <item>2: A summary of previous content<ref type="pageref">2</ref></item>
                            <item>3: The Henrican and Caroline sets and their presence at
                                    Peterhouse<ref type="pageref">5</ref></item>
                            <item>4. A preliminary description and inventory of the Henrican set
                                    (Ph)<ref type="pageref">8</ref></item>
                            <item>5. Inventory<ref type="pageref">15</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter Two: A palaeographical study of Ph <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: Collation<ref type="pageref">25</ref></item>
                            <item>2: Interpolations and foliation<ref type="pageref">30</ref></item>
                            <item>3: The indexes<ref type="pageref">33</ref></item>
                            <item>4: At what stage were the books first bound?<ref type="pageref">35</ref></item>
                            <item>5: Layout and staves<ref type="pageref">36</ref></item>
                            <item>6: The music hand and notation<ref type="pageref">41</ref></item>
                            <item>7: The text hands<ref type="pageref">48</ref></item>
                            <item>8: The scribe's method of working<ref type="pageref">52</ref></item>
                            <item>9: Mistakes and their correction<ref type="pageref">62</ref></item>
                            <item>10: The scribe's attitude to his exemplars<ref type="pageref">67</ref></item>
                            <item>11: The watermarks<ref type="pageref">69</ref></item>
                            <item>12: Groupings in Ph<ref type="pageref">75</ref></item>
                            <item>13: The relationship of Ph to other English sources<ref type="pageref">79</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter Three: The composers represented in Ph<ref type="pageref">83</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter Four: The provenance, destination and interpretation of Ph <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: The problem of interpretation<ref type="pageref">115</ref></item>
                            <item>2: The provenance of the music<ref type="pageref">121</ref></item>
                            <item>3: The destination of the partbooks<ref type="pageref">125</ref></item>
                            <item>4: The implications of the collection<ref type="pageref">138</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter Five: Restoring the incomplete compositions <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: Introduction<ref type="pageref">147</ref></item>
                            <item>2: Notes on the restoration of individual compositions<ref type="pageref">150</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter Six: Latin texts and English translations <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: Introduction<ref type="pageref">197</ref></item>
                            <item>2: Texts and translations<ref type="pageref">203</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Chapter Seven: Critical Commentary <xmt:uList>
                            <item>1: Introduction<ref type="pageref">239</ref></item>
                            <item>2: List of concordant sources<ref type="pageref">240</ref></item>
                            <item>3: Commentary<ref type="pageref">244</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList></item>
                    <item>Musical Appendix: Cantus firmus and other material used in the incomplete
                            compositions<ref type="pageref">271</ref></item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>