<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p13_31"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Uri Smilansky, Rethinking <hi rend="italic">Ars Subtilior</hi>: Context,
                    Language, Study and Performance (PhD, University of Exeter, 2010)</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-11-29" who="Charlotte Tupman">Created</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head/>

            <div>
                <head>PDF Download Links</head>

                <!-- PDF links -->
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/Sandon12.pdf"
                        >Full dissertation (8.7 MB)</ref></p>
                <p>This PDF is an electronic version of the original dissertation and should
                    therefore be searchable within Adobe Acrobat.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Abstract</head>
                <!-- Abstract -->
                <p>This dissertation attempts to re-contextualise the late fourteenth and early
                    fifteenth century musical phenomenon now referred to as the Ars subtilior, in
                    terms of our modern understanding of it, as well as its relationship to wider
                    late medieval culture. In order to do so I re-examine the processes used to
                    formulate existing retrospective definitions, identify a few compelling reasons
                    why their re-evaluation is needed, and propose an alternative approach towards
                    this goal. My research has led me to analyse the modern preoccupation with this
                    repertoire, both in musicology and performance, and to explore external
                    influences impinging on our attitudes towards it. Having outlined current
                    attitudes and the problems of their crystallisation, I seek to re-contextualise
                    them within medieval culture through a survey of the surviving physical
                    evidence. The resulting observations highlight the difficulties we face when
                    looking at the material. Above all, they point at the problems created by using
                    narrow definitions of this style, whether these are technical, geographic,
                    temporal or intellectual. My observations shed some light on the scale,
                    complexity and relevance of the Ars subtilior phenomenon. The next step is to
                    look at the music itself by analysing the use and function of stylistic features
                    that distinguish the style. As my goal is to conceptualise the style as a whole,
                    and not merely isolate interesting events within it, the variety of stylistic
                    features examined is wider than those traditionally defined as characteristic of
                    Ars subtilior. A series of case-studies examine the validity and usefulness of
                    my conceptualisations, and attempt to couple modern inquiry into technique with
                    an understanding of its place within medieval culture and society. In my
                    conclusion, I attempt to bring the different strands together by proposing a new
                    conceptualisation of the Ars subtilior which takes our understanding of medieval
                    history and thought-patterns as a starting point, and proves useful also in a
                    modern context. My proposal revolves around the concept of „exceptionality‟
                    within a culture that seeks legitimacy. I have formulated it to make sense of
                    the apparent appeal of this music to medieval performers, audiences, patrons,
                    composers, compilers and collectors. Status and meaning was created by
                    attracting attention to a work as a whole, or specific locations within its
                    music or text, through the deviation from older or newly created norms. At the
                    heart of my conceptualisation though, are its modern implications. My goal in
                    this work is to transcend the technicalities of the Ars subtilior and supply
                    scholars and performers with the tools to interpret and perform its music
                    expressively, finding meaning in this unique musical phenomenon.</p>
            </div>
            <div type="contents">
                <head>Table of Contents</head>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Abstract<ref type="pageref">2</ref></item>
                    <item>Table of Contents<ref type="pageref">3</ref></item>
                    <item>Tables and examples<ref type="pageref">6</ref></item>
                    <item>Manuscript signatures<ref type="pageref">9</ref></item>
                    <item>Abbreviations<ref type="pageref">12</ref></item>
                    <item>Introduction<ref type="pageref">14</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 1: <hi rend="italic">Ars subtilior</hi> research and performance - a historiography<ref type="pageref">22</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 2: <hi rend="italic">Ars subtilior</hi> manuscripts and distribution<ref type="pageref">54</ref></item>
                    <item>Chapter 3: Composers and society <ref type="pageref">84</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>i. The surviving materials<ref type="pageref">85</ref></item>
                            <item>ii. Order of evidence<ref type="pageref">92</ref></item>
                            <item>iii. Interpretation<ref type="pageref">103</ref></item>
                            <item>Conclusion<ref type="pageref">112</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter 4: Features of <hi rend="italic">Ars subtilior</hi> style <ref type="pageref">138</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Genre and register<ref type="pageref">116</ref></item>
                            <item>Mode, setting and pitch-structures<ref type="pageref">121</ref></item>
                            <item>Melody and counterpoint<ref type="pageref">148</ref></item>
                            <item>Rhythm and notation<ref type="pageref"
                                    >160</ref></item>
                            <item>Visuality<ref type="pageref">186</ref></item>
                            <item>Text and language<ref type="pageref">192</ref></item>
                            <item>Conclusion<ref type="pageref">195</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/></item>
                    <item>Chapter 5: Case Studies<ref type="pageref"
                        >206</ref>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Displicebat ei etc.<ref type="pageref">262</ref></item>
                            <item>Non est inventus similes illi<ref type="pageref">274</ref></item>
                            <item>Magister invidie / Magister meus Christus?<ref type="pageref">281</ref></item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/>
                    </item>
                    <item>Chapter 6: Conclusion - a working definition for <hi rend="italic">Ars subtilior</hi> style<ref type="pageref">283</ref></item>
                    <item>Bibliography<ref type="pageref">306</ref></item>
                    <item>List of recordings<ref type="pageref">328</ref></item>
                </xmt:uList>
                <p/>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
