<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_7_3"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Information in Archive</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-05" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>


            <div>
                <head>The Information in the Archive</head>

                <div>
                    <head>I can't find the manuscript I'm looking for, even though I know it is in
                        the relevant library, archive, private collection.</head>
                    <p>Assuming there is no error in your information about the library, or that the
                        shelf mark has not been changed, the most common reason for this is that the
                        manuscript falls outside the date or musical parameters that define this
                        project:</p>
                    <p>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>We do not list any plainchant manuscripts: DIAMM contains (at
                                present) only sources of polyphonic music. </item>
                            <item>The manuscript you are looking for may fall outside the dates of
                                the project. At the moment, although there is some flexibility, we
                                cut off at about 1550.</item>
                            <item>It may be possible that you are actually looking for a printed
                                book, not a manuscript. One of the reasons for the 1550 cutoff date
                                is that from 1500 onwards music was increasingly reproduced in
                                print, and multiple copies of these types of book survive, making
                                them easier to access in person.</item>
                        </xmt:uList><p/>
                    </p>
                    <p>The final reason why a manuscript may not be listed is that we do not know
                        about it. If you think the manuscript in question is one that we should list
                        as it contains polyphony and falls within the remit of the project, then
                        please contact us and let us know about the book so that we can add it to
                        the database. Your contribution in bringing it to our notice will be
                        publicly acknowledged.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I want to find all the works of a particular composer: how do I do
                        this?</head>
                    <p>Unfortunately we don't have inventories that would allow you to do this yet,
                        but these should be brought online during 2010-2011. If a manuscript is
                        listed in the Census Catalogue (CCM) this lists the names of composers
                        represented in the manuscript. This information is stored in the Source
                        Description field, and you may be able to find most of the relevant
                        manuscripts by entering the name of the composer you wish to find in the
                        Source Description free text field on the Search page.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>How do I find out which pages in a manuscript have the pieces that I
                        want?</head>
                    <p>Unfortunately we don't have inventories yet, but these should be brought
                        online during 2010-2011. You could look through the RISM pages until you get
                        to the inventory section IF the MS is listed in RISM. Unfortunately if it's
                        only listed in CCM you're not likely to find what you want yet, but we're
                        working on it. Sometimes the prose description lists specific composers or
                        pieces along with folio numbers, so check that too.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>What does [pr. bk.] mean, preceding some shelf marks?</head>
                    <p>Printed book. This is usually a book of printed music with additions by hand.
                        Sometimes there is no music in the book except those items added by
                        hand.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Why are there no pictures available for the manuscript that I'm interested
                        in?</head>
                    <p>We haven't photographed it yet (or had it photographed for us).</p>
                    <p>DIAMM lists all the known manuscripts of Medieval Music in the world. There
                        are over 3100 manuscripts in the database so far and this number grows
                        constantly. We only have pictures for some of these sources; since starting
                        in 1998 we have only had the finances available to negotiate rights and
                        travel to photograph documents for about 6 months in total. The images we
                        have represent this work, which was spread over about 5 years. We
                        concentrated first on obtaining pictures of fragments, since these are
                        sources that are most neglected. Most individuals would not consider it
                        cost-effective to visit a library just to see one leaf of music, whereas to
                        travel in order to see a whole manuscript is more worthwhile.</p>
                    <p>Having photographed the fragments on our primary list we added some of the
                        more important complete manuscripts, and have obtained as many further items
                        as possible within the limitations of our funding.</p>
                    <p>There are a small number of important sources that have been photographed by
                        DIAMM, but for which we were unable at the time to obtain the additional
                        permission needed to make these images available on the website. We are
                        currently negotiating with these libraries to extend the permission to allow
                        web-delivery, and these images will be brought online as soon as
                        possible.</p>
                    <p>If you have a request for a particular manuscript, please let the project
                        manager or research assistant know, and we will put this on our priority
                        list if funding for further digitization becomes available. You could also
                        subscribe to our RSS news page, which will inform you when any new material
                        is added to the online collection. You may be able to obtain a grant to have
                        digital images made by a library, or to have DIAMM travel to the library and
                        make them for you. If you are considering this course please contact DIAMM
                            <hi rend="bold">before</hi> ordering the images for advice on how to
                        ensure you get images of suitable quality, or visit our <ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p11">Services page</ref> for information on preparing a grant
                        application in conjunction with DIAMM.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Are there plans to digitize the manuscripts that are not included in the
                        collection yet?</head>
                    <p>Yes, but digitization work is costly, and DIAMM does not have a regular
                        income that can pay for this activity. We are currently without funding to
                        create new digital images, but through various collaborations with
                        institutions and with individual scholars we are making grant applications
                        to obtain digital images of specific collections that will then be made
                        available through the site.</p>
                    <p>If you have a request for a particular manuscript, please let the project
                        manager or research assistant know, and we will put this on our priority
                        list if funding for further digitization becomes available. You could also
                        subscribe to our RSS news page, which will inform you when any new material
                        is added to the online collection. You may be able to obtain a grant to have
                        digital images made by a library, or to have DIAMM travel to the library and
                        make them for you. If you are considering this course please contact DIAMM
                            <hi rend="bold">before</hi> ordering the images for advice on how to
                        ensure you get images of suitable quality, or visit our <ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p11">Services page</ref> for information on preparing a grant
                        application in conjunction with DIAMM.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I have digital images of a manuscript that you do not have: can I donate
                        them to the online collection?</head>
                    <p>If you own the rights in the images we would be very grateful to receive them
                        to add to our online collection if they are of suitable quality for online
                        presentation. If you are not the owner of the document you, or DIAMM, would
                        need to check that there would be no rights issues raised by donating them
                        to DIAMM. Please contact the Project Manager for further details.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I am a collection holder and would like to have my manuscripts
                        photographed by DIAMM. How can I arrange this?</head>
                    <p>DIAMM is available for digitization work on a consultancy basis. You can find
                        details of our consultancy availability on <ref type="internal" cRef="p11"
                            >this page.</ref> DIAMM is available to digitize, or advise on the
                        digitization of any document collection; it does not have to be medieval,
                        manuscript or music.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I have done research on a manuscript but it is not published. However, the
                        information I have is more up-to-date than that on the DIAMM website. What
                        should I do?</head>
                    <p>Assuming you are willing to share your information, we would be very grateful
                        to receive a copy of any work you have done on any manuscript source. The
                        information will be added to the website with full credit given to the
                        author. Since this material is thus ‘published' online it will count as a
                        research output for you. If you subsequently publish the material elsewhere
                        you should inform the publisher in advance that it already appears in some
                        form on the DIAMM website.</p>

                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Does DIAMM only digitize music, or only medieval manuscripts?</head>
                    <p>DIAMM will digitize just about anything (as long as it is not illegal,
                        pornographic, copyright or for any other nefarious purpose). We prefer our
                        objects to be flat (books, pictures, maps etc.), but apart from that we are
                        able to digitize most items and most types of collection. If we feel our
                        approach is not suitable for your collection we will pass you on to other
                        experts in the appropriate fields. For more information about hiring DIAMM
                        to undertake digitization work for you, please see the <ref type="internal"
                            cRef="p11">Services page.</ref>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>The music looks very different from the music I usually play/sing. How can
                        I learn how to understand this notation?</head>
                    <p>There are two books that describe how Medieval Music notation works: Apel,
                        Willi: <hi rend="bold">The Notation of Polyphonic Music 900-1600</hi>
                        (Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1942. (4th ed., 1949)) – this may not be in
                        print, but is available from most libraries that have a (classical) music
                        section. Rastall, Richard: <hi rend="bold">The Notation of Western Music: an
                            introduction</hi> (St Martin's Press, New York, 1982)</p>
                    <p>If you are looking for a historical introduction to Medieval Music the
                        following is recommended: Hoppin, Richard H: <hi rend="bold">Medieval
                            Music</hi> (New York: W. W. Norton, 1978)</p>
                </div>

                <div>
                    <head>I'm interested in researching my family history. Where can I find out
                        about them?</head>
                    <p>DIAMM contains no information about family history. This is a resource for
                        studying Medieval Music Manuscripts. By searching you may find a name or
                        names that seem relevant to you, but there is no genealogical information
                        created from these names.</p>
                </div>
            </div>


        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
