<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_7"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>FAQ</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-05" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>FAQ</head>
                <!-- <div part="N" sample="complete" org="uniform">
                <head>General use</head>-->
                <div>
                    <p> This FAQ list was compiled on the basis of questions sent to the DIAMM team
                        since 1998. </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Website Usage and Functions</head>
                    <div>
                        <head>I have an account. How do I log in?</head>
                        <p>To log in, please click on the 'MyDIAMM' tab at the top of the page,
                            underneath the logo.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>How do I see the full-sized images?</head>
                        <p>You must be logged in to see the full-sized images. If you do not have an
                            account you can create one within a couple of minutes by completing the
                            information on the <ref type="db" target="createnewuser.jsp">Register
                                page</ref>. Account details will be sent to you by e-mail, so you
                            must have an e-mail account to register, and access to your e-mail as
                            your password will be sent to that account. Once you are logged in you
                            can use the search function to find manuscripts that have images
                            available or, if you know which manuscript you want to view, you can go
                            there using the Browse menus. Once you reach the source description page
                            you will see a ‘tab' entitled ‘Images'. Under this tab you will find
                            thumbnails for all images associated with the manuscript. Clicking on a
                            thumbnail will load the image viewer with the full-sized image. Note: if
                            you are not logged in the thumbnails do not become live links: the link
                            only works once you are logged in. </p>
                    </div>

                    <div>
                        <head>Why can't I see the full-sized images when I click on a thumbnail,
                            even if I'm logged in?</head>
                        <p> Make sure you have the correct version of the Flash plugin for your
                            browser. You can download that <ref type="external"
                                target="http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/">here.</ref>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Nothing seems to work right. I keep getting error messages.</head>
                        <p>Some browsers work better with the website than others. You could try
                            using a different browser if you are using one that is not very
                            common.</p>
                        <p>Please also make sure that you are using the most recent version of your
                            browser.</p>
                        <p>Internet Explorer for Macintosh is not supported.</p>
                        <p>The website may be undergoing a technical upgrade or an upload. Try
                            visiting again later.</p>
                        <p>If the error persists you should report it to the project manager, but
                            please include the following information:</p>
                        <p>
                            <xmt:uList>
                                <item>Your operating system</item>
                                <item>Your browser software, including version number if
                                    possible</item>
                                <item>What you did to cause the error (i.e. which link you clicked
                                    on, or which search you performed).</item>
                                <item>If possible include the URL of the page</item>
                                <item>If possible, cut and paste the http error information into
                                    your e-mail.</item>
                            </xmt:uList><p/>
                        </p>
                        <p>If are having technical trouble, please try to use the <ref
                                type="internal" cRef="p2_9">Feedback Form.</ref> If this is
                            impossible, please email <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk"
                                >the Project Manager.</ref></p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>How can I let other scholars know that I am working on a particular
                            manuscript?</head>
                        <p>You can use the Public Comments tool to indicate to other users the
                            images that you are working on or that you are interested in. You may
                            include your contact details in the comment so that people can get in
                            touch with you if they wish. To foil spam e-mail harvesters we advise
                            that you replace the ‘@' sign in your e-mail address with ‘[at]'.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>How can I contact other scholars who may be working on the same
                            repertory as me?</head>

                        <p>You can use the Public Comments tool to indicate to other users the
                            images that you are working on or that you are interested in and ask
                            them to contact you. You may include your contact details in the
                            comment. To foil spam e-mail harvesters we advise that you replace the
                            ‘@' sign in your e-mail address with ‘[at]'.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I want to put my digital collection online and have been looking at
                            your delivery mechanism. Can I buy the software to create my own
                            collection using your methods?</head>
                        <p>The delivery system used for DIAMM was custom-designed for us, and cannot
                            currently be bought as a software package (although it is all
                            open-source). It involved several years of technical development and
                            considerable cost. However you can contact our design and technical team
                            and they will be happy to discuss your needs and what would be necessary
                            to adapt the DIAMM model to your needs, since it was built with a
                            transferable end-use in mind. Since the framework is now designed, other
                            projects would not be faced with the enormous cost of developing this
                            from scratch, and we welcome interest from other projects or
                            institutions in using this delivery system with other collections.
                            Please contact Paul Vetch, our technical consultant at the Centre for
                            Computing in the Humanities at King's College, London on
                            paul.vetch[at]kcl.ac.uk</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>How do I ask DIAMM to take pictures of manuscripts for me or anything
                            else?</head>
                        <p>DIAMM offers an extensive array of consulting services for hire by
                            anyone. Please see our <ref type="internal" cRef="p11">services</ref>
                            section for more information.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I do not have access to the internet. Will I be able to use the
                            website?</head>
                        <p>Probably not. If you can gain access to the internet you will be able to
                            use the website and, indeed, read this answer.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Registration and Your MyDIAMM account</head>
                    <div>
                        <head>Do I have to be employed in a University to register?</head>
                        <p>No, anyone can register to use the site and view the images.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Is it possible for my institution to obtain an institutional IP
                            address to register anyone within our IP range for use of the
                            website?</head>
                        <p>Use of the features associated with image browsing is dependent on
                            individual login. Users cannot create a personalised workspace unless
                            they have a personal login. Since creating a user account is so quick,
                            this should not be a problem for the members of your institution.</p>
                        <p>One advantage of individual user accounts is to ensure that anyone
                            entering spurious material in the public comments or transcriptions
                            fields is identified. This helps to avoid spam, pornography and other
                            undesirable material from appearing on the website.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I'm not affiliated with any institution: can I still register to use
                            the website?</head>
                        <p>Anyone can register to use the site and view the images. You do not have
                            to be an academic, employed, or a musician to use and appreciate the
                            content.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I am not a musician or a medievalist, can I register to use the
                            website?</head>
                        <p>Anyone can register to use the site and view the images. You do not have
                            to be an academic, employed, or a musician to use and appreciate the
                            content.</p>
                    </div>


                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>The Information in the Archive</head>
                    <div>
                        <head>I can't find the manuscript I'm looking for, even though I know it is
                            in the relevant library, archive, private collection.</head>
                        <p>Assuming there is no error in your information about the library, or that
                            the shelf mark has not been changed, the most common reason for this is
                            that the manuscript falls outside the date or musical parameters that
                            define this project:</p>
                        <p>
                            <xmt:uList>
                                <item>We do not list any plainchant manuscripts: DIAMM contains (at
                                    present) only sources of polyphonic music. </item>
                                <item>The manuscript you are looking for may fall outside the dates
                                    of the project. At the moment, although there is some
                                    flexibility, we cut off at about 1550.</item>
                                <item>It may be possible that you are actually looking for a printed
                                    book, not a manuscript. One of the reasons for the 1550 cutoff
                                    date is that from 1500 onwards music was increasingly reproduced
                                    in print, and multiple copies of these types of book survive,
                                    making them easier to access in person.</item>
                            </xmt:uList><p/>
                        </p>
                        <p>The final reason why a manuscript may not be listed is that we do not
                            know about it. If you think the manuscript in question is one that we
                            should list as it contains polyphony and falls within the remit of the
                            project, then please contact us and let us know about the book so that
                            we can add it to the database. Your contribution in bringing it to our
                            notice will be publicly acknowledged.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I want to find all the works of a particular composer: how do I do
                            this?</head>
                        <p>Unfortunately we don't have inventories that would allow you to do this
                            yet, but these should be brought online during 2010-2011. If a
                            manuscript is listed in the Census Catalogue (CCM) this lists the names
                            of composers represented in the manuscript. This information is stored
                            in the Source Description field, and you may be able to find most of the
                            relevant manuscripts by entering the name of the composer you wish to
                            find in the Source Description free text field on the Search page.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>How do I find out which pages in a manuscript have the pieces that I
                            want?</head>
                        <p>Unfortunately we don't have inventories yet, but these should be brought
                            online during 2010-2011. You could look through the RISM pages until you
                            get to the inventory section IF the MS is listed in RISM. Unfortunately
                            if it's only listed in CCM you're not likely to find what you want yet,
                            but we're working on it. Sometimes the prose description lists specific
                            composers or pieces along with folio numbers, so check that too.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>What does [pr. bk.] mean, preceding some shelf marks?</head>
                        <p>Printed book. This is usually a book of printed music with additions by
                            hand. Sometimes there is no music in the book except those items added
                            by hand.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Why are there no pictures available for the manuscript that I'm
                            interested in?</head>
                        <p>We haven't photographed it yet (or had it photographed for us).</p>
                        <p>DIAMM lists all the known manuscripts of Medieval Music in the world.
                            There are over 3100 manuscripts in the database so far and this number
                            grows constantly. We only have pictures for some of these sources; since
                            starting in 1998 we have only had the finances available to negotiate
                            rights and travel to photograph documents for about 6 months in total.
                            The images we have represent this work, which was spread over about 5
                            years. We concentrated first on obtaining pictures of fragments, since
                            these are sources that are most neglected. Most individuals would not
                            consider it cost-effective to visit a library just to see one leaf of
                            music, whereas to travel in order to see a whole manuscript is more
                            worthwhile.</p>
                        <p>Having photographed the fragments on our primary list we added some of
                            the more important complete manuscripts, and have obtained as many
                            further items as possible within the limitations of our funding.</p>
                        <p>There are a small number of important sources that have been photographed
                            by DIAMM, but for which we were unable at the time to obtain the
                            additional permission needed to make these images available on the
                            website. We are currently negotiating with these libraries to extend the
                            permission to allow web-delivery, and these images will be brought
                            online as soon as possible.</p>
                        <p>If you have a request for a particular manuscript, please let the project
                            manager or research assistant know, and we will put this on our priority
                            list if funding for further digitization becomes available. You could
                            also subscribe to our RSS news page, which will inform you when any new
                            material is added to the online collection. You may be able to obtain a
                            grant to have digital images made by a library, or to have DIAMM travel
                            to the library and make them for you. If you are considering this course
                            please contact DIAMM <hi rend="bold">before</hi> ordering the images for
                            advice on how to ensure you get images of suitable quality, or visit our
                                <ref type="internal" cRef="p11">Services page</ref> for information
                            on preparing a grant application in conjunction with DIAMM.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Are there plans to digitize the manuscripts that are not included in
                            the collection yet?</head>
                        <p>Yes, but digitization work is costly, and DIAMM does not have a regular
                            income that can pay for this activity. We are currently without funding
                            to create new digital images, but through various collaborations with
                            institutions and with individual scholars we are making grant
                            applications to obtain digital images of specific collections that will
                            then be made available through the site.</p>
                        <p>If you have a request for a particular manuscript, please let the project
                            manager or research assistant know, and we will put this on our priority
                            list if funding for further digitization becomes available. You could
                            also subscribe to our RSS news page, which will inform you when any new
                            material is added to the online collection. You may be able to obtain a
                            grant to have digital images made by a library, or to have DIAMM travel
                            to the library and make them for you. If you are considering this course
                            please contact DIAMM <hi rend="bold">before</hi> ordering the images for
                            advice on how to ensure you get images of suitable quality, or visit our
                                <ref type="internal" cRef="p11">Services page</ref> for information
                            on preparing a grant application in conjunction with DIAMM.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I have digital images of a manuscript that you do not have: can I
                            donate them to the online collection?</head>
                        <p>If you own the rights in the images we would be very grateful to receive
                            them to add to our online collection if they are of suitable quality for
                            online presentation. If you are not the owner of the document you, or
                            DIAMM, would need to check that there would be no rights issues raised
                            by donating them to DIAMM. Please contact the Project Manager for
                            further details.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I am a collection holder and would like to have my manuscripts
                            photographed by DIAMM. How can I arrange this?</head>
                        <p>DIAMM is available for digitization work on a consultancy basis. You can
                            find details of our consultancy availability on <ref type="internal"
                                cRef="p11">this page.</ref> DIAMM is available to digitize, or
                            advise on the digitization of any document collection; it does not have
                            to be medieval, manuscript or music.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I have done research on a manuscript but it is not published. However,
                            the information I have is more up-to-date than that on the DIAMM
                            website. What should I do?</head>
                        <p>Assuming you are willing to share your information, we would be very
                            grateful to receive a copy of any work you have done on any manuscript
                            source. The information will be added to the website with full credit
                            given to the author. Since this material is thus ‘published' online it
                            will count as a research output for you. If you subsequently publish the
                            material elsewhere you should inform the publisher in advance that it
                            already appears in some form on the DIAMM website.</p>

                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>Does DIAMM only digitize music, or only medieval manuscripts?</head>
                        <p>DIAMM will digitize just about anything (as long as it is not illegal,
                            pornographic, copyright or for any other nefarious purpose). We prefer
                            our objects to be flat (books, pictures, maps etc.), but apart from that
                            we are able to digitize most items and most types of collection. If we
                            feel our approach is not suitable for your collection we will pass you
                            on to other experts in the appropriate fields. For more information
                            about hiring DIAMM to undertake digitization work for you, please see
                            the <ref type="internal" cRef="p11">Services page.</ref>
                        </p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>The music looks very different from the music I usually play/sing. How
                            can I learn how to understand this notation?</head>
                        <p>There are two books that describe how Medieval Music notation works:
                            Apel, Willi: <hi rend="bold">The Notation of Polyphonic Music
                                900-1600</hi> (Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1942. (4th ed., 1949)) –
                            this may not be in print, but is available from most libraries that have
                            a (classical) music section. Rastall, Richard: <hi rend="bold">The
                                Notation of Western Music: an introduction</hi> (St Martin's Press,
                            New York, 1982)</p>
                        <p>If you are looking for a historical introduction to Medieval Music the
                            following is recommended: Hoppin, Richard H: <hi rend="bold">Medieval
                                Music</hi> (New York: W. W. Norton, 1978)</p>
                    </div>

                    <div>
                        <head>I'm interested in researching my family history. Where can I find out
                            about them?</head>
                        <p>DIAMM contains no information about family history. This is a resource
                            for studying Medieval Music Manuscripts. By searching you may find a
                            name or names that seem relevant to you, but there is no genealogical
                            information created from these names.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Copyright and permission for use</head>
                    <div>
                        <head>Why can't I download the images?</head>
                        <p>DIAMM delivers images via a complex web-delivery system. The images are
                            not owned by DIAMM, but are available online through us thanks to rights
                            agreements with the owning institutions, and this rights agreement
                            prohibits the free download of images. DIAMM does not have permission to
                            sell or give away any of these images, since we are not the copyright
                            holder. More details about this can be found on the <ref type="internal"
                                cRef="p2_3">Rights Protection page.</ref> If you wish to obtain
                            personal copies of images that you have seen on the DIAMM website you
                            need to contact the library that owns them. Clicking on the library name
                            in any view will take you to the library contact details.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I want to show pictures from the website in a lecture/presentation.
                            Will I be infringing copyright or breaching my access agreement?</head>
                        <p>The Website Access Agreement is clear that the images may only be used
                            for research or non-commercial reasons. Since teaching falls under this
                            category you may show any page from the DIAMM website either as a
                            screenshot or live during a lecture.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I want to publish an article using images from the DIAMM website. How
                            can I get permission?</head>
                        <p>If you wish to obtain print-quality copies of images that you have seen
                            on the DIAMM website you need to contact the library that owns them to
                            obtain permission. For publications you (or your publisher) may have to
                            pay a reproduction rights fee, although this is usually waived for
                            academic (i.e. non-profit) publications. Clicking on the library name in
                            any view will take you to the library contact details. Make sure that
                            you give the accurate information about which image(s) you require as it
                            is extremely frustrating for libraries if they are simply given the name
                            of a piece. You must supply the correct, complete shelf-mark for the
                            manuscript, and the exact folio number(s) of the images you require:
                            this is found in the text displayed beneath the images.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I want to get copies of the original images that I have seen on the
                            website. How can I get them?</head>
                        <p>If you wish to obtain copies of images that you have seen on the DIAMM
                            website you need to contact the library that owns them to obtain
                            permission. You will need to specify the size/quality of the image you
                            want. Remember that web-sized images are unsuitable for printing. If you
                            ask for the full-sized images you will need image-processing software
                            such as Photoshop or PaintShop Pro to open them. Clicking on the library
                            name in any view will take you to the library contact details. Make sure
                            that you give the accurate information about which image(s) you require
                            as it is extremely frustrating for libraries if they are simply given
                            the name of a piece. You must supply the correct, complete shelf-mark
                            for the manuscript, and the exact folio number(s) of the images you
                            require: this is found in the text displayed beneath the images.</p>
                    </div>
                    <div>
                        <head>I am a collection holder and would like to have my digital images
                            included in the DIAMM collection. Will I have to pay to have them
                            included?</head>
                        <p>There is no currently charge for adding your images of music manuscripts
                            to the DIAMM collection. Our delivery mechanism was built to handle as
                            many images as we can put into it, and the success of the site is
                            largely dependent on its content. We are therefore more than happy to
                            include digital images from other collections, provided there is no
                            copyright issue.</p>
                        <p>If your collection is of non-musical items we may also be able to deliver
                            the images. For a small number of images there would be no charge, but
                            for collections of significant size we may need to acquire more server
                            space, and that additional cost would have to be met by the depositor.
                            Please contact us if you would like more information about this
                            service.</p>
                    </div>


                    <!-- OLD CATEGORISATION IS BELOW
                    
                    
            <div part="N" sample="complete" org="uniform">
                <head>Technical questions</head>-->

                    <!-- </div>
            <div part="N" sample="complete" org="uniform">
                <head>Rights</head>-->

                    <!--     </div>
            <div part="N" sample="complete" org="uniform">
                <head>For scholars and libraries</head>-->

                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
