<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_7_2">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Registration &amp; Account</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-05" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>



            <div>
                <head>Registration and Your MyDIAMM account</head>

                <div>
                    <head>Do I have to be employed in a University to register?</head>
                    <p>No, anyone can register to use the site and view the images.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Is it possible for my institution to obtain an institutional IP address to
                        register anyone within our IP range for use of the website?</head>
                    <p>Use of the features associated with image browsing is dependent on individual
                        login. Users cannot create a personalised workspace unless they have a
                        personal login. Since creating a user account is so quick, this should not
                        be a problem for the members of your institution.</p>
                    <p>One advantage of individual user accounts is to ensure that anyone entering
                        spurious material in the public comments or transcriptions fields is
                        identified. This helps to avoid spam, pornography and other undesirable
                        material from appearing on the website.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I'm not affiliated with any institution: can I still register to use the
                        website?</head>
                    <p>Anyone can register to use the site and view the images. You do not have to
                        be an academic, employed, or a musician to use and appreciate the
                        content.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I am not a musician or a medievalist, can I register to use the
                        website?</head>
                    <p>Anyone can register to use the site and view the images. You do not have to
                        be an academic, employed, or a musician to use and appreciate the
                        content.</p>
                </div>


            </div>



        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
