<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_7_1" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Website Usage and Functions</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change>
            <change when="2008-05-05" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            
            
            <div><head>Website Usage and Functions</head>
         
               
                <div>
                    <head>I have an account. How do I log in?</head>
                    <p>To log in, please click on the 'MyDIAMM' tab at the top of the page,
                        underneath the logo.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>How do I see the full-sized images?</head>
                    <p>You must be logged in to see the full-sized images. If you do not have an
                        account you can create one within a couple of minutes by completing the
                        information on the <ref type="db" target="createnewuser.jsp">Register
                            page</ref>. Account details will be sent to you by e-mail, so you must
                        have an e-mail account to register, and access to your e-mail as your
                        password will be sent to that account. Once you are logged in you can use
                        the search function to find manuscripts that have images available or, if
                        you know which manuscript you want to view, you can go there using the
                        Browse menus. Once you reach the source description page you will see a
                        ‘tab' entitled ‘Images'. Under this tab you will find thumbnails for all
                        images associated with the manuscript. Clicking on a thumbnail will load the
                        image viewer with the full-sized image. Note: if you are not logged in the
                        thumbnails do not become live links: the link only works once you are logged
                        in. </p>
                </div>

                <div>
                    <head>Why can't I see the full-sized images when I click on a thumbnail, even if
                        I'm logged in?</head>
                    <p> Make sure you have the correct version of the Flash plugin for your browser.
                        You can download that <ref type="external"
                            target="http://www.adobe.com/products/flashplayer/">here.</ref>
                    </p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Nothing seems to work right. I keep getting error messages.</head>
                    <p>Some browsers work better with the website than others. You could try using a
                        different browser if you are using one that is not very common.</p>
                    <p>Please also make sure that you are using the most recent version of your
                        browser.</p>
                    <p>Internet Explorer for Macintosh is not supported.</p>
                    <p>The website may be undergoing a technical upgrade or an upload. Try visiting
                        again later.</p>
                    <p>If the error persists you should report it to the project manager, but please
                        include the following information:</p>
                    <p>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Your operating system</item>
                            <item>Your browser software, including version number if possible</item>
                            <item>What you did to cause the error (i.e. which link you clicked on,
                                or which search you performed).</item>
                            <item>If possible include the URL of the page</item>
                            <item>If possible, cut and paste the http error information into your
                                e-mail.</item>
                        </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    </p>
                    <p>If are having technical trouble, please try to use the <ref type="internal"
                        cRef="p2_9">Feedback Form.</ref> If this is impossible, please email
                            <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk">the Project
                            Manager.</ref></p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>How can I let other scholars know that I am working on a particular
                        manuscript?</head>
                    <p>You can use the Public Comments tool to indicate to other users the images
                        that you are working on or that you are interested in. You may include your
                        contact details in the comment so that people can get in touch with you if
                        they wish. To foil spam e-mail harvesters we advise that you replace the ‘@'
                        sign in your e-mail address with ‘[at]'.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>How can I contact other scholars who may be working on the same repertory
                        as me?</head>

                    <p>You can use the Public Comments tool to indicate to other users the images
                        that you are working on or that you are interested in and ask them to
                        contact you. You may include your contact details in the comment. To foil
                        spam e-mail harvesters we advise that you replace the ‘@' sign in your
                        e-mail address with ‘[at]'.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I want to put my digital collection online and have been looking at your
                        delivery mechanism. Can I buy the software to create my own collection using
                        your methods?</head>
                    <p>The delivery system used for DIAMM was custom-designed for us, and cannot
                        currently be bought as a software package (although it is all open-source).
                        It involved several years of technical development and considerable cost.
                        However you can contact our design and technical team and they will be happy
                        to discuss your needs and what would be necessary to adapt the DIAMM model
                        to your needs, since it was built with a transferable end-use in mind. Since
                        the framework is now designed, other projects would not be faced with the
                        enormous cost of developing this from scratch, and we welcome interest from
                        other projects or institutions in using this delivery system with other
                        collections. Please contact Paul Vetch, our technical consultant at the
                        Centre for Computing in the Humanities at King's College, London on
                        paul.vetch[at]kcl.ac.uk</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>How do I ask DIAMM to take pictures of manuscripts for me or anything
                        else?</head>
                    <p>DIAMM offers an extensive array of consulting services for hire by anyone.
                        Please see our <ref type="internal" cRef="p11">services</ref> section for
                        more information.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I do not have access to the internet. Will I be able to use the
                        website?</head>
                    <p>Probably not. If you can gain access to the internet you will be able to use
                        the website and, indeed, read this answer.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
           
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
