<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_3" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Source Descriptions</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2008-05-02</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Source Descriptions</head>
            <div>
                <head>Source Description tab</head>
                <p>You do not need to be logged in to access source descriptions but you will need
                    to be logged in to see manuscript images.</p>
                <p>The first line of the Source Description is the Archive which holds the
                    manuscript. To access details about the library you should click on the library
                    name. This will take you to a list of manuscripts in that library with their
                    source descriptions, dates and provenance. </p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help10"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>(Clicking on a shelf mark in this second view will take you to the main source
                    description page for that manuscript. At the top of the library details list you
                    will find contact details for the library if that is included in our data. We
                    would be grateful to receive any additional information that users can supply to
                    supplement our own data.)</p>

                <p>Each manuscript is designated by its call number or shelf mark, not by any common
                    or colloquial name by which it may also be known. The source description for any
                    manuscript can be reached: <xmt:uList>
                        <item>By clicking on the shelf mark in the Browse layout;</item>
                        <item>By clicking on the shelf mark in a found set after searching;</item>
                        <item>By clicking on the shelf mark in any list or found set.</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help11"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p> In this view there are two ‘tabs' in the main part of the page: the first tab,
                    ‘Source Description' shows all the textual material available to us that
                    describes the manuscript. The ‘Olim' paragraph is quite important as this will
                    list names by which the manuscript may be known and any other shelf mark that
                    may have been used to designate the manuscript either in its current library, or
                    a previous one. </p>
                <p>The main description field contains text scanned from RISM or the Census
                    Catalogues and read by OCR software. The results have been proof-read and we
                    hope will no longer contain any errors. (Please notify us if you find anything
                    that needs correcting.) The content and extent of the description depends on the
                    information provided in the printed catalogues. The originating catalogue will
                    be identified preceding each description. In some cases there are descriptions
                    supplied by more than one source catalogue. In this case both descriptions are
                    reproduced. All descriptions are reproduced as they appeared in the original
                    book, without any edits, even where we now know that the information may be
                    inaccurate. If there are any corrections to the original information this is
                    recorded in the ‘Notes' paragraph at the foot of the ‘Source Description' tab.
                    To see an image of the original catalogue pages, go to the paragraph near the
                    foot of this tab entitle ‘Catalogue Image' (see notes below for details).</p>
                <p>The <hi rend="bold">Date</hi> paragraph gives the most accurate date known for
                    the origins of the manuscript. This does not attempt to identify dates of
                    composition for individual works in the manuscript, only a date of copying.</p>
                <p>The <hi rend="bold">Bibliography</hi> originally contained the abbreviated
                    bibliographies compiled by the catalogues. These are difficult to use unless you
                    are familiar with the bibliographical keys employed by the authors. The
                    bibliographies are presented as much as possible in their full form, but where
                    work on linking the abbreviations to their full forms is incomplete the
                    abbreviated list has been retained. These will be replaced by full
                    bibliographies as soon as is possible.</p>
                <p>Further information that is also found in the description paragraph is also
                    listed in the following paragraphs which are self-explanatory: <hi rend="bold">Page measurements</hi>, <hi rend="bold">Provenance</hi>, <hi rend="bold">Notation</hi> and <hi rend="bold">Surface.</hi></p>
                <p>In all cases if there is no content under the subject headings they will not
                    appear.</p>
                <p>The paragraph entitled <hi rend="bold">Catalogue Image</hi> will contain one or
                    more links entitled ‘RISM' or ‘CCM'. These links will open an image viewer
                    showing the original catalogue page as it was scanned. <hi rend="bold">Next</hi>
                    and <hi rend="bold">Previous</hi> buttons will allow you to page back and forth
                    through the books without limitation. Since some sources appear in more than one
                    catalogue, and some may have entries in more than one volume of either
                    catalogue, there may be more than one link in this paragraph. (You do not need
                    to be logged in to have access to these images).</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Image List tab</head>
                <p>The second tab will read ‘Image list' if there are images of the manuscript
                    available online. (If there are no images linked to the manuscript it will read
                    ‘(No images available)' and will not be active if you click on it.) Under this
                    tab you will find a thumbnail list of images with their folio numbers. Although
                    these are very small they are sufficient to give you an idea of what can be seen
                    on the full-size image. If you are not logged in these images are as far as you
                    can go in this part of the website.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help12"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>Once you are logged in, each thumbnail becomes an active link to a copy of the
                    full-size image which appears in a customized image-viewer. For details of
                    viewing images see the Help page describing the <ref type="internal" cRef="p9_4">Image
                    Viewer.</ref></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>