<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Finding Manuscripts</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2008-05-02" who="Greg Skidmore">Created File</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Help</head>

            <div>
                <head>Browse manuscripts</head>
                <p>You do not need to be registered to browse the manuscript list, but you DO need
                    to be registered to see any images that you find when looking through manuscript
                    information. The libraries listed contain many manuscripts that are non-musical
                    in content: only those related to Medieval music, and covered by the remit of
                    the DIAMM project, are given in the manuscript lists.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Help06"/>
                    </figure>
                </p>
                <p>The manuscripts listed on this website are organised by the libraries where they
                    are kept. The Browse facility allows you to enter the library of your choice by
                    selecting a country and city and then browsing the list of archives and their
                    contents to find the manuscript you are looking for. Each manuscript is
                    designated by its call number or shelf mark, not by any common or colloquial
                    name by which it may also be known. If you only know the ‘name' of the
                    manuscript you should use the Search facility to locate it by entering the name
                    into the Source Description box (see ‘Search manuscripts').</p>
                <p>If you do not know (or do not see) the shelf mark of the manuscript in the
                    library you reach, you should use the search page to select the library, and
                    then narrow your search using any further information you have, such as date,
                    provenance, or keywords that would appear in the source description.</p>
                <p>Since the catalogues that form the basis of the DIAMM database were written some
                    time ago, many libraries have changed their shelf marks, so that it may be
                    difficult to locate a manuscript without the new shelf mark. Alternate or old
                    shelf marks are listed in an ‘olim' field in the source descriptions for each
                    manuscript, but these are not yet searchable.</p>
                <p>In the browse view manuscripts have images available to view are show with a tick
                    preceding the shelf mark.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Help07"/>
                    </figure>
                </p>
                <p>The database now lists ALL medieval manuscripts that we are currently aware of
                    (please notify us of anything that we appear to have missed from our list), but
                    only a relatively small proportion of these are accompanied by images. We are
                    working to increase this number all the time. If you would like to donate images
                    to the online collection please contact us: there is no charge for including
                    images in the DIAMM resource.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>Search manuscripts</head>
                <p>Note: this search page does not search the website, it searches the database of
                    571 libraries (in 28 countries) containing 2648 manuscripts to find a particular
                    manuscript source. You do not need to be registered to use the search engine,
                    but you DO need to be registered to see images in found manuscripts. </p>
                <p>There are 5 search criteria that you can select on the search page:</p>
                <p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Help08"/>
                    </figure>
                </p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Archive City:</hi> this drop-down menu lists alphabetically all
                    the cities in the DIAMM database.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Archive:</hi> this drop down will show nothing unless you have
                    first selected a city. When you have done that the Archive list will show only
                    the archives, private collections or other libraries in the DIAMM database for
                    that city. You may know of other libraries in that city, but we only list those
                    in which there are medieval music manuscripts containing polyphony.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Century:</hi> this field allows you to select the century in
                    which a manuscript was written. You can use this field without preselecting any
                    countries or cities.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Provenance:</hi> Most manuscripts in the database have known
                    origins: this field does not refer to the current location of a manuscript, but
                    the country where it was originally copied. You may be looking for French
                    manuscripts, and they may now be kept in any country in the world. You do not
                    need to select a country or library to use this field for searching across the
                    manuscript collection.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Source Description:</hi> This is the only free-text entry box on
                    the search page. It does not however allow Boolean searching. For example, if
                    you enter the words ‘Eton Choirbook' in this field the search results will find
                    all source descriptions that contain the word ‘Eton' AND all the source
                    descriptions that contain the word ‘Choirbook'. However if you enter only the
                    word ‘Eton' (which is a more specific term than ‘Choirbook') you will get only
                    get results for the Eton Choirbook. You will get best search results using this
                    field if you use it in addition to the other fields.</p>
                <p>Under ‘Display Options' you can choose how many results are displayed on each
                    page, and there is a checkbox that will further limit your results: <hi
                        rend="bold">Return only sources that have images available on the
                    web.</hi></p>
                <p>You can use the search page in two ways:</p>
                <list type="ordered">
                    <item>1. You can use the drop-down process to find the library or city in which
                        you are interested. You do not need to select all the levels of drop-downs,
                        but can narrow the search results if you are not sure of the location of
                        your manuscript by using the Century, Provenance and Source Description
                        fields.</item>
                    <item>2. You can search only on the single fields: Source Description,
                        provenance or date, with or without qualification from other fields.</item>

                </list>
                <p>The search results will be returned as a list of all Manuscripts that match your
                    search criteria.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure>
                        <graphic url="Help09"/>
                    </figure>
                </p>
                <p>When you click on the sample thumbnail or the manuscript shelf mark on the
                    results page you will be taken to the full source description for that
                    manuscript. If you click on the library name beside the sample thumbnail you
                    will be taken to a list of manuscripts held in that library, with contact
                    details for the library if that is available.</p>
                <p>Over the next 18 months the search facility will be extended and enhanced to
                    enable users to select more specific criteria, and also to free aspects which
                    are currently dependent on other information (e.g. entering shelf marks in
                    free-text search).</p>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
