<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p9_4" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Image Viewer</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change><date>2008-05-02</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Image Viewer</head>
            <div>
                <head>Using the Zoomify Viewer</head>
                <p>You can only access this part of the website if you have an account and have
                    logged in. Due to the extensive use of Java programming language throughout the
                    website, some browsers do not function optimally when using the manuscript image
                    viewer. Safari (Mac) is one browser in which the commenting tools lack some
                    features. For Mac users we recommend the free browser, <ref type="external" target="http://www.mozilla-europe.org/en/products/firefox/">Firefox.</ref></p>
                <p>Registered users of the DIAMM website have access to very high quality images of
                    the original manuscripts. Because of the size of these images, they are
                    displayed using a special image viewer which ensures that they can be quickly
                    downloaded. The image viewer offers a number of tools which allow you to zoom in
                    to a very high level of detail, and navigate around the image. Please note that
                    in order to use the Image Viewer your browser must have support for the
                    Macromedia Flash player, version 6 or later. If you do not have the plugin
                    installed, you will find instructions on how to obtain it from the <ref type="external" target="http://www.adobe.com/shockwave/download/download.cgi">Adobe website</ref> or your browser may give you an error message that
                    directs you to the download page.</p>
                <p>The following image illustrates what you might typically see when using the
                    viewer. Please note that the appearance will vary very slightly depending on the
                    type of computer (for example, Mac or PC) and the web browser you are using.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help13"/></figure>
                </p>
                <xmt:oList>
                    <item>The grey triangle can be clicked (PC users: using the left mouse button)
                        and dragged to the right to increase the level of zoom. Moving to the <hi rend="bold">right</hi> will <hi rend="bold">zoom in</hi> to the image;
                        moving to the <hi rend="bold">left</hi> will <hi rend="bold">zoom out</hi>.</item>
                    <item>The plus and minus buttons offer a second way of controlling the level of
                        zoom, but are easier to use for finer adjustments. Clicking the plus sign
                        will zoom in to the image, clicking the minus sign zooms out.</item>
                    <item>The arrows can be used to pan the image around. This is important when you
                        have increased the zoom level since much of the image will run off the
                        screen.</item>
                    <item>Clicking this symbol will reset the image to the default level of zoom,
                        i.e. completely zoomed out.</item>
                    <item>This smaller representation of the manuscript image remains in the top
                        left hand corner of the screen. When you have zoomed in, the portion of the
                        overall image you are viewing is indicated on this part of the screen by a
                        red box.</item>
                </xmt:oList>
                <p>The next image shows what the Image Viewer looks like once the zoom level has
                    been increased:</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help14"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:oList>
                        <item>The pointer appears when you move your mouse over the image. By
                            clicking (PC users: using the left mouse button) and dragging the mouse,
                            the image can be panned around freely to reveal parts of the image which
                            are off the screen.</item>
                        <item>The red box here represents the portion of the complete image visible.
                            The box can be dragged around by clicking and dragging with the mouse to
                            pan the main image. </item>
                    </xmt:oList>
                </p>
                <p> In some browsers pressing the shift or alt/option keys, or right/left clicking
                    with the mouse on the image will cause the image to zoom in or out. If you
                    resize your window the area available to view the MS will increase. To maximize
                    the viewing area, click on the small ‘close tab' icon at the top left of the
                    Tools Palette. </p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help14a"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p> The text below the image is extremely important as it gives the copyright holder
                    (if you wish to obtain a personal copy of the image, this is who you must
                    contact) and, following the heading ‘Source', the full information about the
                    manuscript and the folio that you will need to cite in any reference to this
                    page, or any request to the library for a copy. However, this is not simply
                    static information:</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help15"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:oList>
                        <item>Clicking on the city name will open a new window that lists all the
                            libraries and sources in that city</item>
                        <item>Clicking on the library name will open a new window that is the
                            library information page. At the top of the page you will see contact
                            details for the library (if that is available), with a complete source
                            list for the library given below (clicking on a manuscript shelf-mark in
                            this list will open a window to the manuscript description page for that
                            source.</item>
                        <item>Clicking on the manuscript shelf mark will open the source description
                            page</item>
                        <item>Below the heading ‘Source' you will see a number in square brackets
                            preceded by the letter ‘s'. This is the source key number in the DIAMM
                            database. You can cut and paste this number into the commenting tools
                            attached to any image (see ‘Tools Palette' below for further
                            information) and this will create a live link to this manuscript. </item>
                        <item>To the right of the source key number is another number in square
                            brackets preceded by the letter ‘i'. This is the key number for the
                            image, and if cut and pasted into a comment will create a live link to
                            this image.</item>
                    </xmt:oList>
                </p>
                <p>You can use this function to create a string of images linked to each other for
                    e.g. teaching a course where you wish students to follow a trail of instructions
                    from one image to the next, bypassing the browsing mechanism. This is also
                    useful to direct other users to e.g. other sources for the same piece or music,
                    instances of the same scribe in other manuscripts or pages of the same
                    manuscript in other libraries. Alternatively you may simply use this to link
                    between images in which you are interested.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <head>The Tools Palette</head>
                <p> To the right of the zoomable image you will see a Tools Palette with a number of
                    button headings. </p>
                <p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Public Comments</item>
                        <item>My Private Notes</item>
                        <item>Other images I've commented on</item>
                        <item>Transcriptions</item>
                        <item>Catalogue Images</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                </p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help16"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>When you click on any of these buttons a content area appears below it, and the
                    button becomes active. You can ‘open' any or all of these buttons
                    simultaneously.</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help17"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Public Comments</hi>, <hi rend="bold">My Private Notes</hi> and
                        <hi rend="bold">Transcriptions</hi> are interactive tools that allow you to
                    enter content. Anything entered in Public Comments or Transcriptions will be
                    visible to all other users of the website. Anything entered in Private Notes is
                    only visible to you when you are logged in.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Public comments</hi> and <hi rend="bold">Transcriptions</hi> are
                    cumulative and cannot be edited once the content is submitted. Other users may
                    add to these fields. The most recent entry appears at the top of the list. Your
                    private notes can be edited or changed.</p>
                <p><hi rend="bold">Other images I've commented on</hi> provides you with a list of
                    links to your other comments. This facility can also allow you to create work
                    lists or pick-lists. It shows only the images to which you have added private
                    comments. To access your complete lists of comments use the My DIAMM link to see
                    your personal page (only visible if logged in).</p>
                <p>The <hi rend="bold">Catalogue images</hi> button will show links to images of the
                    original catalogue pages for the manuscript you are viewing. Clicking on a link
                    will split the viewer window and show the catalogue page to the right. At the
                    bottom of the second image you will find a link to close the new split window.
                    And it works.</p>
                <p>On certain images, a further button heading will appear at the top of the list:</p>
                <p>
                    <figure><graphic url="Help18"/></figure>
                </p>
                <p>This lists other versions of the image you are viewing, specifically ultra-violet
                    imaging, or restored versions of the normal colour image. This button will only
                    appear when these options are available. Clicking on any of the links in this
                    tool will split your view screen into two, and bring the secondary image up
                    beside the first one. Both images are zoomable.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>