<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p2_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Producing DIAMM Publications</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2010-05-07</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Producing DIAMM Publications</head>
                <p>DIAMM Publications was set up to create facsimile publications of the highest
                    quality without the massive cost markup of conventional publishers. High-quality
                    colour printing is expensive, and the price only comes down when doing runs off
                    tens of thousands, such as is done for glossy exhibition catalogues. With runs
                    of a few hundred the unit cost is massively higher, but we felt that if we could
                    produce publications without the usual overheads of a publishing house then we
                    could produce publications that were affordable by to individuals, and to
                    research libraries, whose spending budgets have been seriously diminished in the
                    last few years. The profit margin on our publications is therefore extremely
                    small, and is used only to subsidize future publications. All the income is
                    spent on the actual cost of printing and binding. Nothing is spent on marketing,
                    advertising, office management etc. All these costs have been met by private
                    sponsorship.</p>

                <p><figure>
                        <graphic url="aboutpub1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="left"/>
                    </figure>Publications are funded by pre-publication sales offers, which give the
                    opportunity to buy the books at a considerable discount from the full cover
                    price.</p>
                <p>Our prices are calculated based on the number of copies we think we can sell in
                    the very long term. We then obtain the printing cost for this number of copies
                    (the more we can print at one time, the lower the unit cost, but the overall
                    cost still goes up, so we have to be able to raise that amount before we go to
                    press. Printing costs have to be paid in full at the time of printing).
                    Pre-publication sales help in determining the final print run number, but we
                    also have to work out how many copies we can sell pre-publication. The
                    pre-publication number is crucial, as the pre-publicaton cover price is
                    calculated by dividing the printing/binding cost by the pre-publication sales
                    number.</p>
                <p>We also have to remember that booksellers and other suppliers expect a 25%
                    discount on our normal prices (pre- or post-publication), so that they can make
                    some profit on sales, so we have to ensure the cover prices will allow us that
                    further discount leeway.</p>

                <p><figure>
                        <graphic url="aboutpub2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="right"/>
                    </figure>If we miscalculate and don't sell enough copies then the project has to
                    underwrite the deficit. At the moment that means the project team are
                    underwriting, but eventually we hope the publications will bring in sufficient
                    funds for less popular publications to be subsidized by those that have a better
                    market. The Dow Partbooks project was subsidized by the Eton Choirbook at the
                    point when we had to pay the printing bill. Since publication we have sold a few
                    more copies of Dow so that the book has paid for its own printing, but it has
                    not raised enough yet to pay the full typesetting costs. Dow was therefore
                    printed at a loss, but over the life of the project we expect it to pay for
                    itself.</p>
                <p>Once the printing bill is paid future sales will pay for the cost of typesetting
                    and the administration necessary for shipping and managing orders (in the early
                    stages this is around 1 hour a day), and then will go toward the photography
                    costs for future projects, and will underwrite future printing costs.
                    Effectively the project is non-profit therefore, ensuring we can give the best
                    possible price to our purchasers.</p>
                <p>The printing bill for Eton and Dow together was £42,000. The binding of Eton will
                    cost a further £33,000 approx, but we will only be binding this in batches as
                    required, so we don't have to find that amount right away.</p>
                <p>We work very closely with Information Press at Eynsham. Andrew Hopwood and Martin
                    Horsley ensure we produce exactly what they need to print perfectly, and work
                    closely with us to find the best solutions for quality and materials. We decided
                    at the outset that we would not cut corners to save a few pence, since colour
                    printing needs to be at the best possible quality to be useful and attractive
                    (and to showcase the superb quality of our images), and Information Press have
                    gone out of their way to ensure we are getting the best value and output.</p>

                <p><figure>
                        <graphic url="aboutpub3.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="left"/>
                    </figure>Limp binding (as for Dow) is done in-house by Information Press, but
                    for the Eton Choirbook we are working with Green Street Bindery (in Oxford), a
                    long-established firm of hand binders. The physical size of Eton and the
                    relatively short print run meant that the project could not be outsources to
                    large-scale machine binders (who would normally only take on projects with an
                    output of 10,000 copies or more). Each copy of Eton will therefore be hand bound
                    and finished.</p>

                <p><figure>
                        <graphic url="aboutpub6.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="right"/>
                    </figure>There is no doubt that in order to print in colour in short runs the
                    books will be expensive. Our costs are kept to an absolute minimum, and we hope
                    that buyers will appreciate that we are not overcharging for our books. Many
                    academic publications are subsidized by subventions from grant bodies or
                    personal donations, and we hope that this type of income will also support our
                    publications, but at the moment we are entirely self-supporting, and much of the
                    work involved in producing a book is done <hi rend="italic">pro bono</hi>. A
                    comparison might be made between the Eton Choirbook and the Henry VIII choirbook
                    recently published by the Folio Society:</p>
                <p>Henry VIII 'Royal Choirbook'; print run of 500: 36 colour pages, gilded, in
                    slipcover, plus 120pp commentary volume - £395 Eton: 256 colour pages, plus
                    112pp introduction - £180</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
