<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p2_3" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>DIAMM Publications</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2009-27-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created page</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>

            <div>
                <head>The Dow Partbooks</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">A full-colour facsimile edition of Christ Church Oxford Library,
                        MSS 984-988</hi>
                </p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="Dow1.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="right"/></figure>DIAMM has published The Dow Partbooks in
                    partnership with the <ref target="http://www.vdgs.org.uk" type="external">Viola da Gamba Society
                        (UK)</ref>.</p>
                <p>There are 5 partbooks (Discantus-ii + i + 93 folios, Medius-ii + 93 + i, Altus
                    and Tenor-ii + 95 + i folios each, Bassus-ii + 89 + i), each original measuring
                    142 x 194 cm. They are presented published in full colour on matt art paper in
                    open-flat soft covers, with an introductory volume by John Milsom with
                    comprehensive indexes and finding lists, all included in a hard slipcase.</p>
                <p><figure><graphic url="Dow2.jpg" mimeType="image/jpg" rend="left"/></figure>Robert Dow's partbooks, copied in Oxford around
                    1580, rank among the most beautiful of all Tudor music manuscripts, and are also
                    an important and authoritative source for the works they contain. Conceived with
                    both singers and instrumentalists in mind, they contain a varied repertory
                    suitable for voices and viols, including Latin-texted motets, English-texted
                    anthems and consort songs, and a selection of In nomines and textless chansons,
                    scored mainly for five-voice texture. Featured composers include William Byrd,
                    Thomas Tallis, Robert White, Robert Parsons, Philip van Wilder and Alfonso
                    Ferrabosco Sr. Dow was a trained calligrapher, and his exquisite penmanship,
                    executed in black ink on printed red staves, is unusually accurate and easy to
                    read.</p>
                <p>Pages: 5 partbooks (Discantus 192 pp, Medius 192 pp, Altus 196 pp, Tenor 196 pp,
                    Bassus 184 pp) and 1 vol introduction, full text 96pp, each facsimile volume
                    measuring 170 x 240 mm (landscape format)</p>
                <p>Images from and detailed source descritions of each partbook are available on the
                    DIAMM website. While the descriptions are always available, you must be logged
                    in to DIAMM in order to see the images. Please sign up for your free DIAMM
                    account <ref type="internal" cRef="p7_2">here</ref> or log in <ref type="internal" cRef="p12_2">here.</ref> Once you have logged in, please
                    come back to this page and use the links below to be taken direct to each
                    partbook's page.</p>
                <p>
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=2353">Discantus</ref> ¦ <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=2354">Medius</ref> ¦ <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=2355">Altus</ref> ¦ <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=2356">Tenor</ref> ¦ <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/jsp/Source.jsp?navToggle=1&amp;sourceKey=2357">Bassus</ref></p>
                <p>A contents list for the partbooks can be found <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/Dow_Contents.pdf">here</ref> (PDF document)</p>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="bold">For Pricing and order information please visit the <ref
                        type="external" target="http://tinyurl.com/DIAMMpubs">online
                        shop</ref></hi></p>
                <p>UK/Europe Orders and payment may be made electronically in any currency via our
                    <ref type="external" target="http://tinyurl.com/DIAMMpubs">online
                        shop</ref></p>
                <p>All orders for <hi rend="bold">USA and Canada</hi> should be made through <ref
                    type="external" target="http://www.omifacsimiles.com">OMI Facsimile
                    sales</ref></p>
                <p>All orders for <hi rend="bold">Japan and Asia</hi> should be made through <ref
                    type="external" target="http://www.academia-music.com">Academia
                    Music</ref></p>
                <p>Orders in <hi rend="bold">Australia and New Zealand</hi> can also be made through
                    <ref type="external" target="http://www.saraband.com.au">Saraband
                        Music</ref></p>
                <p>Please contact DIAMM or OMI if you wish to make multiple purchases to enquire
                    about discounts, or if you are a retailer.</p>
            </div>
            
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>