<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p11_0" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Consultancy</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>
                   
                </p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2008-10-09</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added page, removed other pages' content</change><change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Finalised content</change><change><date>2008-02-18</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created first version of content</change><change><date>2008-01-24</date><name>AC</name>created doc</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Consultancy</head>
            <div>
                <head>Consultancy</head>
                <p>DIAMM was set up in 1998, when archive-quality digital imaging was relatively in
                    its infancy, and has worked in archives across the UK and Europe, and as far
                    afield as Japan, producing consistent results of the highest quality. Our
                    experience therefore is longer than most institutions and commercial businesses
                    offering this type of digitization. Archive-quality imaging is not as simple as
                    many equipment purchasers believe: it is worlds away from the consumer digital
                    camera market, where the end user can buy a camera, computer and printer off the
                    shelf and reasonably expect to be able to create very good, colour accurate
                    prints within minutes of unpacking and plugging in their equipment.</p>
                <p>We define an 'archive-quality' image as one which provides the end-user with an
                    image from which a very high quality, colour accurate surrogate can be made at
                    full size without reference to the original (in case of deterioration or loss).
                    This means that the image must contain all the information necessary for later
                    evaluation and reproduction, and must be stored in a format that ensures no loss
                    of data. Our minimum specification for 'archive quality' is 400 dpi at real
                    size. Ideally we aim to obtain higher resolution wherever possible. We will
                    always capture images at the the highest resolution available to our equipment.</p>
                <p>Surprisingly, many commercial businesses and institutions offering digital
                    imaging are producing extremely poor-quality images, and this can be due to any
                    number of factors, from simple cost-cutting, through ignorance, to the inability
                    to evaluate an image for quality output.</p>
                <p>DIAMM expertise is available to new and existing projects to share the benefit of
                    our experience, and ensure that high-end digital imaging work produces the
                    superb quality pictures that it is capable of.</p>
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>Training and education in imaging basics: understanding file formats; file
                        compression; technical terms; image storage basics; colour calibration etc;</item>
                    <item>Evaluation of needs for projects proposing to use digital images;</item>
                    <item>Advice for ordering archive-quality digital images from a third party
                        supplier (how to ensure you write your order specifications so that you get
                        images that meet your requirements);</item>
                    <item>Independent image evaluation and QA for end-users employing commercial
                        companies to supply their imaging needs, or projects purchasing images from
                        other organisations;</item>
                    <item>Training in digital image QA;</item>
                    <item>Collection evaluation and equipment purchasing advice for new digitization
                        departments;</item>
                    <item>Licensing and copyright advice and support for buying or selling images;</item>
                    <item>Training in equipment use and imaging workflow.</item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
                <p>DIAMM has worked closely with <ref target="http://www.digitalconsultancy.net/" type="external">King's Digital
                        Consultancy Services (KDCS)</ref> at King's College London, who offer
                    guidance on every aspect of setting up and managing digital projects, from
                    collection evalutation onwards.</p>
                <p>Consultancy is normally offered on a daily rate (plus travel and subsistence).
                    Please enquire about rates and a quotation from the Project Manager.</p>
            </div>
            
            
            
            
            <div>
                <p>If you would like to enquire further about your requirements, or about a project
                    that you are planning, please contact the Project Manager, <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk">Julia
                        Craig-McFeely,</ref></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>