<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p11_2">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Digital Restoration</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2008-10-09</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added page</change><change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Finalised content</change><change><date>2008-02-18</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created first version of content</change><change><date>2008-01-24</date><name>AC</name>created doc</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Digital Restoration</head>
            
            
            <div>
                <head>Digital Restoration</head>
                <p>Unfortunately, due to the time involved in the digital restoration process, DIAMM
                    is not currently able to offer a digital restoration service except in very
                    limited cases.</p>
                <p>We have however found that it is usually preferable for researchers to receive
                    training in digital restoration processes, which they can then apply to their
                    sources. This includes advice on the specifications for digital images required
                    for restoration purposes. We offer one-day group or half- to one-day individual
                    training in digital restoration.</p>
                <p>The DIAMM digital restoration workbook is available for download <ref type="redist" cRef="pdf/RestorationWorkbook.pdf">here</ref>). For copyright reasons the sample images
                    discussed in the workbook are not available online, and you would need to apply
                    to the project manager for access to these images.</p>
                <p>If your intention is to do digital restoration work on digital images, please
                    contact DIAMM before ordering your images, as most standard digital images
                    supplied by libraries or archives are not suitable for restoration work. We do
                    not usually charge for information about image ordering specifications, as this
                    can be covered in a brief e-mail or phone call.</p>
                <p>For digital restoration you will need to ensure that you have a full version of
                    an image editing software (preferably Photoshop, as DIAMM techniques were
                    designed using this software), and a suitable computer with at least 1GB RAM
                    (preferably more) and large processing capability for dealing with images from
                    200 MB up to 1.2 GB or more during the restoration process. This work can be
                    done on a standard (reasonably new) computer, but you may find the process very
                    slow.</p>

            </div>
            
            
            <div>
                <p>If you would like to enquire further about your requirements, or about a project
                    that you are planning, please contact the Project Manager, <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk">Julia
                        Craig-McFeely,</ref></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>