<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p11_3">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Services</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
              <p></p>  
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2008-10-09</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added page</change><change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Finalised content</change><change><date>2008-02-18</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created first version of content</change><change><date>2008-01-24</date><name>AC</name>created doc</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Grant Applications</head>
            
            
            
            <div>
                <head>Grant applications</head>
                <p> DIAMM welcomes collaborations with projects in which image acquisition by DIAMM
                    is either purchased following a successful grant application, cited in the
                    application process. Outsourcing your imaging needs ensures that your time is
                    spent doing the work that you and your researchers are best qualified to do, and
                    leaves imaging to a specialist who will ensure you receive the best possible
                    quality of images, that meet your needs ideally. </p>
                <p>We are available to consult on grant applications for projects in which you
                    either intend to use DIAMM as your image supplier, or for projects where you
                    would use other suppliers but require guidance on completing the technical parts
                    of the application form. If you intend to use DIAMM to create your digital
                    images you may simply cite DIAMM as the image-supplier or imaging consultant, as
                    long as you have checked with us first to ensure we are able to undertake your
                    work, and that the document-owners concerned will allow us to work with their
                    documents.</p>
                <p>DIAMM has currently made 7 successful grant applications to three funding bodies,
                    in the UK and the USA. We would normally charge for consultancy time required to
                    prepare text for a grant application.</p>

            </div>
            
            <div>
                <p>If you would like to enquire further about your requirements, or about a project
                    that you are planning, please contact the Project Manager, <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk">Julia
                        Craig-McFeely,</ref></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>