<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p11_1" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Services</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p></p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2008-10-09</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added page</change><change><date>2008-02-22</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Finalised content</change><change><date>2008-02-18</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Created first version of content</change><change><date>2008-01-24</date><name>AC</name>created doc</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Imaging by DIAMM</head>
            
            <div>
                <head>Imaging by DIAMM</head>
                <p>DIAMM has specialised in the digitization of rare and/or delicate documents,
                    either bound or unbound. Our original remit was to digitize fragments of
                    medieval music, and has extended to embrace complete manuscripts which are
                    usually in better condition, but which present their own handling and
                    conservation problems. Our photographers have long experience in handling
                    delicate manuscripts and objects during their doctoral work, and since that time
                    in handling manuscripts during photography.</p>
                <p>Imaging priorities concentrate on obtaining the best possible picture without
                    harm to the source, or stress to its binding. DIAMM does not use flash, and only
                    uses 'remote' lighting (at a distance of over 1 metre) which does not generate
                    heat, and is carefully engineered to exclude ultra-violet content, while
                    emulating the colour spectrum of daylight (it is therefore less harmful than
                    daylight). Our intention is that once imaging of a document has been completed
                    by DIAMM, it should not be necessary to repeat digitization work again, thus
                    digitization – as long as it is done to appropriate quality standards – fulfils
                    a conservation purpose.</p>
                <p>DIAMM does not have a studio, but normally works on site with the documents and
                    their owners. In exceptional cases costs can be minimized by bringing the
                    document(s) to Oxford for imaging work. We reserve the right to refuse to handle
                    documents in order to obtain a particular image, in a way that we consider may
                    shorten the life of the document, or damage it in any way.</p>
                <p>There are two imaging processes available, and deciding which one is suitable for
                    your source will depend on evaluation of your intended use of the images, and
                    the size and condition of the source.</p>
                <div>
                    <head>PhaseOne PowerPhase FX</head>
                    <p>Because of the cost of single-shot digital sensors, the highest-quality of
                        digital imaging (i.e. obtaining the greatest number of pixels over the
                        largest area) is done by using a scanning back. This has a double row of
                        sensors, and the equipment acquires an image by taking multiple rows of
                        pictures, in the same way as a flatbed scanner works. A single picture may
                        take as long as 5-6 minutes to acquire.</p>
                    <p>However, a major difference between a scanning back and a flatbed scanner is
                        that a scanning back is mounted on the back of a custom-built large-format
                        camera body, and never touches the manuscript, nor does it have a bright
                        light which is shone directly on the manuscript.</p>
                    <p>This equipment is able to yield images of approximately 132 megapixels (for
                        comparison, high-end consumer cameras now capture at around 8-11
                        megapixels), and is most appropriate for:</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Larger documents (A3 size and upwards);</item>
                        <item>Documents of any size that are damaged and for which imaging is
                            intended to provide a surrogate for digital restoration;</item>
                        <item>Documents for which exceptionally high resolution is required for the
                            end purpose.</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    <p></p>
                    <p>The usual shot-rate for this camera is approx 80 shots per day, or up to 12
                        shots per hour. This is based on normal working hours and reasonable
                        handling and access to the document. If a document requires more complex
                        handling between shots the shot-rate will be lower. Please ensure that you
                        have evaluated the document appropriately before attempting to calculate a
                        shot-rate yourself. The photographer is available to make an initial visit
                        to evaluate a document, or set of documents, for photographic work at a
                        reduced daily consultancy rate.</p>
                    <p>Imaging is undertaken on a daily rate basis (plus travel and
                    subsistence).</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>PhaseOne P45+</head>
                    <p>This is the first in a new generation of high-end single-shot cameras.
                        Similar digital backs have been produced by Leaf, Hasselblad and Sinar, but
                        most end users consider the quality of images from the PhaseOne P45+ to be
                        superior. A very useful review may be found here:<ref target="http://www.luminous-landscape.com/reviews/cameras/p45plus.shtml" type="external">http://www.luminous-landscape.com/reviews/cameras/p45plus.shtml.</ref>
                    </p>
                    <p>A 'single-shot camera' means that the whole image is acquired in one action,
                        so the camera works much as a normal digital SLR would do. The difference is
                        in the size of the images. A high-end consumer digital SLR will capture
                        images at 8-11 megapixels. The P45+ is able to capture images at 39
                        megapixels, thus yielding archive quality images for documents almost as
                        large as A3 size, and quality well above this minimum for smaller documents.</p>
                    <p>The P45+ is ideal for:</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Small documents up to A4 size, or up to A3 if the source material is
                            undamaged and the needs of the end-use do require a higher resolution</item>
                        <item>Projects where a large number of images are required in a short space
                            of time, and where the source documents are in good condition.</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    <p>The shot-rates for the P45+ have not been fully tested: because of the way
                        the software works, capture time is relatively short, but we have to allow
                        at least a day following the capture time for post-processing to produce the
                        final images. We would expect to be able to obtain upwards of 600 images in
                        a full day of shooting, or approx 100 images per hour. This estimate is
                        based on easy document handling. If a document requires more complex
                        handling between shots the shot-rate will be lower. Please ensure that you
                        have evaluated the document appropriately before attempting to calculate a
                        shot-rate yourself. The photographer is available to make an initial visit
                        to evaluate a document, or set of documents, for photographic work at a
                        reduced daily consultancy rate.</p>
                    <p>Imaging is undertaken on a daily rate basis (plus travel and subsistence).</p>
                    <p>
                        <emph>A note on costs: we have compared our consultancy rates with charges
                            made by the British Library and the Bodleian Library for images of the
                            same quality, taken using the same equipment. Based on a two-day,
                            full-time shoot in a library in Switzerland (i.e. including travel from
                            the UK and subsistence expenses), resulting in 200 images in total,
                            projects can usually obtain their images for approx. a tenth of the
                            price of buying the same number of images from either of these
                            institutions. This estimate is based on the use of the PowerPhase FX.
                            Work done using the P45+ works out at less than one fiftieth of the cost
                            of buying images from these suppliers.</emph>
                    </p>
                    <p>Quick comparison:</p>
                    <table>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Equipment</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Sensor size</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Max MPx</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Capture time</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Max file sizes at 24-bit RGB</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Real-size dpi for A4 page</cell>
                            <cell role="label" rows="1" cols="1">Per-image cost*</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">PowerPhase FX</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">10,500 x 12,600 pixels</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">132 Megapixels</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">3-6 mins</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">&lt; 350 MB</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">1077 dpi</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">£5.00/€6.50</cell>
                        </row>
                        <row role="data">
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">P45+</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">7200 x 5400 pixels</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">39 Megapixels</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">Approx 1 sec.</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">&lt; 113 MB</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">700</cell>
                            <cell role="data" rows="1" cols="1">£0.83/€1</cell>
                        </row>
                    </table>
                    <p>*The per-image cost is based on capture of 80 images per day (PowerPhase FX)
                        or 600 images per day (P45+). The costs include only the daily consultancy
                        rate, and DO NOT include travel or subsistence.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Specialised and experimental imaging requirements</head>
                    <p>As long as there are no conservation problems with the source materials, we
                        are happy to undertake experimental imaging processes in consultation with
                        the researcher, including:</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Close-up shots;</item>
                        <item>Raking normal (RGB) light, raking UV light;</item>
                        <item>Transmissive light using a cold fibre-optic light sheet, ideal for
                            documents which are stuck together, for faded ink, or for photographing
                            watermarks;</item>
                        <item>UV imaging using low-frequency ultra-violet lighting heads;</item>
                        <item>Multi-spectral imaging using limited-bandwidth interference filters,
                            which is particularly useful in dealing with very damaged (e.g. burned)
                            documents and erasures;</item>
                        <item>Infra-red imaging (limited effectiveness in the digital medium due to
                            the very long exposure, which gives rise to 'noise' on the
                        image).</item>
                    </xmt:uList><p></p>
                    <p>UV photography uses low-frequency 'blacklight' ultra-violet lighting heads,
                        which do not project the harmful UV that requires protective eye-wear and
                        causes burns to the skin. Because of the low lighting levels, exposures are
                        very long (up to 15 minutes using the FX scanning back, but depends on the
                        size of the source and degree of fluorescence of the subject material under
                        the UV light). Multi-spectral work is done using the P45+, and taking shots
                        with a wide range exposures within the visible spectrum for each of eight
                        filters: thus a set of multi-spectral images for a single leaf would
                        comprise about 60 shots and take about 10-15 minutes to obtain after the
                        document has been positioned. Transmissive light has proved successful in
                        allowing material to be read from pages pasted together, and in
                        photographing watermarks. The light sheet is thin enough to be inserted
                        between pages in a book.</p>
                    <p>The success of these techniques, either singly or in combination, in
                        obtaining data from damaged materials cannot be assured, as each source is
                        different and results vary widely. However, we have found so far that the
                        images always provide some additional information, even if it is not very
                        much, and having tried these processes is a way of ensuring that all efforts
                        have been made to read the document that are possible with current
                        technology.</p>

                </div>
            </div>
            
            
            
            <div>
                <p>If you would like to enquire further about your requirements, or about a project
                    that you are planning, please contact the Project Manager, <ref type="email" target="diamm@music.ox.ac.uk">Julia
                        Craig-McFeely,</ref></p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>