<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_3_1" xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader><fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Scope</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt><publisher>King's College London</publisher><pubPlace>London</pubPlace></publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc><revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change><change><date>2008-03-03</date><name>AC</name>Took out redundant division before list</change><change><date>2006-05-10</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content update</change><change><date>2004-07-06</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p2_7</change></revisionDesc></teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
            <head>Scope</head>
            <!--<p><hi rend="bold">-->
            <div>
                <head>The Resource</head>
                <p>
                    <hi rend="italic">DIAMM is a primarily Musicological resource</hi>, though we
                    have photographed early documents for other projects such as the Anglo-Saxon
                    Charters project at Cambridge University (Prof Simon Keynes) and Alison Stones'
                    Arthurian MSS project at the University of Pittsburgh. </p>
                <p>The remit of the project is to photograph and archive images of:</p>
          
                <xmt:uList>
                    <item>all fragments of English polyphonic music written before 1550;</item>
                    <item>all complete sources of English polyphonic music before 1500, and as many
                        as practically possible 1500-1550;</item>
                    <item>all fragments of European polyphony 1300-1450;</item>
                    <item>as many complete manuscripts of European polphony 1300-1450, and beyond as
                        is possible and practicable.</item>
                </xmt:uList><p></p>
            </div>
            <div>
                <p>The repertory is in manuscript, and almost entirely preserved on parchment,
                    though there are some notable exceptions on paper.</p>
                <p>Opportunistically we have been able to capitalise on our presence in some
                    libraries and exploit our growing reputation to photograph major complete
                    sources in Italy and elsewhere, thus expanding the boundaries of the project to
                    a much wider repertory and user-base.</p>
                <p>One of the specific exclusions of the project is <hi rend="bold">plainchant</hi>.
                    The repertory is vast, and to some extent repetitive, and is therefore not in
                    danger of being lost to the same extent as the polyphonic repertory. However
                    there have been two exceptions to this policy, when significant chant
                    manuscripts have been disbound for conservation purposes: The ‘Winchester
                    Troper' from Corpus Christi College, Cambridge, was photographed by Cambridge
                    University Library and the images were deposited with DIAMM for safekeeping as
                    at the time CUL had no long-term archiving strategy. Currently disbound for
                    conservation is the Wollaton Antiphonal, kept at Nottingham University Library.
                    We hope that DIAMM will be able to photograph this MS while it is disbound on
                    behalf of Nottingham UL.</p>
            </div>
            <div>
                
                <!--DO WE STILL WANT THE TEXT BELOW?  IT LINKS TO A PAGE THAT NO LONGER EXISTS IN THE NEW STRUCTURE (crib.xml)-->
                
               <!-- <head>What to look for</head>
                <p>If you work in an archive and you would like to know what to look for, or if you
                    think you may have a fragment of Medieval polyphony, you can check it against
                    our <ref type="internal" cRef="p2_7_01">crib sheet of
                        notational styles</ref> (it is quite large, and so will download slowly).
                    However, this is not exhaustive, so if you are in any doubt, please contact us,
                    as we are always interested to hear of new sources.</p>-->
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>