<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_7">
    <teiHeader>

        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Copyright and Citation</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p/>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc><change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where necessary</change>
            <change/>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
       
            <div>
                <head>Copyright and permission for use</head>
                <div>
                    <head>Why can't I download the images?</head>
                    <p>DIAMM delivers images via a complex web-delivery system. The images are not
                        owned by DIAMM, but are available online through us thanks to rights
                        agreements with the owning institutions, and this rights agreement prohibits
                        the free download of images. DIAMM does not have permission to sell or give
                        away any of these images, since we are not the copyright holder.<!-- More
                        details about this can be found on the <ref type="internal" cRef="p2_3"
                            >Rights Protection page.</ref>--> If you wish to obtain personal copies of
                        images that you have seen on the DIAMM website you need to contact the
                        library that owns them. Clicking on the library name in any view will take
                        you to the library contact details.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I want to show pictures from the website in a lecture/presentation. Will I
                        be infringing copyright or breaching my access agreement?</head>
                    <p>The Website Access Agreement is clear that the images may only be used for
                        research or non-commercial reasons. Since teaching falls under this category
                        you may show any page from the DIAMM website either as a screenshot or live
                        during a lecture.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I want to publish an article using images from the DIAMM website. How can
                        I get permission?</head>
                    <p>If you wish to obtain print-quality copies of images that you have seen on
                        the DIAMM website you need to contact the library that owns them to obtain
                        permission. For publications you (or your publisher) may have to pay a
                        reproduction rights fee, although this is usually waived for academic (i.e.
                        non-profit) publications. Clicking on the library name in any view will take
                        you to the library contact details. Make sure that you give the accurate
                        information about which image(s) you require as it is extremely frustrating
                        for libraries if they are simply given the name of a piece. You must supply
                        the correct, complete shelf-mark for the manuscript, and the exact folio
                        number(s) of the images you require: this is found in the text displayed
                        beneath the images.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I want to get copies of the original images that I have seen on the
                        website. How can I get them?</head>
                    <p>If you wish to obtain copies of images that you have seen on the DIAMM
                        website you need to contact the library that owns them to obtain permission.
                        You will need to specify the size/quality of the image you want. Remember
                        that web-sized images are unsuitable for printing. If you ask for the
                        full-sized images you will need image-processing software such as Photoshop
                        or PaintShop Pro to open them. Clicking on the library name in any view will
                        take you to the library contact details. Make sure that you give the
                        accurate information about which image(s) you require as it is extremely
                        frustrating for libraries if they are simply given the name of a piece. You
                        must supply the correct, complete shelf-mark for the manuscript, and the
                        exact folio number(s) of the images you require: this is found in the text
                        displayed beneath the images.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>I am a collection holder and would like to have my digital images included
                        in the DIAMM collection. Will I have to pay to have them included?</head>
                    <p>There is no currently charge for adding your images of music manuscripts to
                        the DIAMM collection. Our delivery mechanism was built to handle as many
                        images as we can put into it, and the success of the site is largely
                        dependent on its content. We are therefore more than happy to include
                        digital images from other collections, provided there is no copyright
                        issue.</p>
                    <p>If your collection is of non-musical items we may also be able to deliver the
                        images. For a small number of images there would be no charge, but for
                        collections of significant size we may need to acquire more server space,
                        and that additional cost would have to be met by the depositor. Please
                        contact us if you would like more information about this service.</p>
                </div>

                <div>

                    <head>Rights protection</head>
                    <p>Unlike most commercial organisations, DIAMM has no interest in obtaining
                        rights to images of manuscript sources. Almost all the images archived by
                        the Project and accessible through the DIAMM website are owned (both
                        physically, and in terms of rights) by the institutions who own the original
                        document, even where the photography has been done by DIAMM. The images are
                        made available for archiving through a non-exclusive licence, which means
                        that the rights holder may give permission for them to appear anywhere else,
                        and is able to supply copies to anyone who requests them if they wish.</p>
                    <p>DIAMM is not an image supply service, so scholars requiring their own copies
                        of the images should contact the owner of the document as they would if they
                        were ordering a conventional image. If you wish to obtain copies of the
                        images created by DIAMM, you should request them when ordering. Please
                        ensure that you give the full and correct shelf mark and folio number as
                        this makes it much easier for the archive to locate the image you want</p>
                    <p>Users wishing to access catalogue information and other data about
                        manuscripts, but not requiring access to images do not need to register for
                        use of the site. Registration is necessary, however, to give access to the
                        high-resolution images which are available on this webiste. It also allows
                        access to a number of online tools which are specific to the user account,
                        including the ability to create a 'pick-list' of images.</p>
                    <p>Users wishing to obtain a password to access images through this website
                        should first read the <ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/AccessAgreement.pdf"
                            >Website Access Agreement (pdf)</ref>. This protects both DIAMM and the
                        contributing archives from the infringement of their rights, and ensures
                        users have agreed to respect and observe all aspects of copyright in the
                        images before they are given access to them. Users are strongly recommended
                        to download this document, read it and keep a copy, as online registration
                        constitutes formal agreement with this document. Online registration for
                        access to images in the DIAMM collection may be found by clicking on the
                        link 'Register with DIAMM' on the navigation bar. Registration is free.</p>
                    <p>In order to protect the rights and livelihood of libraries the DIAMM licences
                        are strictly honoured and enforced. Copies of the licences in <hi
                            rend="bold">pdf</hi> format may be downloaded by clicking on the links
                        below. The copyright in the construction of the licences themselves belongs
                        to DIAMM, but this right is waived for institutions or individuals wishing
                        to use the text in original or adjusted form for their own purposes.
                        However, DIAMM may not be held liable for any action arising from agreements
                        using the licences in this way, or resulting from the misuse of any matter
                        pertaining to the licences.</p>
                    <p><ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/AccessAgreement.pdf">Website Access Agreement
                            (pdf)</ref></p>
                    <p><ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/Digitization.pdf">Licence to Digitize and
                            Archive Primary Sources (pdf)</ref></p>
                    <p><ref type="external" target="http://www.diamm.ac.uk/redist/pdf/WebsiteInclusion.pdf">Licence to deliver images
                            via the DIAMM website portal (pdf)</ref></p>
                </div>
            </div>

        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
