<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p0_3_0"
	xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>More about the images</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>King's College London</publisher>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Text from Julia Craig-McFeely</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<revisionDesc>
			<change when="2011-08-17" who="Charlotte Tupman">Created page</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>The Ferrell-Vogüé Machaut manuscript (privately owned, currently on loan to
					GB-Cambridge, Corpus Christi College, Parker Library)</head>
				<p>The Ferrell-Vogüé Machaut manuscript (privately owned, currently on loan to
					GB-Cambridge, Corpus Christi College, Parker Library) Perhaps the most famous
					composer of the Medieval period was the poet-musician Guillaume de Machaut
					(1300-c.1375). He was unusual because he created his own 'collected editions' of
					his poetry and music during is lifetime (something no other composer did),
					supervising the copying, illumination and distribution of a number of manuscript
					copies of his works (this miniature shows Machaut himself). Probably the most
					famous manuscript of his works is this one, the Ferrell-Vogüé manuscript (named
					for its current owners and a previous owner). It is partly famous because
					although it has been widely known, it has always been in private hands so has
					until recently been almost impossible to see. The secrecy and inaccessibility of
					the manuscript have contributed to its notoriety, but also to its exceptionally
					fine state of preservation: its pages - about two thirds poetry and one third
					music - looking as bright and clear as the day they were written. Its current
					owners, James E and Elizabeth J Ferrell, have lent the manuscript to the library
					of Corpus Christi College, Cambridge, where scholars may visit and study the
					manuscript in person for the first time in its long life. Unlike the great
					English choirbooks or the choirbooks of the Alamire workshop, Machaut's books
					were not intended to be sung from by a large group of singers, but were usually
					presentation copies, and are therefore not so massive as the great choirbooks.
					Images of the entire MS can be seen on DIAMM by going to the listing for Corpus
					Christi. The book will also be published in facsimile by DIAMM Publications.</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
