<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p0_3_0"
	xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>More about the images</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>King's College London</publisher>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Text from Julia Craig-McFeely</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<revisionDesc>
			<change when="2011-08-09" who="Charlotte Tupman">Created page</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div xml:id="image08text">
				<head>The Eton Choirbook (GB-Eton, Eton College Library, MS 178)</head>
				<p>This MS is a rarity since it is still in the institution for which it was written
					- the only English MS to do so. It was written for Eton College chapel between
					around 1500 and 1504. As the chapel is dedicated to the Virgin Mary the MS
					contains many Marian works and antiphons to be performed at the services of the
					College. One reason that the MS has survived is that it was lost and forgotten
					for many years in a chest in an unused loft, and only rediscovered in 1895. The
					book is published in facsimile by DIAMM Publications, but images of the whole
					book can also be examined on this website. The original choirbook is over a
					metre in height and was designed to be placed on a large stand and read from by
					the whole choir, so the writing had to be very large. The music is all sacred,
					and copied in black and red, indicating different rhythms. Each voice part was
					copied in a different place on the opening, starting with a beautifully
					decorated initial at the beginning of a piece, and 'lesser' initials for
					continuations after page-turns. </p>
			</div>
			<div xml:id="image14text">
				<head>London, The National Archives, E 163/22/1/3</head>
				<p>Fragments are often all that survives of medieval music manuscripts, because the
					parchment the music was written on was considered more valuable than the music.
					Once the music fell out of fashion, the strong and expensive material that had
					been used to make the original book would be re-used, perhaps by scraping and
					refinishing, so that it could be written on again, or perhaps as structural
					supports for the binding of new books. Many books thus re-used survive only as
					isolated pages, pasted down to the hard front and back binding boards of the new
					binding (and now damaged and discoloured by glue), or in rarer cases cut up into
					narrow strips and wrapped around gatherings of pages to protect the stitching
					from wearing through. Sometimes a fragment might become the binding or wrapper
					for later documents, the outer side becoming rubbed and discoloured so that the
					music is lost, while the inner face remains bright and clear. Sadly some of
					these once beautiful leaves were even eaten by rats (who loved to eat gold leaf)
					or became mouldy and disintegrated, with only tantalising fragments left, though
					even fragments can provide evidence of the development of different musical
					scripts, and sometimes supply a missing voice part to a piece partially
					surviving in a different fragment. Digital restoration has recovered much music
					lost by this the accumulation of dirt and restored images can be seen alongside
					the originals in the image-viewer for these MSS in the DIAMM collection. Sadly
					gaps in the parchment can never be recovered, although the music on this leaf
					survives complete in another manuscript.</p>
			</div>
			<div xml:id="image25text">
				<head>The 'Old Hall' Manuscript (GB-London, British Library Add. Ms. 57950)</head>
				<p>Only four of the 'great' English choirbooks that must originally have numbered in
					their dozens (if not hundreds) survive today in a relatively intact state: Eton,
					Lambeth, Gonville and Caius and Old Hall. Old Hall got its name from a former
					location, St Edmund's College Library, Old Hall Green, nr Ware in Hertforshire.
					Now preserved in the British Library, the fragility and value of the manuscript
					means that it is no longer possible for scholars to handle it, so the images on
					DIAMM are currently the best and only way for members of the public to see the
					MS without buying the images themselves. It was originally copied c. 1410-20,
					though much of the music was composed before that. It may at one time have been
					at Winchester Cathedral, and is a very important source for the music of one of
					the most famous composers of the medieval period, John Dunstaple, and also
					contains works ascribed to King Henry. The music is mostly sacred, and is copied
					in black and red ink. Each piece opens with a beautifully decorated initial. The
					original book is very large as it was intended to be read from by all the
					singers at once. The book will be published in facsimile by DIAMM
					Publications.</p>
			</div>
			<div xml:id="image34text">
				<head>The Ferrell-Vogüé Machaut manuscript (privately owned, currently on loan to
					GB-Cambridge, Corpus Christi College, Parker Library)</head>
				<p>'collected editions' of his poetry and music during is lifetime (something no
					other composer did), supervising the copying, illumination and distribution of a
					number of manuscript copies of his works (this miniature shows Machaut himself).
					Probably the most famous manuscript of his works is this one, the Ferrell-Vogüé
					manuscript (named for its current owners and a previous owner). It is partly
					famous because although it has been widely known, it has always been in private
					hands so has until recently been almost impossible to see. The secrecy and
					inaccessibility of the manuscript have contributed to its notoriety, but also to
					its exceptionally fine state of preservation: its pages - about two thirds
					poetry and one third music - looking as bright and clear as the day they were
					written. Its current owners, James E and Elizabeth J Ferrell, have lent the
					manuscript to the library of Corpus Christi College, Cambridge, where scholars
					may visit and study the manuscript in person for the first time in its long
					life. Unlike the great English choirbooks or the choirbooks of the Alamire
					workshop, Machaut's books were not intended to be sung from by a large group of
					singers, but were usually presentation copies, and are therefore not so massive
					as the great choirbooks. Images of the entire MS can be seen on DIAMM by going
					to the listing for Corpus Christi. The book will also be published in facsimile
					by DIAMM Publications.</p>
			</div>
			<div xml:id="image48text">
				<head>B-Mechelen, Stadsarchief van Mechelen, manuscript without shelfmark</head>
				<p>This MS is one of the treasures of the town of Mechelen in Belgium, and they went
					to enormous trouble to allow DIAMM to photograph it in 2010. The manuscript was
					produced by the scriptorium of Petrus Alamire (c. 1470-1536), which began in
					Antwerp but moved to Mechelen some time between 1505 and 1516. Books prepared in
					Alamire's scriptorium survive all over the world, usually very beautifully
					preserved as they were nearly always created for Royal or noble patrons and were
					extremely highly prized. The largest collections of Alamire books today are in
					the Austrian National Library in Vienna, Austria, the Bibliotheque Royale in
					Brussels, Belgium and the University Library in Jena, Germany. The contents were
					both sacred and secular and they are all very large in size since they were
					designed so that a whole choir could sing from the one book. Alamire's books are
					famous for their elegant strapwork lesser initials, and fascinating 'grotesque'
					illuminations, showing caricature-like faces incorporated into capital letters,
					and real or imaginary animals. The style of the illumination is instantly
					recognisable even to the unpractised observer. The music in the books comes from
					a period of intense book production and musical activity, and includes works by
					most of the famous composers of the day such as Josquin des Pres and Pierre de
					la Rue. Alamire manuscripts became very valuable as gifts, and he produced music
					collections for most of the major Royal households of his day.</p>
			</div>
			<div xml:id="dowpartbookstext">
				<head>The Dow Partbooks (GB-Oxford, Christ Church Library, MSS 984-988)</head>
				<p>This is a complete set of five partbooks (each voice part was written in its own
					book) containing motets, anthems, consort music and consort songs, copied c.
					1581-88 principally by Robert Dow (1553-88), a fellow of All Souls College,
					Oxford, with later additions by John Baldwin and another unidentified copyist.
					This set is one of the most important surviving music manuscripts from
					Elizabethan England, and a major source of sacred and secular works by William
					Byrd. It is also famous for Dow's exquisite penmanship, executed in black ink
					over staves previously printed in red. Although many sets of partbooks survive
					from this period, few are so easy to read, and many of the sets are incomplete,
					lacking one or more of the books. Dow is not only complete, but was very
					accurately copied, so is a very reliable source for the music that it preserves.
					The whole set is published in facsimile by DIAMM Publications.</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
