<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_1">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>The Digital Image Archive of Medieval Music</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2012-02-13" who="Julia Craig-McFeely">Corrected external links</change>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2208-12-02</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Changed email address</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p1_1</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p1_1</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>

    <text>
        <body>
 <div>

                <head>Introduction</head>
                <p><hi rend="bold">DIAMM</hi> has been funded by the <ref
                        target="http://www.ahrc.ac.uk/" type="external">Arts and Humanities Research
                    Council</ref> and is currently supported by the <ref
                        target="http://www.mellon.org//" type="external">Andrew W
                        Mellon Foundation</ref>. It incorporates work from the Motet database
                    compiled by Thomas Schmidt-Beste and funded by the <ref
                        target="http://www.dfg.de/" type="external">Deutsche
                        Forschungsgemeinschaft</ref>.</p>

              <!-- <p>Read this introduction in <ref type="internal" cRef="p1_1_ger">GERMAN</ref>, <ref
                    type="internal" cRef="p1_1_ita">ITALIAN</ref>, <ref type="internal"
                    cRef="p1_1_spa">SPANISH</ref>, <ref type="internal" cRef="p1_1_fre"
                        >FRENCH</ref> or <ref type="external" cRef="http://webhostinggeeks.com/science/about-introduction-ro"
                            >ROMANIAN</ref> (with thanks to Alexander Ovsov for his translation)</p>-->
                <p>From its beginnings in 1998, the purpose of the Digital Image Archive of Medieval
                    Music (DIAMM) was to obtain and archive digital images of European sources of
                    medieval polyphonic music, captured directly from the original document. The
                    purposes were (1) conservation and protection against loss, especially of
                    vulnerable fragments, and (2) to enable libraries to supply the best possible
                    quality of images to scholars. High-quality direct digital capture ensures a
                    level of detail and colour accuracy that is not possible from scans of
                    surrogates such as slides or glossy photographs. In particular, this type of
                    imaging is crucial to detailed study. Normal single-shot digital photography
                    usually captures at a maximum of 7-11 Megapixels. The imaging used by DIAMM
                    captures at a maximum of 144 Megapixels. This extremely high resolution is
                    necessary for digital restoration. Where there is damage that makes these
                    sources difficult to read, detailed restoration of copies of the original images
                    is possible, to improve legibility and scholarly access.</p>
                <p>The project started as a collaboration between scholars at the <hi rend="bold"
                        >University of Oxford</hi> and <hi rend="bold">Royal Holloway</hi>, <hi
                        rend="bold">University of London</hi>, and is now based in Oxford in
                    collaboration with the University Music Faculty and the Bodleian Library. DIAMM
                    has created an electronic archive of more than 14,000 images, to assure their
                    permanent preservation, and is able to present a significant number of them
                    through this website to facilitate detailed study of this music and its
                    sources.</p>
                <p>The first three phases of work (digital capture and archiving) were funded by the
                    Humanities Research Board (1998), and by Major Research Grants from the Arts and
                    Humanities Research Board (1999 and 2001). The current phase of development of
                    the project website to create an online research environment for the images is
                    funded by the Andrew W Mellon Foundation.</p>
                <p>The sources archived include all the currently known fragmentary sources of
                    polyphony up to 1550 in the UK (almost all of these are available for study
                    through this website); all the ‘complete' manuscripts in the UK; a small number
                    of important representative manuscripts from continental Europe; a significant
                    portion of fragments from 1300-1450 from Belgium, France, Italy, Switzerland and
                    Spain. Such a collection of images, created under strict protocols to ensure
                    parity across such a varied collection, has never before been possible, and
                    represents an extraordinary resource for study of the repertory as a whole.
                    Although these manuscripts have been widely studied since their gradual
                    discovery by scholars at various times over the past century, dealing with the
                    repertory as a whole has been hampered by the very wide geographical spread of
                    the manuscripts and the limitations of microfilm or older b/w photography.
                    Fragments are far more numerous than complete sources, but most of them are the
                    sole remaining representatives of lost manuscripts. Some are barely legible and
                    hard to place and interpret. They amount to a rich but widely scattered resource
                    that has been relatively neglected, partly because of difficulty of access,
                    legibility and comparison of materials that are vulnerable to damage and
                    loss.</p>
                <p>The project has always aimed to improve its technical capability in line with
                    developments in software and hardware. Equipment and software are constantly
                    upgraded, and working policies are under review at all times to ensure the
                    highest photographic quality and broadest application of technical advances to
                    extract information from the images.</p>
                <p>DIAMM has concentrated in the last five years on developing a carefully tested
                    image capture and metadata standard. This has been in use for some time, and is
                    proving extremely robust. In many cases imaging quality and metadata content is
                    much higher than that delivered by many European institutions. In tandem with
                    this, the <ref type="internal" cRef="p1_7">licences</ref> written and used by
                    DIAMM have been used as models for institutions wishing to embark on
                    digitization.</p>
                <p>DIAMM now offers its expertise and experience to institutions and individuals
                    worldwide, enabling scholars to create collections based on their own research
                    requirements without having to undertake digital photography themselves (see
                    Services). The project manager and director is currently a consultant to the
                    National Library of Ireland in their establishment of a program to digitize
                    their entire holdings, and to the Israeli Antiquities Authority for the
                    digitization of the Dead Sea Scrolls.</p>
                <p>Since many of the fragmentary sources are damaged or obscured in some way, DIAMM
                    has developed restoration and editing techniques that can be applied to the
                    digital image without any procedure on the original manuscript source, following
                    digital capture. As a result, a number of new works have been discovered. Leaves
                    which were considered to contain no music or to be unreadable have been restored
                    to a state where their contents can be fully transcribed. This is a significant
                    contribution to scholarship on sources in this period. In addition to
                    large-scale restorations on full pages, unreadable notes or words on otherwise
                    readable pages have been improved or revealed by restoration processes, to the
                    point where new information has been provided about well-known sources.</p>
                <p>As well as DIAMM's restoration of images, revealing music where it was not
                    previously legible, visits to and contacts with archives and other institutions
                    have led to the discovery of a number of new sources. New sources are
                    continually notified to DIAMM, and photographed for the archive wherever
                    possible.</p>
                <p>Controlling MS metadata has included correcting and updating existing catalogue
                    entries for previously known sources (in particular where shelf marks have
                    changed), and creating data for new discoveries.</p>
                <p>The website represents the current development area for DIAMM. Better access,
                    more scholarly tools, and better-quality images coupled with shorter download
                    times are among our priorities. The metadata provided online is now no longer
                    limited to those sources for which we can provide images, but embraces all know
                    music manuscripts containing polyphony up to 1550. At present, the whole of RISM
                    Series B IV and the Census Catalogue of Manuscript Sources of Polyphonic Music
                    1400-1550 are included in the online database.</p>
                <p>The offline data content is much larger than that seen online. It includes music
                    incipits and is searchable by text, composer, language, clef, voice-part, number
                    of parts and many other parameters, all linked to both source descriptions and
                    individual images. Development of the resource during 2007-2010 will make all
                    this information available and searchable online.</p>
                <p>If you have a 'wish-list' of website and manuscript study tools, or notes on
                    usability of the resource, please <ref type="email"
                        target="DIAMM@music.ox.ac.uk">contact us by e-mail</ref>. We welcome
                    corrections to the data and additions to the bibliographies.</p>
                <strong>Licensing</strong>
                                <p>The image server uses the Kakadu JPEG2000 library under license.</p>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
