<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p0_3_0"
	xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>More about the images</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>King's College London</publisher>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Text from Julia Craig-McFeely</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<revisionDesc>
			<change when="2011-08-17" who="Charlotte Tupman">Created page</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>London, The National Archives, E 163/22/1/3</head>
				<p>Fragments are often all that survives of medieval music manuscripts, because the
					parchment the music was written on was considered more valuable than the music.
					Once the music fell out of fashion, the strong and expensive material that had
					been used to make the original book would be re-used, perhaps by scraping and
					refinishing, so that it could be written on again, or perhaps as structural
					supports for the binding of new books. Many books thus re-used survive only as
					isolated pages, pasted down to the hard front and back binding boards of the new
					binding (and now damaged and discoloured by glue), or in rarer cases cut up into
					narrow strips and wrapped around gatherings of pages to protect the stitching
					from wearing through. Sometimes a fragment might become the binding or wrapper
					for later documents, the outer side becoming rubbed and discoloured so that the
					music is lost, while the inner face remains bright and clear. Sadly some of
					these once beautiful leaves were even eaten by rats (who loved to eat gold leaf)
					or became mouldy and disintegrated, with only tantalising fragments left, though
					even fragments can provide evidence of the development of different musical
					scripts, and sometimes supply a missing voice part to a piece partially
					surviving in a different fragment. Digital restoration has recovered much music
					lost by this the accumulation of dirt and restored images can be seen alongside
					the originals in the image-viewer for these MSS in the DIAMM collection. Sadly
					gaps in the parchment can never be recovered, although the music on this leaf
					survives complete in another manuscript.</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
