<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p0_3_0"
	xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>More about the images</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>King's College London</publisher>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Text from Julia Craig-McFeely</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<revisionDesc>
			<change when="2011-08-17" who="Charlotte Tupman">Created page</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>B-Mechelen, Stadsarchief van Mechelen, manuscript without shelfmark</head>
				<p>This MS is one of the treasures of the town of Mechelen in Belgium, and they went
					to enormous trouble to allow DIAMM to photograph it in 2010. The manuscript was
					produced by the scriptorium of Petrus Alamire (c. 1470-1536), which began in
					Antwerp but moved to Mechelen some time between 1505 and 1516. Books prepared in
					Alamire's scriptorium survive all over the world, usually very beautifully
					preserved as they were nearly always created for Royal or noble patrons and were
					extremely highly prized. The largest collections of Alamire books today are in
					the Austrian National Library in Vienna, Austria, the Bibliotheque Royale in
					Brussels, Belgium and the University Library in Jena, Germany. The contents were
					both sacred and secular and they are all very large in size since they were
					designed so that a whole choir could sing from the one book. Alamire's books are
					famous for their elegant strapwork lesser initials, and fascinating 'grotesque'
					illuminations, showing caricature-like faces incorporated into capital letters,
					and real or imaginary animals. The style of the illumination is instantly
					recognisable even to the unpractised observer. The music in the books comes from
					a period of intense book production and musical activity, and includes works by
					most of the famous composers of the day such as Josquin des Pres and Pierre de
					la Rue. Alamire manuscripts became very valuable as gifts, and he produced music
					collections for most of the major Royal households of his day.</p>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
