<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_2"
	xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
	<teiHeader>
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title>News</title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher>King's College London</publisher>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<p>Basic Website pdf</p>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<revisionDesc>
			<change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
				necessary</change>
			<change><date>2009-03-18</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added new item regarding BL
				acquisition</change>
			<change><date>2009-02-03</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added new news items</change>
			<change><date>2008-08-05</date><name>AC</name>Added divGen to create link to
				RSS</change>
			<change><date>2008-05-05</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added loads of content ahead of
				1.8 going live.</change>
			<change><date>2007-04-25</date><name>JCM</name>Text content update</change>
			<change><date>2006-04-24</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
				update</change>
			<change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Papakostouli Artemis</name>creation of p4</change>
		</revisionDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text>
		<body>
			<div>
				<head>News</head>
				<div>
					<head>Ferrell-Vogüé Machaut Manuscript</head>
					<p>23 August, 2010</p>
					<p>"The Ferrell-Vogüé Machaut MS (formerly known variously as Vg, Vogüé,
						Wildenstein, etc.) is now available in its entirety online through the DIAMM
						website. The MS is currently on loan to Corpus Christi College, Cambridge
						through the generosity of the owners, James E. and Elizabeth J. Ferrell, and
						the images may be accessed on the website by navigating to that library once
						you are logged in (i.e. Great Britain &gt; Cambridge &gt; Corpus Christi
						College &gt; Ferrell-Vogue MS).</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>AHRC DEDEFI grant award</head>
					<p>4 February, 2010</p>
					<p>We have received the excellent and exciting news of the award of a 1-year
						grant from the AHRC that will enable to project to run for a further year;
						to upgrade our excellent single-shot camera from 39 megapixels to 65 Mpx; to
						obtain further images of fragments in France and Italy; to create an online
						course in reading medieval music to accompany the manuscript images on the
						website; and to continue updating and improving the database content so that
						when the new website comes online the content will be more complete and more
						usefully searchable by users.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Photography work in Spain</head>
					<p>25 January, 2010</p>
					<p>Lynda Sayce, project photographer, has just returned from Spain, having spent
						two weeks with David Catalunya working in Spanish Libraries around Madrid
						and Barcelona. Fragments and complete sources from Barcelona, Burgos,
						Madrid, Solsona, Tarragona, Valladolid and Vallbona, were photographed in a
						whirlwind tour during some of the worst weather conditions for travel that
						we have yet encountered (it took 75 mins to get the car from my front door
						to the main road!). We await news on permissions for making these images
						available online.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM announces upcoming facsimile publications</head>
					<p>1 January, 2010</p>
					<p>DIAMM is launching two high quality colour facsimile publications as the
						pilot outputs for DIAMM Publications: The Eton Choirbook and the Dow
						Partbooks. Full details of the publications, plus a generous pre-publication
						discount, can be seen on our publications page.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Margaret Bent awarded Claude Palisca Prize</head>
					<p>15 November, 2009</p>
					<p>This year's Claude Palisca Prize for an outstanding edition or translation
						has been awarded to Margaret Bent for the introductory study and facsimile
						of the MS Bologna Q15. The photography, typesetting and page-makeup were all
						done by DIAMM, and the citation says "the quality of photography and
						reproduction is breathtaking. Photographed in color when it was disbound,
						with illegible pages digitally restored, the edition allows us to read some
						music for the very first time. Initials have been filmed on both sides
						enabling the editor to discern music that was discarded when the manuscript
						was recopied. Reproducing the original cover, watermarks, and gathering
						signatures, the facsimile can actually claim to be more useful and
						informative than having the original on one's desk." The publication was the
						unanimous choice of the committee.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM Associate Directors</head>
					<p>1 October, 2009</p>
					<p>As part of the restructuring of DIAMM following the retirement of Prof Andrew
						Wathey as a project director, the following have been appointed associate
						directors:</p>
					<p>Dr Nicolas Bell (British Library)</p>
					<p>Dr Elizabeth Eva Leach (Faculty of Music, University of Oxford)</p>
					<p>Dr Martin Kauffmann (Bodleian Library, Oxford)</p>
					<p>Dr Owen Rees (Faculty of Music, University of Oxford)</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM introduces online donations</head>
					<p>21 May, 2009</p>
					<p>DIAMM is now set up to accept donations from its users. A new DIAMM PayPal
						account has been set up into which users can donate any amount they choose
						in any currency in which they have a credit card or bank account.</p>
					<p>It is not necessary for users to have an existing personal PayPal account in
						order to donate.</p>
					<p>If you would like to consider donating to DIAMM in order to keep it free to
						all users, please go to the <ref type="internal" cRef="p1_6">donations
							page</ref> and click on the 'Donate' button.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>More new British Library images</head>
					<p>18 March, 2009</p>
					<p>Due to some recent image acquisitions, we are pleased to announce that the
						following complete manuscripts from the British Library are available to be
						viewed online:</p>
					<p>Add. 5465</p>
					<p>Add. 31922</p>
					<p>Add. 57950</p>
					<p>Egerton 3307</p>
					<p>Royal 11.e.xi</p>
					<p>Royal 8.g.vii</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>New images available: Dow and Peterhouse Partbooks</head>
					<p>1 March, 2009</p>
					<p>DIAMM is pleased to announce that we have just made available more than 3700
						new images on our website. These images are from two very important
						collections from the latter half of the 16th century.</p>
					<p>DIAMM is excited to present online a very famous set of partbooks held at
						Christ Church in Oxford. Known as the 'Dow partbooks', these contain a large
						amount English music by Byrd, Parsons, White, and many other important
						composers from the third quater of the 16th century.</p>
					<p>The shelfmarks for these books are: Oxford, Christ Church, Mus. 984-988.</p>
					<p>In 2008 DIAMM began a collaboration with Peterhouse, Cambridge. 2720
						manuscript images of books housed there are now available online. These are
						from the following books:</p>
					<p>471 - 474, the so-called 'Henrican partbooks'.</p>
					<p>475</p>
					<p>476</p>
					<p>477</p>
					<p>478</p>
					<p>479</p>
					<p>480</p>
					<p>481</p>
					<p>485</p>
					<p>486</p>
					<p>487</p>
					<p>489</p>
					<p>This project will eventually make available all of the music manuscripts held
						at Peterhouse. The remaining three partbooks are current undergoing
						resotoration work and will be photographed in the summer of 2009 while
						unbound.</p>

				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM appoints intern for 2009</head>
					<p>1 February, 2009</p>
					<p>DIAMM has appointed an intern for 2009. Giovanni Varelli will be mainly
						involved in creating inventories.</p>
					<p>Giovanni graduated from the University of Pavia in Italy, from the Faculty of
						Musicology, in December 2008. He studied medieval music manuscripts,
						liturgy, paleography, neumatic notation, and codicology with Professor
						Giacomo Baroffio.</p>
					<p>Giovanni will also be involved with the Digital Catalogue of Illuminated
						Manuscripts at the British Library, working closely with Dr Nicolas Bell,
						one of DIAMM's Associate Directors.</p>
					<p>Giovanni currently works with the editors of <emph>Medioevo Musicale</emph>,
						an Italian medieval music bibliography bulletin.</p>

				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Funding secured by The Alamire Foundation for Alamire Choirbooks Online
						project</head>
					<p>12 September, 2008</p>
					<p>We are pleased to announce that The Alamire Foundation have recently been
						awarded €150 000 over three years to finance its ongoing work. A large
						portion of this money will be dedicated to the photography, processing, and
						delivery of the images required for the proposed Alamire Choirbooks Online
						project in collaboration with DIAMM.</p>
					<p> The grant came from a foundation closely connected with the Katholieke
						Universiteit Leuven.</p>
					<p>Work has already been initiated on photographing these sources and both DIAMM
						and The Alamire Foundation look forward to seeing the fruits of their
						collaboration appear online soon.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Morrill Music Library, Villa I Tatti provides seed funding for Alamire
						Choirbooks Online project</head>
					<p>29 August, 2008</p>
					<p>DIAMM today was made the beneficiary of a €10 000 grant from The Morril Music
						Library at Villa I Tatti (The Harvard University Centre for Italian
						Renaissance Studies). This money is to be used specifically for the
						acquisition of high-quality digital images of Alamire choirbooks and is the
						first funding received for the new Alamire Choirbooks Online collaboration
						between The Alamire Foundation and DIAMM.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Launch of new website</head>
					<p>12 May, 2008</p>
					<p>Version 1.8 of the DIAMM online resource was brought online on. Apart from a
						reorganisation of the information pages this iteration brings several
						important technical changes online. </p>
					<p>
						<xmt:uList>
							<item>The list of countries and libraries now uses tabbed browsing, and
								creates lists in columns rather than run-on paragraphs. The original
								display was designed for a relatively small number of countries and
								cities, and became redundant with the expansion of metadata content
								to embrace all known manuscript sources.</item>
							<item>The image viewer now allows zoomified images to extend to the full
								width of the browser window, optimising the screen space available
								for viewing images</item>
							<item>Several new content tabs have been added to the image-viewer
								toolbar: ‘Other images I've commented on'; ‘Transcriptions';
								‘Catalogue images', all of which will allow you to maintain a
								fingertip connection to your use of the web images.</item>
						</xmt:uList><p/>
					</p>
					<p>There are numerous content updates, the most important of which is the
						expansion of the abbreviated bibliographies taken from RISM and CCM to full
						citations of every entry. Unfortunately this is not yet available for every
						source description, but this is because we found that many of the
						abbreviations in the bibliographies were not provided with full expansions
						in the full bibliography lists in these catalogues. We are working on
						supplying the information, and future uploads should include the new
						data.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Alamire collaboration</head>
					<p>19 March, 2008</p>
					<p>DIAMM has been in collaboration for some time with the University of Jena
						regarding the digitization of their choirbook collection, which includes one
						of the larges collections of manuscripts originally prepared by the workshop
						of Petrus Alamire in the Netherlands. The digitization of the collection
						(which is still ongoing) led to the conception of a project within DIAMM to
						digitize all the Alamire books that survive, and to make them available as
						‘Alamire Choirbooks Online'. The primary research and early organisation of
						this project was undertaken by Greg Skidmore, the DIAMM Outreach Research
						Co-ordinator. With the additional support and enthusiasm of Michael Friebel
						in Vienna, DIAMM secured an invitation from the ONB to digitize their
						Alamire collection, which is rivalled only by that of Jena in size and
						importance. We are investigating funding that would allow us to undertake
						this work as soon as possible, together with the Alamire books in other
						libraries across a number of European countries. </p>
					<p>A recent development in this exciting project is what we hope will turn into
						a fruitful collaboration between DIAMM and the Alamire Foundation in Leuven.
						Members of both groups will be meeting in Oxford in May 2008 to discuss
						plans for digitization and the eventual presentation of these manuscripts
						online. We look forward to reporting on the outcome of this meeting.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Professor Thomas Schmidt-Beste appointed Director</head>
					<p>25 February, 2008</p>
					<p>We are very pleased to announce the appointment of Professor Thomas
						Schmidt-Beste as a new Director of DIAMM following the retirement of
						Professor Andrew Wathey. </p>
					<p>Thomas Schmidt-Beste came to Bangor University as Professor of Music and Head
						of School in 2005, after having taught at the universities of Heidelberg and
						Frankfurt. One of his main research interests (besides the music of
						Mendelssohn and Mozart) has always been the music of the late Middle Ages
						and the Renaissance, and the study of sources of that period in particular.
						From 1995 to 2002, he was employed as a postdoctoral research assistant at
						the "Cappella Sistina" research project of the Heidelberg Academy of Arts
						and Sciences, cataloguing the music manuscripts of the Papal Chapel in the
						Vatican Library. In 1998-9, he was a Fedor Lynen Fellow of the Humboldt
						Foundation, working in the Renaissance Music Archives at the University of
						Illinois-Urban/Champaign. After his <hi rend="italic">Habilitation </hi>in
						2001 (on Text Declamation in the 15th-Century Motet), he initiated a
						research database on 15th- and early-16th-century motets which was funded by
						the <hi rend="italic">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</hi>, first through a
						Heisenberg Senior Research Fellowship (2002-2005) and then through a large
						research grant (2005-2007). The project is ongoing and output from it will
						soon be made available through DIAMM. Thomas Schmidt-Beste is a member of
						the editorial board of <hi rend="italic">Die Musik in Geschichte und
							Gegenwart</hi>; a founding member of the Institute of Medieval and Early
						Modern Studies (IMEMS) at Bangor/Aberystwyth; secretary of the Plainsong and
						Medieval Music Society; and a member of RMA Council. In the autumn of 2008,
						he will spend a term as a Visiting Fellow of All Souls College, Oxford.</p>
					<p>Professor Thomas Schmidt-Beste and his research team have been working for
						several years on (among other things) transcriptions of full texts of motets
						in original and modern spellings, and the creation of new diplomatic
						incipits for this corpus of music, represented until now only by the
						manuscript descriptions provided in RISM. These descriptions were created in
						some cases nearly half a century ago, and used shortcuts such as referring
						the reader to incipits of the same work in another manuscript which may have
						used a different notational style, thus misrepresenting the contents of the
						first manuscript.</p>
					<p>These new incipits and the transcriptions of the texts will soon become
						available and will be searchable through the DIAMM website. Work on creating
						the data is ongoing and will be incorporated into the website on a rolling
						basis.</p>
					<p>Crucial to the creation of new incipits since 2007 has been the development
						by Theodor Dumitrescu of his CMME software, which allows early music
						notations to be encoded in xml, making the output searchable and
						editable.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM receives major equipment grant from the John Fell OUP Research
						Fund</head>
					<p>21 February, 2008</p>
					<p>DIAMM has been awarded a grant of £28,000 from the John Fell OUP Fund to
						enable us to purchase a new single-shot high-resolution digital camera, the
						PhaseOne P45+.</p>
					<p>The camera will enable DIAMM to photograph at its customary high standards,
						but at much greater speed than has been possible with existing equipment,
						thus bringing per-image costs down dramatically. The P45+ is a 'single-shot'
						digital camera, which means that it operates much as any consumer camera:
						the click of the shutter takes the picture. The big difference with this
						camera is that its sensor is large enough to obtain archive quality images.
						It is suitable for documents around A4 size and smaller. For larger
						documents, or those requiring higher resolution the project will continue to
						use the PhaseOne PowerPhase scanning back.</p>
					<p>This new equipment also enables DIAMM to complete work for client projects at
						a much lower cost than would have originally been considered. As an example,
						one project would have taken around 5 months to complete with the PhaseOne
						PowerPhase, but could be done in less than a month with the new P45+. This
						brings many projects that have been financially out of reach into the realm
						of possibility.</p>
					<p>DIAMM is extremely grateful to the Faculty of Music in Oxford for sponsoring
						its application, and to Alex Lumbers for guiding us through the application
						process, and suggesting the Fund to us initially. </p>
					<p>The camera is available to other Humanities departments in Oxford when it is
						not in use by DIAMM.</p>
				</div>

				<div>
					<head>Professor Andrew Wathey retires as Director</head>
					<p>20 February, 2008</p>
					<p>Following his appointment as Vice-Chancellor of the University of
						Northumbria, Andrew Wathey has stepped down as an active director of DIAMM,
						though remains involved in the project as a Founding Director. We are very
						sorry to lose his valuable advice and participation in the project that he
						co-founded, and wish him well in his new post.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Prof Andrew Wathey Appointed Vice-Chancellor of the University of
						Northumbria</head>
					<p>19 December, 2007</p>
					<p>Professor Andrew Wathey, co-founder and Director of DIAMM has been appointed
						to the position of Vice-Chancellor of the University of Northumbria at
						Newcastle. For the last few years Prof Wathey has been Vice-Principal for
						Planning and Resources at Royal Holloway, and recently the senior
						Vice-Principal.</p>
				</div>

				<div>
					<head>Installation of master database server</head>
					<p>11 November, 2007</p>
					<p>Data input to the master DIAMM database forms a very large part of our
						day-to-day work. The inclusion of the whole of RISM series BIV and the
						Census Catalogue involves not simply cutting and pasting the scanned text,
						but careful proof-reading and the transfer of the information it contains to
						fields that will eventually be searchable online. In addition there is a
						considerable amount of work involved in keying the bibliographical
						abbreviations to the full citations, and marking up the full bibliographical
						citations to a consistent house style.</p>
					<p>In 2008 we appointed a number of new research assistants. Under the guidance
						of Prof Thomas Schmidt-Beste in Bangor, Diane Temme was put in charge of
						proofing the German text entries and Alison Salter works on the database of
						motet texts. Tim Symonds in Newcastle took on much of the English-language
						proof-reading, with assistance from Eleanor Weaver and Joe Bell in Oxford.
						Ben Ganly took on the mammoth task of checking and marking up the
						bibliography database of nearly 3400 items, about 300 of which were
						incomplete or too vague to be of use as expanded references.</p>
					<p>This meant of course that, along with the existing DIAMM staff, a large
						number of people from all over the country needed access to the master
						offline database. Ican, who provide us with technical support for our
						Filemaker databases installed a Filemaker web server, and the working
						database went live in November 2007. The server had the added benefit of
						being able to serve databases from sister projects, Chopin's First Editions
						Online (<ref type="external" target="http://www.cfeo.org.uk"
							>www.cfeo.org.uk</ref>) and the Online Chopin Variorum Edition (<ref
							type="external" target="http://www.ocve.org.uk">www.ocve.org.uk</ref>).
						Naturally this working database is not visible to the public, but the
						results of the work being done on it are becoming increasingly visible as
						our content expands and is constantly enriched.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Establishment of International Advisory Board</head>
					<p>15 October, 2007</p>
					<p> The advice of the scholarly community has always shaped the activities of
						DIAMM, and ensured that it meets the needs of the scholars for whom it is
						principally intended. Many of these scholars have contributed to shaping the
						content of DIAMM by negotiating with the owners of documents on which they
						are working to allow DIAMM to photograph them, or facilitated our work
						abroad with their assistance and advice. In many cases they have also
						contributed information about new discoveries and updates to our manuscript
						descriptions, which are largely drawn from relatively old printed
						catalogues.</p>
					<p>The establishment of the International Advisory Board gives recognition for
						the support and contribution of these scholars, and also formalizes their
						activities as part of the essential roots of DIAMM.</p>
					<p>
						<hi rend="bold">DIAMM International Advisory Board:</hi>
					</p>
					<p>
						<xmt:uList>
							<item>Michael Scott Cuthbert, Massachusetts Institute of
								Technology</item>
							<item>Theodor Dumitrescu, University of Utrecht</item>
							<item>Michael Friebel, University of Salzburg</item>
							<item>Marco Gozzi, University of Trento</item>
							<item>Oliver Huck, University of Hamburg</item>
							<item>Martin Kirbauer, University of Basel, Historisches Museum
								Basel</item>
							<item>Karl Kügle, University of Utrecht</item>
							<item>Peter M. Lefferts, University of Nebraska-Lincoln</item>
							<item>Pedro Memelsdorff, Barcelona Conservatory, Fondazione Giorgio Cini
								(Venice), Mala Punica (Bologna)</item>
							<item>John Nádas, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</item>
							<item>Jason Stoessel, University of New England</item>
							<item>Philippe Vendrix, Centre d'Etudes Supérieurs de la Renaissance,
								University of Tours</item>
							<item>Lorenz Welker, University of Munich</item>
							<item>Giovanni Zanovello, Padua</item>
							<item>Francesco Zimei, Istituto Abruzzese di Storia Musicale</item>
						</xmt:uList><p/>
					</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Dr Suzannah Clark appointed Associate Director of DIAMM</head>
					<p>22 September, 2007</p>
					<p>Dr Suzannah Clark, Lecturer in Music and Fellow of Merton College, Oxford
						joins Dr Nicolas Bell, Dr Elizabeth Eva Leach and Prof Thomas Schmidt-Beste
						as an Associate Director of DIAMM, building on our existing Oxford
						connection. Dr Clark works primarly on the history of music theory, and has
						focused in particular on Rameau, Fétis, Oettingen, Schenker, as well as
						neo-Riemannian approaches. She is interested in how theorists underpin their
						systems with appeals to external phenomena and how this affects their
						conceptions of tonal space. She is also currently working on a book <hi
							rend="italic">Analyzing Schubert</hi>, which is a reception history of
						Schubert's harmony in both the songs and instrumental music. Her medieval
						research focuses on the 13th-century French motet and its use of the
						'refrain', and she teaches undergraduate courses in the Music Faculty on the
						motet from c.1220-1450 and the lyric traditions of the troubadours and
						trouvères, among other subjects.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Appointment of Outreach Research Co-ordinator (ORC)</head>
					<p>5 August, 2007</p>
					<p>Greg Skidmore, one of the team of researchers working on DIAMM has been
						appointed Outreach Research Co-ordinator. Greg will head up negotiations and
						organisation of collaborative projects with other organisations, and is
						starting with the establishment of a working group to examine the financial
						and practical needs of the digitization and online presentation of the
						Alamire Choirbooks, a project that has been under consideration for several
						years.</p>
					<p>Greg is currently a DPhil candidate at the University of Oxford, studying the
						printed music book trade in the 16th and early 17th centuries using the
						music library of King John IV of Portugal as a case study. He is also a
						professional singer, employed in Oxford at Christ Church Cathedral as a Lay
						Clerk. He also sings regularly with The Gabrieli Consort, I Fagiolini, and
						Ex Cathedra and is busy on the oratorio circuit.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Digitization of the Peterhouse partbooks</head>
					<p>23 May, 2007</p>
					<p>A major initiative was undertaken in May 2007 with the start of digitization
						of the Peterhouse Partbooks. Partly stimulated by the discovery of several
						of the lost partbooks, Scott Mandelbrote and Peterhouse Cambridge decided
						that the partbooks should be restored and digitized.</p>
					<p>The digitization is being undertaken by DIAMM's photographer Lynda Sayce, in
						Cambridge and in Devon, where some of the books are being restored. The
						digitization is ongoing due to the large number of books and folios. Work
						will be completed some time in 2008, and the images will be brought online
						through the DIAMM website on a rolling basis.</p>
					<p>In total this project will digitize 18 partbooks, realising several thousand
						new images of central early modern English repertory.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>New Phase of development work begins with funding from the Andrew W Mellon
						Foundation</head>
					<p>1 January, 2007</p>
					<p>A major technical development grant from the Andrew W Mellon Foundation has
						given DIAMM funds to expand its data content dramatically, and undertake
						major work on the web delivery mechanism that will radically enhance content
						and improve the user interface.</p>
					<p>The first change that users will notice is that registration for use of the
						site no longer requires users to download, print, sign and post a user
						access agreement. Online registration has been implemented, so that access
						to all the images on the site can be gained within seconds.</p>
					<p>Many other improvements and enhancements will become visible in a staged
						upgrading process from now until December 2009.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Appointment of Associate Directors for DIAMM</head>
					<p>23 October, 2006</p>
					<p>We are pleased to announce the appointment of Nicolas Bell (British Library),
						Elizabeth Eva Leach (Royal Holloway) and Professor Thomas Schmidt-Beste
						(Bangor) as Associate Directors of DIAMM. Direction and support from those
						involved in medieval musicology is essential to the development of the DIAMM
						resource as a research entity, and we look forward to their input and advice
						in planning and realising our future.</p>
					<p>Dr Nicolas Bell is Curator of Music Manuscripts at the British Library. His
						research interests centre on polyphonic music of the thirteenth and early
						fourteenth centuries, and his study of the Las Huelgas Codex was published
						by Testimonio of Madrid in 2003. He acts as reviews editor for <hi
							rend="italic">Plainsong &amp; Medieval Music</hi> and <hi rend="italic"
							>The Library (Transactions of the Bibliographical Society)</hi>. and
						sits on the Councils of the Plainsong and Medieval Music Society and the
						Henry Bradshaw Society as well as the Advisory Board of the Cantus Planus
						Study Group of the International Musicological Society.</p>
					<p>Elizabeth Eva Leach is Reader in Music at Royal Holloway, University of
						London and specializes in the music and poetry of lyrics in
						fourteenth-century France. A historical musicologist and music theorist, she
						recently received the Outstanding Publication Award of the Society for Music
						Theory for an article on the gendering of the semitone in fourteenth-century
						theory. Her book, <hi rend="italic">Sung Birds: Music, Nature, and Poetry in
							the Later Middle Ages</hi> was published by Cornell in 2007. She is
						currently Chairman of the Plainsong and Medieval Music Society and has just
						completed a book on Guillaume de Machaut during a period of leave funded by
						RHUL and the AHRC. </p>
					<p>Thomas Schmidt-Beste came to Bangor University as Professor of Music and Head
						of School in 2005, after having taught at the universities of Heidelberg and
						Frankfurt. As well as the music of the late Middle Ages and the Renaissance,
						and the study of sources of that period in particular, he has done research
						on Mozart and Mendelssohn. After his <hi rend="italic">Habilitation </hi>in
						2001 (on Text Declamation in the 15th-Century Motet), he initiated a
						research database on 15th- and early-16th-century motets which was funded by
						the <hi rend="italic">Deutsche Forschungsgemeinschaft</hi>, first through a
						Heisenberg Senior Research Fellowship (2002-2005) and then through a large
						research grant (2005-2007). The project is ongoing and output from it will
						soon be made available through DIAMM. Thomas Schmidt-Beste is a member of
						the editorial board of <hi rend="italic">Die Musik in Geschichte und
							Gegenwart</hi>; a founding member of the Institute of Medieval and Early
						Modern Studies (IMEMS) at Bangor/Aberystwyth; secretary of the Plainsong and
						Medieval Music Society; and a member of RMA Council.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>Dr Julia Craig-McFeely appointed co-Director of DIAMM</head>
					<p>1 October, 2006</p>
					<p>Since its inception in 1998 DIAMM has been managed by Dr Julia Craig-McFeely,
						who undertook all management tasks as well as considerable travelling
						throughout the UK and Europe, visiting libraries and archives to photograph
						their documents. Early in 2007 her contribution to the development and
						growth of DIAMM was recognised when she was made a Director of DIAMM. She
						was made a Research Fellow of Royal Holloway, Unversity of London, in early
						2007.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>AHRC ICT Methods Network: Digital Image Restoration Workshop</head>
					<p>29 June, 2006</p>
					<!--<p>
					<xref type="external"
						url="http://www.methodsnetwork.ac.uk/activities/workshops.html"
						>http://www.methodsnetwork.ac.uk/activities/workshops.html</xref>
				</p>-->
					<p>The DIAMM Digital Restoration Workshop, took place at Oxford University on 29
						June 2006.</p>
					<p>This centred on the pioneering use of mainstream commercial software to
						recover damaged and obscured readings from manuscript sources which have
						been captured by high-resolution digital imaging. As the facilities required
						to create high quality digital images become more widely available in
						libraries and other repositories, increasing numbers of scholars are looking
						to this medium to reveal information that has either been obscured by
						conventional document restoration processes, or has proved beyond the
						capacity of conventional restoration to reveal. The main advantage of
						digital restoration is the lack of invasive procedure on the original
						document, and the provision of an image that may be more revealing than the
						original.</p>
					<p>DIAMM has been demonstrating the results of digital restoration at
						conferences and seminars for some years, and this workshop was organised by
						the AHRC ICT Methods Network in response to demand from scholars
						internationally to learn the techniques and underlying methods used by DIAMM
						this process. Full training materials and information about creating a
						suitable "master" image were provided.</p>
					<p>Participants received a printed workbook, and this is also available to buy
						in hard copy (price £10 plus p+p), or to download as pdf which can then be
						printed. Unfortunately because of rights issues we are not currently able to
						supply the images used for demonstration purposes during the workshop, but
						the descriptions and examples in the book should be sufficient to enable
						users to try the techniques on their own images.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>New content</head>
					<p>31 May, 2006</p>
					<p>Two major British Library MSS have been brought online - Add. 57950 (The Old
						Hall Manuscript) and Eg. 3307. These are both major sources of medieval
						English polyphony, and contrast with much of our content as the sources are
						complete rather than fragmentary. Dr Bent has long been associated with the
						Old Hall Manuscript through her pioneering work on John Dunstaple, and users
						will be glad to have access to these superb high-resolution colour
						images.</p>
					<p>In addition to these major manuscripts, 152 enhanced images and 225 UV images
						have been brought online and are viewable alongside their unrestored
						counterparts, photographed with normal light.</p>
				</div>
				<div>
					<head>DIAMM Project Manager appointed to manage Chopin project</head>
					<p>1 January, 2006</p>
					<p>
						<ref type="external" target="http://www.ocve.org.uk"
							>http://www.ocve.org.uk</ref>
					</p>
					<p>The Online Chopin Variorum Edition, was guided through its pilot phase by
						Director Professor John Rink and Project Manager Dr Danae Stefanou.
						Following Dr Stefanou's appointment to a lectureship in Greece OCVE sought a
						new project manager experienced in handling digital images.</p>
					<p>As DIAMM had been advising OCVE and its sister project Chopin's First
						Editions Online (<ref type="external" target="http://www.cfeo.org.uk"
							>www.cfeo.org.uk</ref>) in managing its metadata and imaging needs, the
						progression to taking over management duties from Dr Stefanou was natural,
						and took place seamlessly in March 2007. </p>
				</div>
			</div>
		</body>
	</text>
</TEI>
