<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_3_4"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Partners/Sponsors</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>Basic Website pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2012-02-13" who="Julia Craig-McFeely">removed information that should be on another page (acknowledgements), revised reference to DDH and funding info, revised internal link to reports</change>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2006-05-10</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-6</date><name>Papakostouli Artemis</name>creation of p5_3</change>
            <change><date>2007-11-29</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Partner institutions</head>
                
                <div>
                    <head>
                        <ref target="http://www.kcl.ac.uk/artshums/depts/ddh/index.aspx" type="external">The
                            Department for Digital Humanities</ref>
                    </head>
                    <p>The development and exploitation of the DIAMM web resource is
                        managed by the research team at DDH, who have devoted much time and
                        expertise to exploring the needs of scholars and expanding our
                        resource, and continue to apply their developments to the DIAMM website.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>
                        <ref target="http://www.bodley.ox.ac.uk" type="external">The Bodleian
                            Library, University of Oxford</ref>
                    </head>
                    <p>The Bodleian Library will be hosting DIAMM's dark data archive, our master
                        images not available on the internet.</p>
                </div>
            </div>
            

<div>
    <head>Financial support</head>
    <div>
        <head>The <ref target="http://www.alamirefoundation.org/" type="external">Alamire Foundation</ref> (Leuven) funded by the <ref target="http://www.iwt.be/" type="external">Agentschap voor Innovatie door Wetenschap en Technologie
        </ref></head>
        <p>In October 2011, The Alamire Foundation was awarded funds to follow an ambitious programme of digitization and technical activity
        over three years, to create a permanent resource celebrating the work of the scriptorium of Petrus Alamire. Included was funding to provide DIAMM project mangement and photography to support these activities.</p>
    </div>
    <div>
        <head>The Andrew W Mellon Foundation </head>
        <p>The Mellon Foundation has sponsored the development of the DIAMM website and
            delivery systems and also the purchase of an upgrade to our scanning back
            for high-resolution image capture. More recently they have funded the
            development of online research tools, the expansion of the online archive
            and metadata content, and a number of workshops and studies aimed at
            ensuring we meet the needs of the public, and build a resource that should
            be able to sustain itself financially in the future. DIAMM is extremely
            grateful not only for the financial support of the Mellon Foundation, but
            also for the guidance it gives in developing the project as a major online
            research resource. DIAMM is currently funded by a major grant from the
            Mellon Foundation.</p>
        <p> If you would like to view a series of reports DIAMM has created for the
            Mellon Foundation, please <ref type="internal" cRef="p1_3_6">click here</ref>.
        </p>
    </div>
    <div>
                    <head>The Arts and Humanities Research Council</head>
                    <p>The original grant that started DIAMM and sponsored all the photographic work
                        came from the Humanities Research Board in 1998. The HRB became the Arts and
                        Humanities Research Board during the life of the project and DIAMM has been
                        the recipient of two major resource enhancement grants in 1999 and 2001 from
                        the AHRB. The grants have financed equipment and the travel costs and salary
                        to enable us to extend the remit of DIAMM to embrace the complete UK
                        polyphonic repertory up to 1550, and important representative sources from
                        outside the UK. In March 2010, DIAMM began receiving new funding from the
                        Arts and Humanities Research Council as part of its DEDEFI scheme (DEDEFI:
                        Digital Equipment and Database Enhancement for Impact).</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>The British Academy (Small Research Grants)</head>
                    <p>In January 2009, Dr Julia Craig-McFeely was awarded a Small Research Grant of
                        £7498 to assist in the creation of inventories for manuscripts listed in
                        DIAMM. These inventories will be brought online in the next phase of
                        technical development of the website. The work will be undertaken during
                        2009/2010 by Giovanni Varelli.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>The Morrill Music Library in the Biblioteca Berenson, Villa I Tatti - The
                        Harvard University Center for Italian Renaissance Studies, Florence</head>
                    <p>In 2008, The Morrill Music Library donated €10 000 to spearhead the
                        digitisation of the Alamire Choirbooks. The project will enable DIAMM, The
                        Alamire Foundation, and The Morrill Music Library to provide scholars with
                        high-quality digital images of this exceptional collection of choirbooks
                        currently located in 7 countries.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>The John Fell OUP Research Fund</head>
                    <p>In February 2008, DIAMM was awarded £28,000 to enable the project to purchase
                        a new single-shot high-resolution digital camera, the PhaseOne P45+.</p>
                    <p>The camera will enable DIAMM to photograph at its customary high standards,
                        but at much higher speeds than has been possible with existing equipment,
                        thus bringing per-image costs down dramatically. The P45+ is a 'single-shot'
                        digital camera, which means that it operates much as any consumer camera:
                        the click of the shutter takes the picture. The big difference with this
                        camera is that its sensor is large enough to obtain archive quality images.
                        It is suitable for documents around A4 size and smaller. For larger
                        documents, or those requiring higher resolution the project will continue to
                        use the PhaseOne PowerPhase scanning back.</p>
                </div>
                
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
