<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="p1_5"
    xmlns:xmt="http://www.cch.kcl.ac.uk/xmod/tei/1.0">
    <teiHeader>
        <fileDesc>
            <titleStmt>
                <title>Project Team</title>
            </titleStmt>
            <publicationStmt>
                <publisher>King's College London</publisher>
                <pubPlace>London</pubPlace>
            </publicationStmt>
            <sourceDesc>
                <p>BasicWebsite.pdf</p>
            </sourceDesc>
        </fileDesc>
        <revisionDesc>
            <change when="2012-02-13" who="Julia Craig-McFeely">removed text that should be in Acknowledgements</change>
            <change when="2011-02-22" who="Charlotte Tupman">Converted to P5 and hand-tidied where
                necessary</change>
            <change><date>2008-10-09</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Added a member of the
                International Advisory Board</change>
            <change><date>2008-02-08</date><name>Greg Skidmore</name>Text content update as per
                Arianna's email.</change>
            <change><date>2006-04-18</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Text content
                update</change>
            <change><date>2004-10-26</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Addition of ICAM
                details</change>
            <change><date>2004-07-5</date><name>Arianna Ciula</name>creation of p1_2</change>
            <change><date>2007-11-29</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Revisions to personnel,
                and addition of Advisory Board</change>
            <change><date>2007-12-07</date><name>Julia Craig-McFeely</name>Typos corrected, new
                project researchers and Assoc Dir added</change>
        </revisionDesc>
    </teiHeader>
    <text>
        <body>
            <div>
                <head>Project team</head>

                <p>DIAMM was founded by two leading musicologists in the field of Medieval
                    Manuscript Studies, and has since grown to encompass scholars and researchers in
                    musicological and technical disciplines:</p>
                <div>
                    <head>Founding Directors</head>

                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Margaret Bent CBE, FBA, All Souls College, Oxford</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Margaret Bent was a Senior Research Fellow of All Souls College, Oxford from
                        1992, now an Emeritus Fellow, though she continues to teach in Oxford and
                        internationally, and maintains active contact with young scholars and
                        performing groups. She taught for many years at Brandeis and Princeton
                        Universities in the U.S.A. A former President of the American Musicological
                        Society, she is a Fellow of the British Academy and was appointed CBE in
                        2008. Among many other awards are honorary degrees from the universities of
                        Glasgow and Notre Dame and the Harrison Medal of the Society for Musicology
                        in Ireland. Her research centres on English, French and Italian music of the
                        fourteenth to sixteenth centuries. Over a hundred published essays range
                        across technical matters of music theory, issues that bridge notation and
                        performance, manuscript studies and descriptions of new sources, interfaces
                        with literary, historical and biographical questions. Her most recent major
                        publication is a facsimile and study of the Veneto manuscript Bologna Q15,
                        co-published with DIAMM, and winner of the AMS's Claude Palisca award,
                        2009.</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Professor Andrew Wathey, Vice-Chancellor and Chief Executive,
                            Northumbria University</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Professor Andrew Wathey is Vice-Chancellor and Chief Executive of Northumbria
                        University. He was previously Senior Vice-Principal at Royal Holloway
                        University of London (2006-08), serving also as Vice-Principal Planning and
                        Resources (2003-6), Dean of Arts (2002), and Head of Music (2000-02). He was
                        appointed Professor of Music History at Royal Holloway in 1999, having been,
                        from 1989, successively, Lecturer, Senior Lecturer and Reader. As Senior
                        Vice-Principal he had policy responsibility for strategic planning and for
                        the College's financial resources and the estate, leading the development of
                        Royal Holloway's Corporate Strategy 2005-2010, developing strategic
                        collaborations, and overseeing a £100m capital programme. He also led its
                        Music Department to a 5** in the 2001 RAE. He was Lecturer in Music at
                        Lancaster University (1988-89), Research Fellow at Downing College,
                        Cambridge (1985-8), Junior Research Fellow at Merton College, Oxford
                        (1982-5), graduating from St Edmund Hall, Oxford University in 1979. He was
                        a Visiting Fellow at All Souls College, Oxford in 1998.</p>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>President</head>

                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Margaret Bent</item>
                    </xmt:uList>

                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Directors</head>
                    <div>
                        <head>Holders of the current AHRC: DEDEFI grant</head>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Dr Martin Kauffmann, Department of Special Collections and Western
                                Manuscripts, Bodleian Library, University of Oxford (AHRC:
                                DEDEFI)</item>
                        </xmt:uList>

                        <p>Since 1989 Martin Kauffmann has worked as a medieval specialist in the
                            Western Manuscripts section of the Bodleian's Department of Special
                            Collections and Western Manuscripts, with curatorial responsibility for
                            medieval manuscripts (mostly European) from late antiquity to c.1500,
                            involving acquisitions, cataloguing, exhibitions, and assistance to
                            readers and members of the public. He supervises projects for the online
                            cataloguing of medieval manuscripts and for the digitization of images
                            of illuminated manuscripts (in partnership with ARTstor of New York). He
                            is the Library's subject consultant for art history and
                            palaeography/manuscript studies, and chairs the University's Committee
                            for Library Provision in Art History. From 1999 to 2001 he edited the
                            Bodleian Library Record, and now sits on its editorial board. He is the
                            Bodleian representative of the Association of University Teachers. Dr.
                            Kauffmann acts as an advisor to the Acceptance in Lieu Panel of the
                            Museums, Libraries and Archives Council, and to the Reviewing Committee
                            on the Export of Works of Art in the Department for Culture, Media and
                            Sport. He is a member of the consultative user group for the British
                            Library survey of illuminated manuscripts. He has served as an advisor
                            to the International Center of Medieval Art in New York, and as a member
                            of the advisory panel of the project ‘Palaeography – developing the
                            national resource', based at the University of London Library. He has
                            also been a visiting consultant to the Department of Manuscripts at the
                            J. Paul Getty Museum, California.</p>

                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Dr Elizabeth Eva Leach, St. Hugh's College, University of Oxford
                                (AHRC: DEDEFI)</item>
                        </xmt:uList>

                        <p>Elizabeth Eva Leach is University Lecturer in Music at the University of
                            Oxford, having previously been Reader in Music at Royal Holloway,
                            University of London. Her book Sung Birds: Music, Nature, and Poetry in
                            the Later Middle Ages was published in 2007 by Cornell University Press,
                            who will also publish her monograph on Guillaume de Machaut in 2011.
                            Leach gives regular papers to audiences of musicologists and
                            medievalists. In 2011 she will be one of the speakers in the 26th Annual
                            Darwin College Lectures at the University of Cambridge. Please visit her
                            personal website <ref type="external"
                                target="http://web.me.com/elizabethevaleach/">here</ref>. Read her
                                <ref type="external" target="http://eeleach.wordpress.com/"
                                >blog</ref>!</p>
                        <xmt:uList>
                            <item>Prof Thomas Schmidt-Beste, School of Music, University of Wales,
                                Bangor (Chair of DIAMM Board of Directors)</item>
                        </xmt:uList>
                        <p/>
                        <p>Thomas Schmidt-Beste (* 1968) is Professor and Head of Music at Bangor
                            University. He studied at the universities of Heidelberg and Chapel Hill
                            (USA) and received his doctorate in Heidelberg in 1995 with a thesis on
                            Felix Mendelssohn's aesthetics. After working in Heidelberg for the
                            Cappella Sistina (Music of the Papal Chapel) research project and
                            spending a year as a Humboldt Fellow at the University of Illinois
                            (Urbana), he received his Habilitation in 2001 and was appointed to a
                            Heisenberg Senior Research fellowship. In 2004 and 2005 he was a
                            visiting professor in Frankfurt, before being appointed at Bangor in
                            2005. In 2008, he was a Visiting Fellow at All Souls College, Oxford.
                            His main areas of research are sacred music and musical sources of the
                            15th and 16th centuries and German music of the late 18th and 19th
                            centuries (Mendelssohn and Mozart in particular). Recent publications
                            include Die Sonate (2006; English translation as Cambridge Introduction
                            to the Sonata to appear in 2010) and critical editions of Mendelssohn's
                            'Scottish' and 'Italian' Symphonies.</p>
                    </div>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Board of Directors</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Nicolas Bell, Music Collections, The British Library, London
                            (Publications Chair)</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Nicolas Bell is Curator of Music Manuscripts at the British Library. He has
                        published studies of the Las Huelgas Codex, the principal Spanish source of
                        early polyphonic music, and of British Library Royal MS 11 E XI, a volume of
                        motets presented to Henry VIII. He is Secretary of the Henry Bradshaw
                        Society (for the editing of rare liturgical texts) and book reviews editor
                        for the journal Plainsong and Medieval Music.</p>


                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Julia Craig-McFeely, Royal Holloway, University of London (Project
                            Manager)</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Julia Craig-McFeely studied at Edinburgh University (BMus, MMus) with Michael
                        Tilmouth, Kenneth Leighton and Peter Williams. She completed her DPhil on
                        English Lute Manuscripts and Scribes 1530-1630 at the University of Oxford
                        in 1994. After several years as a college lecturer at a number of Colleges
                        she held a Junior Research Fellowship at St Anne's College. From 1996 she
                        ran a successful freelance business typesetting music and text that had
                        particular difficulties in layout or design (including transcribing and
                        setting Donizetti's opera Elisabetta from his autograph, for the Royal Opera
                        House, Covent Garden), and has since typeset a number of publications in
                        musicology, including the award-winning Facsimile and introductory study of
                        Bologna MS Q.15, by Margaret Bent. She continues her publishing activities
                        as the principal member of the production team for DIAMM Publications. She
                        has been the Project Manager of DIAMM since 1998 and a Director since 2007.
                        She has published and lectured in Europe and the USA both about her research
                        subjects and about the work of DIAMM, and in particular about creating
                        high-quality images of archive documents and digital restoration. She has
                        also lectured on intellectual property rights in relation to digital images.
                        She is known internationally as an expert in archive-quality imaging of
                        delicate documents, and consults to a number of organisations including the
                        National Library of Ireland and the Israel Antiquities Authority. In 2008
                        she was one of the team of specialists who undertook the pilot project to
                        digitize the Dead Sea Scrolls in Jerusalem.</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Michael Scott Cuthbert, Massachusetts Institute of
                            Technology</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Dr Michael Scott Cuthbert (cuthbert[at]mit.edu) is <ref type="external"
                            target="http://web.mit.edu/music/facstaff/cuthbert.html">Assistant
                            Professor of Music</ref> at <ref type="external"
                            target="http://web.mit.edu/">M.I.T</ref>. Cuthbert received his A.B. <hi
                            rend="italic">summa cum laude</hi>, A.M. and Ph.D. degrees from Harvard
                        University. He spent 2004-05 at the <ref type="external"
                            target="http://www.aarome.org/">American Academy</ref> as a <ref
                            type="external" target="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rome_Prize">Rome
                            Prize</ref> winner in Medieval Studies and 2009-10 as Fellow at
                        Harvard's <ref type="external" target="http://www.itatti.it/">Villa I Tatti
                            Center</ref> for Italian Renaissance Studies in Florence. Prior to
                        coming to M.I.T., Cuthbert was Visiting Assistant Professor on the faculties
                        of Smith and Mount Holyoke Colleges. His teaching includes
                        <!--<ref
                            type="external"
                            target="http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Music-and-Theater-Arts/21M-220Spring-2007/CourseHome/"
                            >early music</ref>, <ref type="external"
                            target="http://ocw.mit.edu/OcwWeb/Music-and-Theater-Arts/21M-262Fall-2006/CourseHome/"
                            >-->early
                        music<!--</ref>,--> and music theory. Cuthbert has worked extensively on
                        computer-aided musical analysis, fourteenth-century music, and the music of
                        the past forty years. He is creator and principal investigator of the <ref
                            type="external" target="http://music21-mit.blogspot.com/">music21</ref>
                        project. He has lectured and published on <ref type="external"
                            target="http://ciconia.trecento.com/dissertation/">fragments and
                            palimpsests</ref> of the late Middle Ages, set analysis of Sub-Saharan
                        African Rhythm, Minimalism, and the music of John Zorn. Cuthbert is writing
                        a book on Italian sacred music from the arrival of the Black Death to the
                        end of the Great Schism. </p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Helen Deeming, Royal Holloway College, University of London (Medieval
                            Song Network)</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p> Helen Deeming is a Lecturer in Music at Royal Holloway, University of
                        London. She is joint co-ordinator (with Ardis Butterfield) of the Medieval
                        Song Network based at the Institute of Musical Research and was editor of
                        the journal Plainsong and Medieval Music from 2006-2010. Her current
                        research is centred on songs in English manuscripts of the twelfth and
                        thirteenth centuries, and she is preparing an edition of these for the
                        series Musica Britannica. Her monograph on miscellany manuscripts (both with
                        and without music) is in press, and she has published articles on medieval
                        song and its manuscript sources in Music and Letters, Early Music, Plainsong
                        and Medieval Music and Scriptorium. </p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Theodor Dumitrescu, University of Utrecht (REMEDIUM and CMME)</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Theodor Dumitrescu is assistant professor of musicology at Utrecht
                        University, where he directs the CMME Project for online publication of
                        early music editions. He holds degrees in Computer Science (BA, Princeton
                        University, 1999) and Musicology (D.Phil., University of Oxford, 2004) , and
                        previously held research fellowships at the Centre d'Études Supérieures de
                        la Renaissance (Tours) and Utrecht University. Presently he sits on the
                        directorial board of the Netherlands' royal musical association (KVNM) and
                        advises numerous digital musicology initiatives. Dumitrescu's research and
                        publications center on history, analysis, and theory of European music c.
                        1500, as well as editorial technique and issues in digital publication. His
                        books and editions include <hi rend="italic">The Early Tudor Court and
                            International Musical Relations</hi> (Ashgate, 2007); <hi rend="italic"
                            >John Dygon's Proportiones practicabiles secundum Gaffurium,</hi>
                        (University of Illinois Press, 2006); <hi rend="italic">The York Masses</hi>
                        (Early English Church Music 52; Stainer and Bell, 2010); and <hi
                            rend="italic">The Occo Codex</hi> (CMME Project, 2008). Recent and
                        forthcoming studies address subjects such as pitch and accidentals in
                        late-medieval notation; attribution and compositional technique in the works
                        of Regis and Obrecht; archival documentation on Prioris and the chapel
                        singers of Louis XII of France; and the concept of materiality in digital
                        publication.</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Owen Rees, The Queen's College, University of Oxford</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Owen Rees specialises, in his research and performing activities, in music of
                        the sixteenth century and the first half of the seventeenth—particularly
                        Spanish, Portuguese, and English sacred repertories. He took his first
                        degree and doctorate at Cambridge University, where he studied with Peter le
                        Huray and Iain Fenlon. From 1989 to 1991 he was College Lecturer in music at
                        St Peter's College and St Edmund Hall in Oxford, and from 1991 to 1997
                        taught within the Music Department at the University of Surrey. He is now
                        Fellow in Music at The Queen's College, Oxford, Senior Research Fellow at
                        Somerville College, Oxford and a Reader in the Faculty of Music. He has
                        published studies of the music of, for example, Cristóbal de Morales,
                        Francisco Guerrero, and William Byrd, and of musical sources and repertories
                        from Portugal and Spain. His first book, Polyphony in Portugal, was
                        published by Garland, and he was co-editor (with Bernadette Nelson) of
                        Cristóbal de Morales: Sources, Influences, Reception (Boydell). His work as
                        a scholar regularly bears fruit in terms of performance and recordings (he
                        conducts the A Capella Portuguesa, the Choir of The Queen's College, Oxford,
                        and the Cambridge Taverner Choir), including substantial repertories of
                        Portuguese polyphony which were previously largely unknown.</p>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Magnus Williamson, Newcastle University</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                    <p>Magnus Williamson read music at Magdalen College, Oxford. After completing
                        his doctoral thesis he was lecturer in music at Somerville College prior to
                        his appointment as lecturer at Newcastle in 1997. His research is in the
                        late middle ages and early renaissance; he has published on the origins of
                        the Eton choirbook, and on the social context of English music before,
                        during and after the Reformation. He is currently General Editor of the
                        British Academy series, Early English Church Music. He is currently the
                        General Editor of the British Academy series, Early English Church Music,
                        and active as a performer both on the organ and as a choral director.</p>
                </div>


                <div>
                    <head>International Advisory Board</head>
                    <xmt:uList>

                        <item>Bart Demuyt, Director of The Alamire Foundation</item>

                        <item>Michael Friebel, University of Salzburg</item>
                        <item>Marco Gozzi, University of Trento</item>
                        <item>Oliver Huck, University of Hamburg</item>
                        <item>Martin Kirnbauer, University of Basel, Historisches Museum
                            Basel</item>
                        <item>Karl Kügle, University of Utrecht</item>
                        <item>Peter M. Lefferts, University of Nebraska-Lincoln</item>
                        <item>Thomas J Mathiesen, Centre for the History of Music Theory and
                            Literature, Jacobs School of Music, Indiana University</item>
                        <item>Pedro Memelsdorff, Barcelona Conservatory, Fondazione Giorgio Cini
                            (Venice), Mala Punica (Bologna)</item>
                        <item>John Nádas, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill</item>
                        <item>Jason Stoessel, University of New England</item>
                        <item>Philippe Vendrix, Centre d'Etudes Supérieurs de la Renaissance,
                            University of Tours</item>
                        <item>Lorenz Welker, University of Munich</item>
                        <item>Giovanni Zanovello, Indiana University</item>
                        <item>Francesco Zimei, Istituto Abruzzese di Storia Musicale</item>

                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>
              <!--  <div>
                    <head>Project Researcher and Outreach Research Co-ordinator</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Gregory Skidmore, The Queen's College, Oxford</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>-->
                <!--<div>
                    <head>Intern 2009</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Giovanni Varelli [Creation of inventories], Royal Holloway, The
                            University of London</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>-->
                <!--<div>
                    <head>Research Assistants</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Esther Anstice (Conference Manager), Oxford</item>
                        <item>Stella Holman (Inventories), Oxford</item>
                        <item>Henry Hope (Outreach Assistant), Oxford</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>-->
              <!--  <div>
                    <head>Principal technical advisor</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Marilyn Deegan, King's College London</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>-->
                <div>
                    <head>Photographer</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>Dr Lynda Sayce, Oxford</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Imaging equipment technical support</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item><ref type="external" target="http://www.icamarchive.co.uk/">ICAM
                                Archive Systems</ref>, Blisworth, Northamptonshire</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>
                <div>
                    <head>Technical development: Department of Digital Humanities, King's
                        College London</head>
                    <xmt:uList>
                        <item>John Bradley</item>
                        <item>Bea Caballero</item>
                  <!--  <item>Arianna Ciula</item>-->
                        <item>Elliott Hall</item>
                        <item>John Lee</item>
                        <!--<item>Artemis Papakostouli</item>-->
                        <item>Charlotte Tupman</item>
                        <item>Paul Vetch (Technical Research Director, 2009-present)</item>
                        <item>José Miguel Vieira</item>
                    </xmt:uList>
                    <p/>
                </div>
            </div>
        </body>
    </text>
</TEI>
